Cleaned & corrected by Tronar
Hundred percent, Utah. Good job.
Hi. Johnny Utah.
Your 9:00 appointment is here.
Special Agent John Utah,
day number one in L.A. Welcome aboard.
- Your personnel record, very impressive.
- Thank you.
You may have been in top 2 percent
of your class at Quantico...
...but quite frankly, son, out here, you have
exactly zero hours of experience in the field.
You know nothing, in fact,
less than nothing.
If you even knew you knew nothing,
that'd be something.
Yes, sir.
- You eat a solid breakfast?
- Sir?
All the food groups,
avoiding caffeine, sugar?
I like that all my people maintain
sound cardiovascular fitness.
We don't drink, and we don't smoke.
- Sir, I take the skin off chicken.
- Good man.
- Bank Robbery.
- All right, I got it.
You are now in the
bank-robbery capital of the world.
Thirteen hundred
and twenty-two last year.
- Up 26 percent from the year before.
- That's correct.
We nailed over 1000 of them.
Miss Deer, take a look at that for me.
Thank you.
Do you know how we nail the bad guys?
Do you know how we nail them?
By crunching data,
good crime-scene work, good lab work...
...and most importantly,
good data-based analysis.
Special Agent Utah,
are you receiving my signal?
Zero distortion, sir.
I love these things.
You're a real blue-flame special,
aren't you, son?
Young, dumb and full of come. I know.
What I don't know
is how you got yourself assigned...
...out here in Los Angeles with us.
I mean, hell.
I guess we just must have ourselves
an asshole shortage, huh?
Yeah? You're on.
Not so far.
Okay.
- Pappas?
- Yeah?
Here, put on the blindfold.
I wanna see you retrieve
at least two bricks off the bottom.
One...
...two.
There.
I've been in the field for 22 years...
...I fired my piece over 19 times
in the line of duty.
I got no idea what a blind man fetching
bricks from the bottom of the pool...
...has got to do
with being a special agent.
Added to which indignity, I have
been saddled with some blue-flamer...
...Quantico cat.
Some quarterback punk.
Johnny Unitas or something.
- The shit they pull, huh?
- Yeah.
- Hey, Angie.
- What?
Here's your guy.
What?
Pappas. Angelo Pappas.
Punk. Quarterback punk.
Hmm.
Welcome to Sea World, kid.
Good luck, Pappas.
Two bricks, coming up.
Little hand says it's time to rock 'n' roll.
- Everybody freeze!
- Nobody move!
Keep your hands up and your eyes down!
Back away from the Counters!
Hands on your head now!
Everybody out
from behind your desk. On the floor.
Move it! Move it! Now! Get down!
What's the matter with you people?
Gut of the cubicle. Get out of my way.
Now back away from the counter
and get your fucking hands up!
Hey, bitch, what's the matter
with you? You got earwax?
Keep your hands where I can see them!
- Get down, now!
- Hands up.
Hello, hello, hello, ladies and gentlemen.
We are the ex-presidents.
And we need just a few moments
of your time.
We've been screwing you for years
so a few more seconds shouldn't matter.
On the floor, asshole.
The money's insured
so it's not worth dying for.
- How you doing, Dick?
- Implementing our own personal plan...
...of deregulation, Mr. President.
- Time, Mr. Carter.
- Sixty.
- LBJ?
- We're styling.
Oh, Ron, I got Nancy on the line.
Whoo! Ha, ha.
Eighty.
Air Force One is waiting, Mr. President.
Let's go, let's go, let's go.
Get your hands where I can see them!
Thank you.
Thank you very much, ladies and gentlemen.
And please don't forget to vote.
I'm not a crook.
Twenty-seven banks in three years.
God. In and out in 90 seconds.
No one ever gets shot.
Now, what are we talking about here?
We're talking about solid professionals.
- Good moves.
- Yeah.
They control the room well...
...and they stick strictly
to the cash drawers.
They don't go for the vault?
No, they never go for the vault.
They never get greedy.
- Smart. You burn time in the vault.
- Yup, that's right.
Reagan usually does the driving.
Stolen switch car,
they leave it running on the curb.
It looks parked from a distance.
And when they run,
they dump the vehicle and they vanish.
Like a virgin on prom night.
I mean, they vanish.
Surgical.
Look at them separate the dye pack.
Dick and Ronnie know their jobs.
The ex-presidents are the best
I've ever seen, ever.
Any time you two have finished jerking off
watching MTV...
...we need a look at these tapes.
Hey, Pappas, you, uh, tell the kid
your theory on the presidents?
Just take the tapes and go, Babbitt.
Hang ten, Pappas, like totally rad, dude.
I tell you, the department loves it.
What's he talking about?
- Found the drop car on Mulholland Drive..
- We'll go work it.
- Oh, no.
- Angelo?
- Come on.
- Thank you.
- We'll go work it.
- Good.
Excuse me.
I'm working a fucking drop car.
I don't believe it. Working a drop car.
Pappas. What a hard-on.
- Keep them away from there.
- All right.
- Yeah, well...
- Came around the corner...
Four fifty-nine, called it in about 5:25.
This car doesn't have AC.
Today was a scorcher.
Sweat secretions in the setbacks.
Are you through, Mr. Wizard?
Let me know if you find Jimmy Hoffa
under the seat while you're at it.
Yo, can you photograph this?
Oh, look at this. It's 7:30.
The night is still so young.
The way you're going,
you'll solve this case and start another one.
Drop car, my ass. Goddamn.
You been working Bank Robbery,
what, 22 years?
Yeah, 22 years.
Man, L.A. has changed a lot
during that time.
- The air got dirty and the sex got clean.
- Uh-huh.
So a guy with that kind of time in
must have a theory about these guys.
Leave it alone, Johnny.
Okay, fine, you've given up, fine.
It doesn't mean I have to.
Hey, hey, listen.
Forget about it, kid. They are ghosts.
Yeah, of course.
What am I thinking? If you couldn't crack it
with all your years of experience...
...it's impossible to conceive
that I might have something to offer, right?
Well, maybe I can do better
than some over-the-hill burnout.
- Watch your mouth.
- Maybe you ought to take...
...some early retirement right now.
And get some rent-a-cop, night-security job,
tell Nam stories.
Listen, you snot-nosed little shit!
I was taking shrapnel in Khe Sanh...
...while you were crapping in your hands
and rubbing it on your face!
- You mad?
- Yeah, I'm mad!
- Good and mad?
- Yeah, what you wanna do about it?
Feels good, doesn't it?
Like you're still alive, right?
- Yeah!
- Well, since you're still alive...
...and you're not in the box just yet,
why don't you tell me this theory of yours...
...and we'll go get these guys?
Okay, hotshot.
You wanna nail the bank robbers
and be a big hero?
- Definitely.
Then here it is.
The ex-presidents are surfers.
- Surfers?
- Surfers.
It's in our face.
Look at the tan line on this guy.
- Oh, well, he must be a surfer.
- Well, yeah.
So last year, Nixon scuffs the counter
when he's going over...
...so there is a soil sample.
Non-specific mud.
Traces of asphalt, traces of oil.
Traces of sand, carnauba wax.
So I become a wax expert.
Now, there's 80-some uses for this stuff.
Something like 500 products.
Candle wax, car wax, mustache wax.
It could be anything.
Guy's waxing his mustache
at the beach...
...gets sand in it...
...takes it off with a shoe.
Shoe scuffs the counter...
- Would you just shut up a minute?
- Ha, ha.
Just listen, maybe you'll learn something.
The lab gave us three possible matches.
This is one of them.
- Sex Wax.
- Yeah.
You're not into kinky shit, are you,
Angelo?
Ha, ha. Not yet. Surfers use this.
They rub it on their boards for traction.
- Thanks for the tip.
- You're welcome for the tip.
And here's another tip.
Check out the dates on these robberies.
It's strictly a summer job for these idiots.
Four months.
June to October.
- Same the year before.
- That's right.
We have one more month.
We won't see them till next summer.
They're traveling on the money,
going where the waves are.
That's right.
Ha!
The ex-presidents rip off banks
to finance their endless summer.
Whoa!
Hey, man, a lot of guys your age
are learning to surf.
It's cool. There's nothing wrong with it.
- I'm 25.
- That's what I'm saying. It's never too late.
Hope you stick with it.
Surfing's the source, can change your life.
Swear to God.
Why can't I just walk around
with this thing under my arm...
...and act stoned, ask a few questions?
Well, look.
Look at them.
They're like some kind of tribe.
They got their own language.
You can't just walk up to those guys.
You have to get out there...
...and learn the moves, get into their head,
pick up the speech.
You trying to tell me the FBI
is going to pay me to learn to surf?
It's either you or me out there on the board.
Get my drift?
Angelo, this is for little rubber people
who don't shave yet.
Come on, you're the quarterback jock.
It's all balance, right?
And coordination.
How hard can it be?
Hold on.
Use your arms.
Paddle. Come on.
It's all right, come on. You're okay.
You crazy son of a bitch.
You wanna commit suicide,
you do it someplace else.
This pig board piece of shit.
You got no business out here
whatsoever.
Hey.
My name's Johnny Utah.
Who cares?
That is your surfing contact?
Female, blue eyes, black hair...
...5'6", 119 pounds.
God, Utah.
Not bad, Utah.
"Tyler Ann Endicott, born 11/27/64."
Exhibition of speed.
"Indecent exposure
inside moving vehicle."
Hot, very hot.
What else they got on her?
I still haven't found anything I can use.
I gotta find an approach. A way in.
Here we go.
"Both parents deceased.
Airplane crash, San Diego, '84."
Yeah.
Definitely.
See you later, man.
Next?
What do you want?
Shrimp and fries.
I mean, what do you want?
- Why do you keep hanging around here?
- I need you to teach me.
Give me a break.
Uh, shrimp and fries...
...to go.
- Would you like something to drink, sir?
- I'm serious.
I can see that you're serious. Forget it.
Stick to tennis.
I don't know, whatever you do good.
Uh, miniature golf. Your number's 37.
You don't understand.
I'm gonna learn to surf or break my neck.
What is it?
You all of a sudden got this bug
that you just have to go surfing?
- This is a line, right?
- No, no.
See...
My whole life I've done things
for other people.
In high school, I played football
because my old man expected me to.
Mm-hm.
Then my parents always figured
I'd go to law school.
So I did. Football scholarship.
Phi Beta Kappa...
- Is this gonna take a really long time?
- Wait.
So I'm a big hero to my folks, right?
But two years ago,
they were killed in a car wreck.
You can't imagine it.
Your whole life changes.
And I suddenly realized
that all my goals had been their goals...
...and I hadn't been living my own life...
...so I wanted something for myself.
So I come out here from Ohio
a month ago.
I've never seen the ocean before.
Any ocean.
I never thought
it would affect me so much.
I'm drawn to it.
Or something.
I wanna do what you do.
It's the truth.
All right.
Okay. Tomorrow, here, 6 a.m.
If you are one minute late, I'm gone.
And, stud, I didn't take you on to raise,
so I'll teach you a few things...
...and then after that,
you're gonna be on your own, okay?
Oh, God.
Stop here.
You agree to do exactly
what I say when I say it?
Sure.
Pop.Pop.
You stand straight up, you're just gonna fall
right over, so let's try it again.
Start over. Just do it again.
Hey, what you doing, huh?
Just do it again. Pop up.
- You gotta stay low, you're gonna bite it.
- Ha, ha.
You dragged your knee that time,
you'll just wipe out.
You're dragging your foot,
you're gonna be fish food.
Both feet have to land on the board
at the same time.
That's it. That's it. You're surfing.
Whoo!
Yeah!
Whoa!
You're doing all right, city boy.
Whoo!
Yeah.
You are surfing.
That's Bodhi.
They call him the Bodhisattva.
He's a modern savage.
He's a real Searcher.
What's he searching for?
The ride.
The ultimate ride.
The guy's even crazier than you, Johnny.
Not bad.
Yeah.
Hey.
- Okay.
- Whoo!!
Heads up.
- Hey!
- Aah!
Put me down.
Uh, we know each other.
That's a...
That's a Surfboard, all right.
Looks like a '57 Chevy I used to have.
Uh, Tyler, come here.
So, uh...
...who's the guy? You replace me?
- Give me a break. Where you been?
- He surfs real well.
Come on.
He's from Kansas or something.
- He's from Kansas?
- Heads up.
Yeah. Good catch.
Ready. Set. Hut! Hut!
Go, Roach. Go, go, go.
Hut!
Hut.
That's right, get him.
Go get him. Get him.
Hut.
I'm open.
Oh!
Nice pass. Lousy catch.
Yeah! Ha, ha!
Yes, mama. Yes, baby.
Whose ball is it? Who wants it?
Go, go. go.
Hut.
- Get him.
Very bad.
Ready.
Set.
Hut.
Go, go.
Hey, what the fuck is wrong with you?
Don't you think that's a little out of line?
- Whoa, cool it. Don't you know who this is?
- I don't know who this is.
This is Johnny Utah.
Ohio State Buckeyes, all conference.
Remember?
Number nine, man. How you doing?
Nice to meet you.
Johnny fucking Utah.
Sorry. Didn't mean to get in your face.
I knew I knew you. It was the Rose Bowl.
Three years ago, you beat SC, right?
- You? You did this?
- That was one hell of a game.
No shit.
Yeah, but you got nuked
in the last quarter.
Yeah, I got my knee folded back
about 90 degrees the wrong way.
- Whoa, that's why you never went pro?
- Two years of surgery, missed my window.
Went through law school instead.
Law school?
You're a lawyer?
Well, life's not over yet, man.
You're surfing.
Lawyers don't surf.
This one does.
- Let's go!
- Let's play some football.
Special Agent Utah,
this is not some job...
...flipping burgers at the local drive-in.
Yes, the Surfboard bothers me.
Yes, your approach to this whole
goddamn case bothers me.
And, yes, you bother me!
And Pappas, oh, for the love of Christ...
...just how the hell did I ever even let you
talk me into this whole boneheaded idea?
Harp, we're working undercover.
It takes time.
- We've produced a few...
- No, no, no, no, no!
Let me tell you what you've produced.
Over the last two weeks,
you two have produced exactly squat!
Squat!
During which time the ex-presidents
have robbed two more banks!
Now, for Christ's sake...
...does either one of you have anything
even remotely interesting to tell me?
Caught my first tube this morning...
...sir.
Goddamn it.
- Why didn't you leave that in the car?
- It sticks out so I can't lock it.
Anyway, what's his problem?
We're handling our caseload.
- I'm surfing on my own time.
- I know, just don't rub Harp's nose in it.
Look, Angelo, you think I joined the FBI
to learn to surf?
This was your lame-o idea in the first place.
You gotta back me up on this.
Johnny, we better come up
with something real quick.
- My friend.
- What?
Encino Savings and Loan.
Guard grabbed LBJ's ponytail.
Twenty-eight robberies.
And what do we get from it?
One fucking hair.
Angelo, pay attention.
There's gonna be a test afterward.
Lab is showing traces of toxins
in the hair.
Selenium, titanium, arsenic.
The beaches are always being closed
because of waste spills, right?
And surfers are territorial.
They stick mostly to certain breaks.
If we can get some hair samples
and get a match at a certain beach...
...we'd know which break
the ex-presidents surf.
You buying this?
- No.
But let's do it anyway.
It will bug the shit out of Harp.
- My man.
- Yeah.
Hey, when you two are done making out,
I need to talk to you.
What's this?
Fucking narco entrapment or what, dude?
- Not exactly, dude.
- Oh, shit.
- Making a wig for my girlfriend. Thank you.
- What the fuck?
- Fucking, that was a narc, man.
- Dude out my hair.
- So what? He didn't bust us.
- But dude, he fucking cut my hair.
Bro. Bro.
Don't move.
Got some huge sucker crawling
right into your ear.
- Got it. Ugh!
- Hey.
Leave some fucking hair, man.
What is it?
Saved your life, bro.
Close one.
PCBs, selenium, titanium, arsenic.
The percentages look right.
Here's a match.
- A match?
- Latigo Beach.
Nice point break.
Long workable rides.
Surf's up, ace.
Stay off my wave.
Goons trying to drop in.
Paddle, paddle, paddle.
Out of the way, you shit.
Hey.
You dinged my board, kook.
Why don't you watch
where the fuck you're going?
Politeness counts, asshole.
Go back to the Valley, man.
Angelo, I've eaten shit 47 times...
...and got my lights punched out
by some psycho local.
There must be 20 guys here
with ponytails.
Patience, hotshot, patience.
It will be subtle, if it's here at all.
They'll be a group within the group.
These guys are a real tight unit.
You'll see them, you'll know it.
- This the guy?
- Yeah.
Okay.
I know.
This is where you tell me
all about how locals rule...
...and yuppie insects like me shouldn't
be surfing your break and all that, right?
Nope.
That would be a waste of time.
We're just gonna fuck you up.
Oh.
Come on, motherfucker.
- Eat that.
- Get him.
Fuck.
Johnny, are you there?
You better not be trying
to pick up any babes.
Again.
Hit him. Yeah. Harder. Yeah.
Back off. He's with me.
Kiss my ass.
Back off, Warchild. Seriously.
Thank you.
Stay out of this, Bodhi.
- What's your name?
- Bunker.
Bunker. Listen, Bunker,
I'm actually really glad you found me.
Yeah, why?
- Hey.
- Back off.
Here, man.
Shit.
Come on. Come on.
Come here.
This is stimulating,
but we're out of here. Let's go, Utah.
Just keep walking.
Hold it. Okay.
You two guys seen a kid run through here
with a car stereo? He stole it from me.
No, but, uh, there's four guys back there
you might wanna check out.
Oh. Thanks, buddy.
- Hope you find him.
- Don't worry, I will.
You like to start shit, don't you?
Who are those guys?
Nazi assholes.
The guy you dropped is Bunker Weiss...
...the big one is Warchild,
a.k.a. Lupton Pitman.
And the other two... Hell, I don't know.
They, uh, think they're some kind
of death squad around here.
What's their program?
Brains are wired wrong.
They're into some bad shit.
Like what? Illegal shit?
Maybe, I don't know.
That's not what I'm talking about.
They live to get radical. They don't have
any understanding of the sea...
...so they'll never get
the spiritual side of it.
Hey, you're not gonna start chanting
or anything, are you?
Ha, ha. I might.
This is me.
So, uh, you still haven't figured out
what riding waves is all about, have you?
It's a state of mind.
It's that place where you lose yourself
and find yourself.
You don't know it yet, but you've got it.
It's right there.
I saw you with those guys, you're a pit bull.
They didn't back you down an inch.
And that is very rare in this world.
Well, thanks for stepping in.
Later. Oh, hey.
I'm, uh, having some people over
at my house tonight if you wanna come.
Sure. Where?
- Come with Tyler. She knows.
- All right.
Next time you leave your piece and shield
in the oar, you stay in sight. Okay?
Okay, Dad.
Yeah, I need you to run a plate for me.
Two-Denver-four-Sam-niner-five-niner,
late '70s Jeep.
Screw you, punk.
The Jeep belongs to a Bunker Weiss.
My buddy. Guy's got quite a sheet.
Yeah. Yeah, skip all that.
Give me the greatest hits.
Felony possession of cocaine.
That's good.
Felony B&E. Three months in juvie.
Felony assault.
Postgraduate work at Chino.
Excellent. I'm loving it.
These guys really fit the profile.
I say we lay it on Harp.
Here comes the night shift.
Hey, who was that girl?
No, the girl with the really big tits.
This is bullshit. This is a bullshit lead.
This is totally bullshit.
Harp must be fucking desperate
if he's listening to you two flakes.
See you bright and early, guys.
Yeah, right.
Cold pizza for you.
It's good for breakfast. See you.
- When did Harp say we'd get the warrant?
- First thing.
You better get some sleep.
This could be an interesting morning.
d Refused to shine d
d I don't mind d
d If the mountains d
d Fell in the sea d
d Let it be d
d It ain't me d
d Got my own world to live through d
d And I ain't gonna copy you d
- Hey.
- Hey, Bodhi.
d Now, if a six turned out to be nine d
I taught him that trick.
I like it.
Watch yourself. She's a wild one.
Make yourself at home.
What's mine is yours.
d I don't care d
Man, it jacks up.
You drop down into the pit.
It's 25 feet straight down...
...and your balls...
Man, your balls are about this big.
And the whole thing's fucking roaring,
right?
Pushing you forward
like you're a hood ornament...
...on a freight train or something, man.
Yeah, and if you lose it,
the fish will be picking you out of the coral.
Big-wave riding's for macho assholes
with a death wish.
No, it's not. It's the ultimate rush.
There's nothing that comes close to it.
Not even sex.
Maybe that's because
you're not doing it right, Roach.
Just paddling out into big surf
is a total commitment.
You can't just call time-out,
stroll on in to the beach...
...if you don't like the way
things are going.
So, what's the biggest? Waimea?
- Ridden?
- Yeah.
- Makaha.
- Dana Point.
Bell's Beach, Australia.
Whoa, whoa. No way Bell's
is bigger than Waimea, bro.
It will be next year.
Bodhi believes the 50-year storm
is coming next year.
Fifty-year storm. What's that?
- That's kind of a legend.
- No, it's real. It's absolutely reel.
Everything moves in cycles...
...so twice a century, the ocean
lets us know just how small we really are.
A winter storm comes out of Antarctica,
tearing up the Pacific...
...and it sends a huge swell north
2000 miles.
And when it hits Bell's Beach, it'll turn into
the biggest surf this planet has ever seen...
...and I will be there.
- So will I.
- Yeah!
If you want the ultimate, you gotta
be willing to pay the ultimate price.
It's not tragic to die
doing what you love.
It's how I wanna go.
I ain't gonna live to see 30.
There's too much testosterone here.
Whoo!
Bunch of goddamn adrenaline junkies.
Hope you're not buying into this banzai
bullshit like the rest of Bodhi's moonies.
What are you talking about?
You got the kamikaze look, Johnny.
I've seen it.
Bodhi can smell it a mile away.
He'll take you to the edge.
Past it.
- Hey, Bodhi.
- Johnny has his own demons.
Don't you, Johnny?
What's going on?
Go.
Here. Time for a little stealth mission.
You up for it?
- Let's go. Come on.
- Let's go.
- Come on. Let's go.
- Hey. Go.
- Let's do it.
- Let's go.
- I can barely do this in broad daylight.
- Come on.
At least
nobody's gonna see how bad you are.
Whoo-hoo!
- I don't think he's ready for this.
- No, he'll be fine.
Shit!
Shit! Oh, Shit! Fuck!
I gotta be fucking crazy.
But are you crazy enough?
Tyler!
Can't see shit out here. I'm gonna die.
Just feel what the wave is doing,
then accept its energy.
Get in sync, then charge with it.
You don't need to see.
Yeah. Right. Vision is highly overrated.
Okay, Johnny, this one's got your number
on it. Let's jam. Now paddle.
- Go, boy, jam.
- Shit. I'm gonna die now.
I'm gonna fucking die now.
Fuck!
Whoo! You're surfing, man.
Whoa!
Whoo!
I'm fucking surfing!
Yeah!
Check it out!
Is this not the best feeling on earth?
Yeah! Whoo!!
Good break, Johnny.
All right!
- Yeah! Whoo!
- Ha, ha.
Looks like we lost somebody.
- Yeah, leave the fire for them.
- Hungry? Want something to eat?
You wanna get something to eat?
- I'm dying.
- I'm starving.
Where's my clothes?
Hey, Nate, you smell bad.
Nate, did you put my clothes in the bag?
Had enough?
Yeah.
I just wanna sit out here for a minute.
Look at you.
What?
Well, usually you have this intense sort of
scowl of concentration on your face...
...like you're doing all this
for a school project or something.
Or like you've got something driving you.
Look it, it's gone.
If I didn't know better...
...I'd say you looked almost happy.
I can't describe what I'm feeling.
You don't have to.
Goose bumps.
- Yeah, it's cold.
- Yeah.
Come here.
Holy shit.
- What?
- Shit.
I'm really late.
I mean, I'm really late.
Holy shit.
Shit. Oh, Shit!
I'm really late.
- Need help?
- I can't believe you're late to your own raid.
What a flake.
Has that worthless quarterback
punk partner of mine shown up?
Right here.
Well, very good of you to show up,
hotshot.
Watch it. You're gonna tear my skin.
- Goddamn it.
- I'm ready, Angelo. Where do you want me?
Here's how it is. Babbit and Alvarez
are gonna go in the back door.
Cullen's gonna back me up. I want you...
...at the side window by the hedge.
You're strictly backup.
I don't wanna burn your cover. Got that?
- Got it.
- Good.
Now take your position. It's Showtime.
- Go.
- Asshole.
Scooby?
Come on, Scooby.
Scooby, where are you?
- Seen a little dog?
- No, man.
No dog? Scooby, come on.
Here, Scooby.
Scooby.
Oh, yeah, baby.
- What the fuck?
- Get up. Someone at the front door.
Let's go. Get your gun now. Get it.
- Yeah, what?
- Oh. Uh, hi. Oh. Ha, ha.
Uh, have you seen my dog?
I got a little dog, a cockapoo-like thing.
- I don't know anything about your dog.
- Wait.
- He's a nice dog.
- I don't give a...
Cullen, this is Utah.
Get Angelo out.
They're pulling out a fucking arsenal.
Utah, repeat. Say again.
Cullen, you copy?
Cullen.
Alvarez.
Don't let him pull his badge.
Fuck. I can't hear jack shit
over the lawn mower. Christ.
Front door.
- Something's going down. This ain't right.
- Chill the fuck out, man. It's nothing.
Will you shut the fuck up?
Check the windows, bro, do it.
- Shit.
- That little bastard.
- Before he goes, he lifts his leg...
- I told you, I don't know anything...
- Hide the Shit.
- Wait, Wait, Wait.
- Sure it's not in the backyard?
- I ain't got time for this.
There's two guys out the back, man.
Duck down.
Oh, shit. Shit, we're fucked.
That fuck comes through the door
I'm gonna pump him up. Swear to Christ.
- You sure he's not in the back?
- He ain't back there.
- Anybody else who has seen him?
- Get the fuck out of my face.
FBI, gorgeous.
- FBI. Drop it!
- Fuck you.
Fucking pigs.
Oh, wait. Hey, no, no.
Goddamn. Ch, motherfucker.
Oh, shut up!
You motherfuckers!
- Motherfucking.. Motherfucking..
- Shut up, I said!
Motherfucker, back up!
Back up or I blow her fucking head off!
Back up or I'll take her with me.
Back up. I'm coming out right now.
Back up. Back up!
Oh, God! Let me go! Let me go!
God. Cullen!
Aah! You bastard!
- Fucked.
- Unh!
You bastard.
Come here. Come on.
- Babbit?
- You fuckers.
Oh, God.
Fuck you up, man.
Speak into the microphone, squid-brain.
Fuck.
- Give me your hand.
- Fuck you.
Give me your other hand.
Fuck.
Must feel good to you.
There you go. You okay?
Fuck!
Oh, God!
- No! Aah!
- May I have your, uh...'?
Don't touch it!
No!
Oh, God!
It's been paper targets up until today,
huh?
It's no different, Johnny.
Just a little more to clean up.
You did all right today.
You did real good.
Goddamn son of a bitch.
You're the cowboys. You're the real
cowboys, right? Batman and Robin?
You know what this is, huh?
You know what this is, punk?
This is two keys.
Uncut. Crystal meth.
Oh, shit.
Special Agent Utah,
I'd like you to meet Agent Dietz.
Works for the DEA.
He was working deep cover until you...
You think I like this hair, man, huh?
You think I like these clothes?
My wife wants me to stay at Ramada.
I've been working on these fuckers
for three months!
Three months!
I finally got them wanting to play
Wheel Of Fortune...
...so I can find out who their supplier is
and you fucking cowboys show up.
Nice tattoo, Dietz.
Oh, you like that, Pappas, huh?
Fuck you.
He has a record of your suspects'
movements for the last three months.
All I wanna know, smart guy...
...all I wanna know is now are these guys
robbing Tarzana City National Bank...
...on August 2nd when they were
in Fort fucking Lauderdale.
- Why don't you figure that out?
- It's not easy, is it, Utah?
You fucking jerks.
Oh, shit.
Shit.
This is not real, is it?
- He believes it. Ask Nathaniel.
- Hey.
Five-foot walls at Zeros. Let's go.
Hey, Tyler.
Hey, Bodhi.
So let's go.
- Time's a-wasting.
- Wait...
- Now.
- He does this.
Here's the set.
Oh, yeah.
Yeah!
Yeah, stop!
You all right?
You look like you saw a ghost.
Forget about it, kid. They're ghosts.
- I gotta go.
- You gotta what?
Listen, I forgot all about a meeting
I have this morning. A new client.
I gotta jam. Sorry. Really.
I'll call you later.
So I started trailing him.
Who, this Zen surf master?
- Bodhi, yeah. I'm on him all day, right?
- Yeah.
He goes here, he goes there, he goes
to Tower Records, buys some CDs.
He has lunch at Patrick's Roadhouse.
He goes
into the Assured Trust Savings and Loan.
- Did he rob it?
- Cute.
He's inside 20 minutes.
The other guy, Roach, waited in the truck.
They were scoping it out, right?
They were scoping it out
or cashing a check.
Wait, wait. Then they go back to their
beach house and they box up all their shit.
- Yeah.
- See, summer's over.
They load it in Bodhi's truck
and they take it to a public storage unit.
And I lost them after that.
But the house is empty.
- They're definitely out of here.
- Goddamn it.
Why didn't you call me?
They're probably halfway to Maui.
Uh-uh. No, they've got to pick up
some traveling money first.
Assured Trust tomorrow.
Next day outside, latest.
I definitely got a feeling on this.
You got a feeling. Last time
you had a feeling, I had to kill a guy.
And I hate that.
It looks bad on my report.
Angelo, I'm right this time.
We can still win this one.
Okay.
Tomorrow morning, first thing,
we'll be at the bank like stink on shit.
- This Calvin and Hobbes is funny.
- Would you like some oranges?
- You want some oranges?
- No.
- No, no, we got a lot.
- Freshly picked, sir.
- Dollar, sir.
- No, thanks. Good luck.
God.
"For his turkey cemetery."
Oh.
It's time for lunch.
Angelo, it's 10:30.
Right around that corner,
there is a sandwich shop.
They sell meatball sandwiches.
Best I've ever tasted.
Would you go get me two?
Come on, partner. Two.
Thank you.
Utah? Get me two.
- Hi. How you doing?
- Hi.
Can I have two meatball sandwiches, a tuna
on wheat, and two lemonades, please?
Okay, that's two meatballs,
one tuna on wheat, two lemonades.
That's 7.84.
- Thank you.
- Uh-huh.
Oh, boy.
God, you scared me.
Here.
Yours is the one that looks like a roadkill.
- A roadkill?
- Enjoy.
- Thank you very much.
- Here's your lemonade.
- An, thanks.
- Did you see that Lincoln pull up?
I'm so hungry I could eat the ass-end
out of a dead rhino.
I should've had you
get me three of these things.
What Lincoln?
- Goddamn. Get them.
- FBI! Freeze!
I got him. I got him.
No! Go, go.
Freeze!
Holy shit.
- Fuck!
- Get down.
- Go. Now.
- Hang on.
Come on. Get in. Get in.
- Jesus Christ. Fuck.
- Go! Go!
- Go!
- Give me a fucking break. I am going.
- Where'd they go?
- I don't fucking believe this.
I think we're losing them.
- Stay on them. You're losing them!
- I'm not!
Over to the right. Over to the right.
Go. Go.
It's coming up.
- Punch it, punch it.
- Be cool, man.
- Where is he, Dick?
- He's still behind us.
Hang on, you guys.
- We're fucked!
- This car is a piece of shit.
- Oh, shit!
- It's okay, they're on the left.
I think we lost them. I Can't see them.
Tell me where he is!
Oh, fuck! Watch out!
- We got you.
- You ain't got shit.
Goddamn it. Come on, come on.
Okay, guys, it's emergency sanitation.
- Back up, buddy.
- Hey!
Try it. Just try it.
- What about the old Chevy?
- This guy down here.
- I got him. I got the guy.
- Take care of him, Jimmy.
Get away from the car. Move it.
- Come on, get in.
- Wait, wait, wait.
Don't do it, man. Don't do it.
Don't be stupid. Run!
Why is he taking so long?
Come on!
We gotta go. What's his problem?
- Wait a minute.
- We gotta go!
- Don't go!
- Come on!
- Let's go.
- Oh, Shit!
Let's go! Go!
Fuck!
Look out!
Hey.
Get the fuck out of this house!
Hey, what do you think you're doing?
Hey! Hey! Hey!
Oh, no! Aah!
Damn!
Say again, 41.
Roger that, 41.
Cal Plate 562, Sam, Ida, X-ray. Base out.
- Nothing?
- Nothing.
Johnny,
I wanna see you in my office right now.
Unit 23. Unit 23.
See the manager at 4650 Wilshire.
Roger, 23.
Unit 41.
Further information on suspect's vehicle?
I want you to know something.
When you shoot, you don't miss.
- I missed.
- No.
I believe you're either scared...
...or you're getting too goddamn close
to this surfing guru buddy of yours.
I don't believe you're scared.
Hey.
Go home and get some rest.
You look like hammered shit.
And if I get anything
that resembles your boy, I'll beep you.
Now, go home.
Goddamn it.
So, what's the other guy look like?
Never saw him.
It was your basic hit-and-run.
You look like you got in a train wreck.
Stupid jerk just kept driving?
Ouch. Baby, I'm sorry.
Johnny, what is it with you?
You've got that look again.
That you...
That you're about to tell me something
and then you don't.
Or you can't.
There's something
I've wanted to tell you.
It's important.
It could really affect things
between you and me.
Man.
This is harder than I thought.
God, men are so bad at this.
Shh.
Some other time.
You act like nothing happened.
Relax, Nathanial.
Don't tell me to relax, Bodhi.
He's a fucking federal agent.
I should've shot him
when I had the chance.
I'll deal with that fucking Cop.
No, Rosie.
We have hit 30 banks in three years
and they haven't been able to touch us.
All this does
is up the stakes of the game.
Fuck the stakes, Bodhi.
The only person this is a game to is you,
man. This is real.
I mean, this is serious shit
and I am scared, okay?
So I say we get the fuck out of here now,
tonight, okay?
You run, you die.
Come on, think about it.
This was never about money for us.
It was about us against the system.
That system that kills the human spirit.
We stand for something.
To those dead souls inching along
the freeways in their metal coffins...
...we show them
that the human spirit is still alive.
So you trust me?
Okay.
Then don't worry about this guy.
I know exactly what to do with him.
A lawyer. You lied to me.
Tyler, put the gun down.
I'll bet you lied about everything.
I'll bet you lied about your parents.
You just tell me the truth, Johnny.
Did your parents die in a car accident?
Did they?
They live in Columbus, Ohio.
I work Bank Robbery. The guys I'm after
are surfers. I needed you at first...
- ...but after that I...
- Fuck you.
Don't you have a soul?
- Goddamn you to hell.
- Tyler...
Tyler, wait!
Tyler!
- Leave a message.
- Tyler, look, I fucked up, okay?
I know I fucked up.
I wanted to tell you but I couldn't.
I was afraid you'd leave.
Good guess, huh?
Fuck.
Why Can't I ever say what I really mean?
I lied to you.
I'm an asshole, but I need you, Tyler.
I went you to know that I've never known
anyone like you before in my life...
...and I hope you change your mind.
Tyler, wait. I'm coming.
Howdy, bro.
So come on, we're rolling.
What's going on, Bodhi?
Whoa, what happened?
Cut yourself shaving?
I don't think I wanna surf right now.
Surf? No, this is different, Johnny.
This is really different.
You are gonna love it.
So we gotta get your stuff
and get out of here.
Okay, uh, socks...
...shirt.
And then, uh, boots. Here we go.
Okay, put the stuff on in the truck.
We gotta go. Life is short.
You are gonna love this.
- Whoo!
- Yo.
- Finally, we're here.
- All right, let's unload.
You take this bag, Grommet.
- Come on.
- Nathaniel, wait a minute.
- Take this too.
- Thank you, sir. There you go.
Ever done this before?
No, but I've seen it on TV.
It's 100 percent pure adrenaline.
Other guys snort for it, jab a vein for it.
All you gotta do is jump.
Sure, it's a blast. But listen,
I sort of screwed my knee up yesterday.
Oh, yeah, I noticed you limping,
but, hey, don't worry, bro.
Don't worry, because
we're not gonna land on land.
Oh, well, fine then. I feel so much better.
Okay, let's fly.
Three minutes.
This is a ceremony we always do at the end
of the summer. One last speed star.
- Yeah.
By the way, you might wanna pull
that orange thing sometime.
The life you save may be your own.
So, uh...
...who packed my Chute?
I did. Why? You don't trust me?
You gotta earn trust.
Okay, we'll earn it together.
Here, take mine.
Hey, Johnny, I don't think
this is such a good idea.
Bodhi's packs are pretty shitty.
They only open about half the time.
- Less.
- Bullshit.
Why don't you take young Grommet's here?
How'd that be?
No, you don't want this one, man.
This one's set for a neck-breaker.
You'd probably be better off
with something like this.
Are we gonna jump or jerk off?
That's my man. Ha, ha.
- Here we go.
- Yeah, let's do it.
Johnny, you're about to jump out
of a perfectly good airplane.
How you feel about that?
Geronimo!
Shit! Whoa, Shit!
Whoa!
Sex with the gods!
You can't beat this!
This is fucking beautiful!
Whoo-hoo!
Whoa!
Yeah! Yeah! Yeah! Ha!
Come on, Johnny.
That's it, Johnny. Go for it.
You can do it.
Come on.
Use your arms. Fly like an eagle, baby.
Whoo!
Keep coming.
All right.
- Johnny, you did it.
- You're a speed star.
We're going like a bat out of hell.
Whoo-hoo!
- Right.
- Right, you're a speed star.
- How do you like it, Johnny?
- Amazing!
Fucking amazing!
This is so beautiful!
I love this ground-rush shit!
Okay. Break.
Great, isn't it?
You're doing good.
A thousand feet, pull.
After you, Alphonse. I insist.
- Pull the ripcord now.
- You first.
- Okay.
- Son of a bitch.
Jesus Christ.
I gotta be losing it.
It's the closest you'll ever get to God.
Like the palm of your hand.
Coming right at you.
- Unbelievable.
- It's ineffable.
- Indescribable.
- An experience to share.
- We did pull pretty low.
- You'll never be the same again.
- Didn't I tell you Johnny'd be just fine?
- Yeah. Damn first.
Hey, Johnny,
you can drop your chute right there.
Good job.
Pack off your shoulders.
Kick it back, step out of it.
- I'll pack that for you, Bodhi.
- Okay. Thanks.
Johnny, come here.
There's something you need to see.
Hop in.
Okay, fucking...
What's this?
This is an insurance policy.
It will sting a bit, but, uh, it's
for your own growth, bro. Press play.
Help!
Fuck you!
She is a wild one,
isn't she, Special Agent Utah?
You're a fucking dead man!
Whoa. Whoa. Hold it, man.
Think. Think it through, man.
I'm the only one that knows
where she is.
I'm the only one, so let me talk.
Let me talk.
Talk.
She'll be fine. Rosie won't do anything...
...as long as I meet him at a certain place
and time six hours from now.
You call him right now
and tell him to let her go.
Sorry, I can't do it, bro.
They're on the road.
And where they're going...
...there are no phones,
so you are shit out of luck.
Oh, man.
I hate this, Johnny.
I really do. I hate violence.
See, that's why I need Rosie.
I could never do that, man.
I could never hold a knife to Tyler's throat.
She was my woman.
We shared time.
But Rosie is a mechanism, you know?
Once you set him in motion,
he will not stop.
He's, like, got this gift of blankness.
But when 3:00 comes...
...he will gut her like a pig
and try not to get any on his shoes.
And there's nothing I can do about it
unless I get there.
So I guess that makes us partners.
Because we both have the same goal.
To get me where I need to go, right?
We're wasting time.
Oh, that's what I love about you, Johnny.
You are just as sharp as a razor.
Murphy, take the plane down
to Santa Monica. Top off the tanks.
- All right.
- Guys, it's party time. Let's move it.
All right. We're on it.
All I'm asking for is 90 seconds
of your life, Johnny. That's it.
You see? It's a basic dog psychology.
If you scare them and get them
peeing down their leg, they submit.
Yet if you project weakness,
you draw aggression.
That's how people get hurt.
You see, fear causes hesitation...
...and hesitation will cause your worst fears
to come true.
So it's simple.
You project strength to avoid conflict.
Peace through superior firepower.
Oh.
There you go.
Can't have you walking through those doors
with your dick in your hand, right?
I can't do this.
Sure you can.
Who knows? You might like it.
It's a killer rush.
Bodhi,
this is your fucking wake-up call, man.
I am an FBI agent.
I know, man. Isn't it wild?
That's what makes it great, Johnny.
We can exist on a different plane,
we can make our own rules.
Why be a servant to the law
when you can be its master?
- Fucking A.
- I love this fucking job.
Okay.
Ninety seconds, door-to-door.
It's a small price to pay
for someone who loves you.
She does, you know.
It's not her style to fall so hard.
I don't think she did with me.
Okay. Mr. Carter.
LBJ.
Mr. Nixon.
Well.
Sorry, Johnny.
Looks like you don't get to be president.
Ha, ha.
I'm ready.
Rock 'n' roll.
Everybody freeze!
- Okay. On the floor now. Do it.
- On the floor right now.
Hold it. Where are you going?
- Everybody down!
- Okay, let's go. I got his gun.
What are you doing, man?
On the floor, asshole.
What's your problem? I'll blow out your
fucking kneecaps, you'll be on the floor.
A kick in the ass, ain't it, man?
Hey, look, you're on TV. Smile.
- Could be little hard to play FBI now, huh?
- Can we just get the goddamn money...
...and get out of here?
Nobody move.
Heads down, eyes down.
Good afternoon, ladies and gentlemen.
May I have your attention, please?
We are the ex-presidents.
And as you can see,
we are, in fact, robbing your bank.
So with a little cooperation,
I won't have to blow your heads off.
So I need just a couple of minutes
of your lives, and we're gone.
Dick. Dick, go to the vault.
Uh, you, Miss Jennings.
Would you be a dear
and open the gate for my associate now?
- Mr. Duggan's got the keys.
- Why are we going to the vault?
- We never go to the vault.
- Just do it.
Lyndon, go with them.
We're hitting the vault, man. Go, go.
Who's Mr. Fucking Duggan?
Mr. Duggan, do you wanna open the vault
or do you want me to do it?
Do whatever they want, Terry.
Take the fucking keys! Take them!
Move it.
Open the damn door!
I'll fucking blow your fucking head off!
Move it!
Come on, now.
Get out of the way.
Okay.
- All right.
- Go for the back. Big bills.
Fucking going in the fucking vault.
- Okay.
- This is a bad idea.
On the ground. Don't look at me.
You're blowing it, man.
You're breaking your own rules.
You're pulling too much time.
Jimmy, how we doing?
- Sixty-five. What's happening?
- Don't worry, man. It's fine. It's great.
Fuck. Fuck.
Hey.
I'm a cop.
So?
- I'm a cop.
- Oh, no. Don't.
You got a gun on your ankle?
- Yeah.
- When I make the move, you back me up.
- Please don't. Don't. You don't have to.
- You back me up.
No. Don't do it. Don't do anything.
Oh, no, don't, don't.
Just put it away.
Please, put it away. Put it away.
Come on, hurry up.
Let's go. We gotta go. Let's go.
Fucking move.
Federal agent. Undercover.
Nobody fucking move!
Are you all right?
Hang on. Hang on, little brother. Come on.
We're out of here. We are out of here.
Hang on. Okay, I'll get you out of here.
- Hang on, little brother. Just hang on, man.
- Help me, Bodhi.
No, please. No.
Are you out of your fucking mind?
What's the matter with you? Is that what
you want? Did you get what you wanted?
Come on, you can't take him with.
Let's go!
Goddamn it. Who's in charge of this
camera crew? This is a crime scene.
- Get them the fuck out of here.
- Come on. Out.
You have the right to remain silent.
Anything you say can and will be used
against you in a court of law.
If you so desire, an attorney
will be provided for you free of cost.
Now, do you understand these rights
I've just given you, Utah?
Do you understand? Understand the rights
I've just read you, Utah?
Hey.
He understands his goddamn rights.
Jesus Christ, kid, are you okay?
Stand up. Get these cuffs off.
- Leave the cuffs on.
- Off.
- Leave them on!
- Oh, boy.
Your partner's an accessory to murder,
understand?
Utah, there are three dead people,
one's a police officer.
Let me show you something, pal.
- How does that sit in your stomach, huh?
- Take your hands off me right now.
Harp. Harp.
Listen. Look at me. Look at me.
Don't send him in with the black and whites
like some punk. Let me ride him in.
Yeah, sure, Angelo, why not?
That's why
I put you two screw-ups together.
You deserve each other, don't you?
You're just as bad as he is.
Only you're a little fatter, slower,
and more pathetic.
It's like the blind leading the blind.
Harp, I wanna tell you something.
I was in this bureau when you were
still popping zits on your funny face...
...and jacking off to the lingerie section
of the Sears catalog.
- Is that right, Pappas?
- Yes, that's right, Harp.
And there's one thing that I learned out
of all these years that you still haven't got.
Oh, yeah?
Why don't you astonish me, shitface?
Respect for my elders.
God. Jesus.
Plain and simple. Come on, kid. Let's go.
- Holy shit.
- Let's get out of here.
Go, please.
I know where they're going.
I figured you did.
Santa Monica Airport, fast.
- But we've got one minor problem.
- What?
We can't arrest them or shoot them.
What?
- Did you set this altimeter?
- One thousand.
- What?
Check the rigging, okay?
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
Fucking FBI.
I'm not armed.
- But you're not alone.
- Good guess.
There's a gun on you right now.
- Where's Roach?
- He's around somewhere.
So listen, Johnny, we are
in kind of a hurry. What do you need?
You gotta tell me where she is.
Oh, and let my policy expire. Good idea.
Look, Bodhi, man, people are dead.
The ride is over.
Oh, no, no. I say when it's over.
The guy you killed was an off-duty cop.
They'll nail you wherever you land.
There's a new thing called radar.
Maybe you've heard of it.
What is your...?
Nathaniel, get in there.
- Get back in the cockpit. Move.
- Yeah.
I know you, man.
When they fall on you,
you won't back down.
They'll have to burn your ass
to the ground.
Uh-huh. And shit happens.
Look, you got a death wish.
You wanna ride to glory, fine.
But don't take Tyler with you.
I'm begging you.
Tell me where she is, then I walk away.
- You walk away?
- I walk away.
That is beautiful, Johnny.
Angelo, don't fire!
They'll kill her! NO!
Get out of the way, kid. Goddamn it.
Damn.
No!
Jesus Christ.
- Angelo.
- I don't have much...
- Come on, man, just hang on.
- I'm really fucked up.
Just hang on. You'll be all right.
- I'm not flying you guys to San Felipe.
- Get in the plane. Start those engines.
Oh, good. Tell him where we're going.
Let's go, man.
We are gonna ride this all the way, Johnny,
you and me. So let's go.
Get the fuck up! Tyler's waiting!
Start the engines now!
Go!
Go, go, go, go, go.
Rosie? Yo, Rosie, this is Air Force One.
Do you read me? Do you read me? Over.
Look, man, we've been over Mexico
for the last half hour.
Can I quit mowing the lawn here?
Getting more bushes in the wheels
than I like.
Shut your mouth and take it to 4000 feet
on this heading, all right?
- All right.
- I don't think that's a good idea, man.
We'll pop up on their screens.
It doesn't matter. We're almost there.
Just gotta get you to a safe jump altitude.
Hey, let's get your rig on.
Hey, man, I'm cold. I'm really cold.
All right, your jacket.
Here's your jacket. Easy.
Oh, fuck.
I know, I know, I know.
- Easy. Easy. One arm at a time.
- I can't get it. I can't get it.
No, man. No, don't, don't, don't.
Johnny...
...throw me that money bag.
Now.
You're cold because blood
is running out of your body, Roach.
You're going to be dead soon.
I hope it was worth it.
Don't listen to him, he's just scared.
You just keep thinking
about all those senoritas and margaritas...
...that are gonna be nursing you back
to health, okay?
What the fuck are you looking at?
Fuck.
- Okay. Okay.
- There you go.
Rosie.
Rosie, this is Air Force One.
Do you copy? Do you copy? Over.
Copy. We have a visual on you.
Tell him to release Tyler.
Do it. Do it now.
You won, you got what you wanted.
What if your Chute fails?
Cancel the order.
She's served her purpose. Do it, man.
You owe me that much.
- Okay, you ready?
- Yeah.
On three. One, two, three.
Easy. Come on, a little more.
- Get your Chute clear. Okay?
- Yeah, okay.
Easy, easy.
Okay.
- I'll see you on the ground, all right?
- All right.
I'll see you in hell, Johnny.
I know it's hard for you, Johnny.
I know you want me so bad,
it's like acid in your mouth...
...but not this time.
Adios, amigo.
Fucked.
- Unh! What?
- Pull the chute, Bodhi.
- You are crazy.
- Pull the fucking Chute!
Why don't you pull it?
No games, Bodhi. Pull the cord now.
No, you pull it.
Go ahead, Johnny, pull it.
You gotta drop the gun, right?
You use your other hand,
what are you gonna hold on with?
Pull it right now, or I blow
your fucking head off and pull it myself!
- It's the only way it's gonna happen. Do it.
- Swear to God, I will!
Do it, man. Do it
or you're gonna die, Johnny!
Six seconds,
we're gonna be meat waffles.
Five, four...
- You're fucking Crazy. Pull it! Pull it!
- ...three, two...
- ...one.
- Shit!
Shit!
Jesus Christ, Bodhi.
Goddamn,
you are one radical son of a bitch.
I'm out of here, Johnny.
That knee again, huh?
Too bad. Looks like this time,
you won't be getting your man.
This game, we both lose.
Let her go.
- Johnny, I...
- Shh.
Some other time.
Come on, we're out of here.
Yo, Johnny!
I'll see you in the next life.
We can't leave him. We gotta bury him.
There's no time, man.
The cyclone warning
is current for coastal areas...
...between Torquay and Cape Otway.
Experts are saying this is potentially one
of the worst storms in Australia's history.
Heavy reins will continue into the night
with destructive winds...
...reaching up to 150 kilometers
per hour.
The center of the cyclone
is now expected to cross the coast...
...between Bell's Beach and Bay Haven
early tomorrow morning.
Residents are advised
to prepare for evacuation.
What do you wanna do now?
- I wanna get out of this mess.
- I'm freezing.
- Sorry, mate.
- Anybody been out there?
No one's been out
and no one's going out.
You gotta be fucking crazy, man.
Death on a stick out there, mate.
Wiping me out, man.
Lose something, bro?
Special Agent Utah.
I knew I could count on you.
I've been to every city in Mexico.
Came across an unclaimed piece of meat
in Baja, turned out to be Rosie.
Guess he picked a knife fight
with somebody better.
Found a passport of yours in Sumatra,
missed you by about a week in Fiji.
But I knew you wouldn't miss
the 50-year storm, Bodhi.
Yeah.
Too bad.
You finally get your waves
and it's totally closed out.
Just waiting for my set.
You gotta go down.
You crossed the line
and people trusted you and they died.
Yeah, it went bad, went real bad.
Life sure has a sick sense of humor,
doesn't it?
Still surfing?
Every day.
Come on, Bodhi.
It's time to go.
You know you gotta go back with me.
Sorry, my friend.
Come on.
Shit.
No! No!
I told them...
...you'd go quietly.
No!
You know there's no way
I can handle a cage, man.
I don't care. You gotta go down.
It's gotta be that way.
- Fellows, with me.
- Yes, sir.
You handle the left side.
Okay, man. Okay.
I'm screwed.
I'm gonna go to jail and I'll pay,
and Johnny Utah gets his guy. Right?
Good for you. That's real good.
You're gonna be a big hero now.
But look at it, Johnny. Look at it.
This is a once-in-a-lifetime opportunity,
man.
Just let me go out there,
let me get one wave before you take me.
One wave.
Now, where am I gonna go, man?
Cliffs on both sides.
I'm not gonna paddle to New Zealand.
My whole life has been about this moment,
Johnny.
Come on, compadre.
Come on.
- Here, this way.
- Come on!
What the fuck, Utah?
- What do you think you're doing?
- You let him go.
No, I didn't.
No way.
Hey, the guy's nuts.
Damn.
We'll get him when he comes back in.
He's not coming back.