Movie & Captions Conformed By :
KoushiK DaS
[ koushik-das@wassup.co.in ]
[ koushik@moviefan.com ]
" Hope You'll Like & Enjoy The Movie !!! "
Subtitle downloaded with
Sublight (www.sublight.me)
Boy: IN THE DECADE
OF THE 1930s,
EVEN THE GREAT CITY
OF METROPOLIS
WAS NOT SPARED THE RAVAGES
OF THE WORLDWIDE DEPRESSION.
IN THE TIMES
OF FEAR AND CONFUSION,
THE JOB OF INFORMING
THE PUBLIC
WAS THE RESPONSIBILITY
OF THEDAILY PLANET...
A GREAT METROPOLITAN NEWSPAPER
WHOSE REPUTATION
FOR CLARITY AND TRUTH
HAD BECOME A SYMBOL OF HOPE
FOR THE CITY OF METROPOLIS.
THIS IS NO FANTASY,
NO CARELESS PRODUCT
OF WILD IMAGINATION.
NO, MY GOOD FRIENDS...
THESE INDICTMENTS
THAT I HAVE
BROUGHT YOU TODAY...
THE SPECIFIC CHARGES
LISTED HEREIN
AGAINST THE INDIVIDUALS,
THEIR ACTS OF TREASON,
THEIR ULTIMATE AIM
OF SEDITION.
THESE...
ARE MATTERS
OF UNDENIABLE FACT.
I ASK YOU NOW
TO PRONOUNCE JUDGMENT
ON THOSE ACCUSED.
ON THIS,
THIS MINDLESS ABERRATION,
WHOSE ONLY MEANS
OF EXPRESSION
ARE WANTON VIOLENCE
AND DESTRUCTION.
ON THE WOMAN URSA,
WHOSE PERVERSIONS
AND UNREASONING HATRED
OF ALL MANKIND
HAVE THREATENED
EVEN THE CHILDREN
OF THE PLANET KRYPTON.
FINALLY,
GENERAL ZOD.
ONCE TRUSTED
BY THIS COUNCIL,
CHARGED WITH
MAINTAINING THE DEFENSE
OF THE PLANET
KRYPTON ITSELF.
CHIEF ARCHITECT
OF THIS INTENDED REVOLUTION
AND AUTHOR
OF THIS INSIDIOUS PLOT
TO ESTABLISH
A NEW ORDER AMONGST US
WITH HIMSELF
AS ABSOLUTE RULER.
YOU HAVE HEARD
THE EVIDENCE.
THE DECISION OF THE COUNCIL
WILL NOW BE HEARD.
GUILTY!
THE VOTE MUST BE
UNANIMOUS, JOR-EL.
IT HAS THEREFORE NOW
BECOME YOUR DECISION.
YOU ALONE WILL
CONDEMN US IF YOU WISH,
AND YOU ALONE WILL BE
HELD RESPONSIBLE BY ME.
JOIN US!
YOU'VE BEEN KNOWN TO DISAGREE
WITH THE COUNCIL BEFORE.
YOURS COULD BECOME AN IMPORTANT
VOICE IN THE NEW ORDER,
SECOND ONLY TO MY OWN!
I OFFER YOU A CHANCE
FOR GREATNESS, JOR-EL!
TAKE IT!
JOIN US!
YOU WILL BOW DOWN
BEFORE ME, JOR-EL!
I SWEAR IT!
NO MATTER THAT
IT TAKES AN ETERNITY!
YOUWILLBOW DOWN
BEFORE ME!
BOTH YOU...
AND THEN ONE DAY...
YOUR HEIRS!
[RUMBLING]
FORGIVE ME!
AN UNPLEASANT DUTY
HAS BEEN MASTERLY
PERFORMED, JOR-EL.
THEY HAVE RECEIVED
THE FATE THEY DESERVED--
ISOLATION
IN THE PHANTOM ZONE,
AN ETERNAL LIVING DEATH.
A CHANCE FOR LIFE,
NONETHELESS--
AS OPPOSED TO US.
IT'S SUICIDE!
NO. IT'S WORSE.
IT'S GENOCIDE.
BE WARNED, JOR-EL.
THE COUNCIL HAS
ALREADY EVALUATED
THIS OUTLANDISH
THEORY OF YOURS.
MY FRIENDS,
YOU KNOW ME TO BE
NEITHER RASH
NOR IMPULSIVE.
I AM NOT GIVEN TO WILD,
UNSUPPORTED STATEMENTS.
AND I TELL YOU
THAT WE MUST
EVACUATE THIS PLANET
IMMEDIATELY.
JOR-EL, YOU ARE ONE OF
KRYPTON'S GREATEST SCIENTISTS.
AH, YES,
BUT SO IS MISS MONDA.
IT ISN'T THAT
I QUESTION YOUR DATA.
THE FACTS
ARE UNDENIABLE.
IT'S YOUR CONCLUSIONS
WE FIND UNSUPPORTABLE.
THIS PLANET WILL EXPLODE
WITHIN 30 DAYS,
IF NOT SOONER.
KRYPTON IS SIMPLY
SHIFTING ITS ORBIT.
JOR-EL,
BE REASONABLE.
MY FRIEND...
I HAVE NEVER
BEEN OTHERWISE.
THIS MADNESS IS YOURS.
THIS DISCUSSION
IS TERMINATED.
THE DECISION
OF THE COUNCIL IS FINAL.
ANY ATTEMPT BY YOU
TO CREATE A CLIMATE
OF FEAR AND PANIC
AMONG THE POPULACE
MUST BE DEEMED BY US
AN ACT OF INSURRECTION.
YOU WOULD ACCUSE ME
OF INSURRECTION?
HAS IT NOW BECOME
A CRIME TO CHERISH LIFE?
YOU WOULD BE BANISHED
TO ENDLESS IMPRISONMENT
IN THE PHANTOM ZONE--
THE ETERNAL VOID
WHICH YOU YOURSELF
DISCOVERED.
WILL YOU ABIDE BY
THE COUNCIL'S DECISION?
I WILL REMAIN SILENT.
NEITHER I...
NOR MY WIFE
WILL LEAVE KRYPTON.
[BABY CRIES]
HAVE YOU FINISHED?
NEARLY.
IT'S THE ONLY
ANSWER, LARA.
IF HE REMAINS
HERE WITH US,
HE WILL DIE
AS SURELY AS WE WILL.
BUT WHY EARTH,
JOR-EL?
THEY'RE THOUSANDS
OF YEARS BEHIND US.
HE WILL NEED THAT
ADVANTAGE TO SURVIVE.
THEIR ATMOSPHERE...
WILL SUSTAIN HIM.
HE WILL DEFY
THEIR GRAVITY.
HE WILL LOOK
LIKE ONE OF THEM.
HE WON'TBE
ONE OF THEM.
NO.
HIS DENSE
MOLECULAR STRUCTURE
WILL MAKE HIM STRONG.
HE WILL BE ODD...
DIFFERENT.
HE'LL BE FAST,
VIRTUALLY
INVULNERABLE.
ISOLATED...
ALONE.
HE WILL NOT
BE ALONE.
HE WILL NEVER BE ALONE.
Official: THE ENERGY INPUT
TO JOR-EL'S QUARTERS
IS NOW IN EXCESS.
OUR DATA
INDICATES THE LOSS
IS DUE TO
A MISUSE OF ENERGY.
INVESTIGATE.
AND IF THE INVESTIGATION
PROVES CORRECT?
HE KNEW THE PENALTY
HE FACED,
EVEN AS A MEMBER
OF THIS COUNCIL.
THE LAW WILL BE UPHELD.
[RUMBLING]
[CRYING]
YOU WILL TRAVEL FAR,
MY LITTLE KAL-EL.
BUT WE WILL NEVER
LEAVE YOU,
EVEN IN THE FACE
OF OUR DEATH.
THE RICHNESS
OF OUR LIVES...
IT WILL BE YOURS.
ALL THAT I HAVE,
ALL THAT I'VE LEARNED,
EVERYTHING I FEEL,
ALL THIS
AND MORE, I--
I BEQUEATH YOU,
MY SON.
YOU WILL CARRY ME
INSIDE YOU
ALL THE DAYS
OF YOUR LIFE.
YOU WILL MAKE
MY STRENGTH YOUR OWN,
SEE MY LIFE
THROUGH YOUR EYES,
AS YOUR LIFE
WILL BE SEEN THROUGH MINE.
THE SON
BECOMES THE FATHER
AND THE FATHER,
THE SON.
THIS IS ALL I...
ALL I CAN SEND YOU...
KAL-EL.
[RUMBLING]
[CRASH]
[EXPLOSION]
[SCREAMING]
Jor-el: ...WHICH EINSTEIN
CALLED HIS THEORY OF RELATIVITY.
EMBEDDED IN THE CRYSTALS
BEFORE YOU
IS THE TOTAL ACCUMULATION
OF ALL LITERATURE
AND SCIENTIFIC FACT
FROM DOZENS OF OTHER WORLDS,
SPANNING
THE 28 KNOWN GALAXIES.
EARLY CHINESE WRITINGS
POINT OUT
THE COMPLEX RELATIONSHIPS...
BY CARRYING
THIS COMPLEX EQUATION
TO ITS ULTIMATE POWER,
MY SON...
...CHIEF AMONG THESE POWERS
WILL BE YOUR SIGHT,
YOUR STRENGTH,
YOUR HEARING,
YOUR ABILITY TO PROPEL YOURSELF
AT ALMOST LIMITLESS SPEED.
THE EARLY HISTORY
OF OUR UNIVERSE
WAS A BLOODY MOSAIC
OF INTERPLANETARY WAR.
EACH OF THE 6 GALAXIES
WHICH YOU WILL PASS THROUGH
CONTAIN THEIR OWN
INDIVIDUAL LAWS
IN SPACE AND TIME.
IT IS FORBIDDEN FOR YOU TO
INTERFERE WITH HUMAN HISTORY.
WHOA!
WHAT WAS THAT?
NOW WOULDN'T THAT
BEAT ALL GET OUT.
WILL YOU--YOU...
HUH?
OH, PA!
OH, MY.
UHH!
ALL THESE YEARS,
AS HAPPY AS WE'VE BEEN,
HOW I'VE PRAYED
THE GOOD LORD
WOULD SEE FIT
TO GIVE US A CHILD.
HONEY, WILL YOU
HAND ME THAT RAG?
TAKE THINGS
EASY NOW, JONATHAN.
REMEMBER WHAT DOC FRYE
SAID ABOUT YOUR HEART.
[CHUCKLES]
NOW, THE FIRST THING WE'VE
GOT TO DO WHEN WE GET HOME
IS FIND OUT WHO THAT BOY'S
PROPER FAMILY IS.
HE HASN'T GOT ANY.
NOT AROUND HERE,
ANYWAY.
MARTHA, ARE YOU THINKING
WHAT I THINK
YOU'RE THINKING?
WE COULD SAY
HE'S THE CHILD
OF MY COUSIN
IN NORTH DAKOTA
AND JUST NOW ORPHANED.
OH, MARTHA!
JONATHAN,
HE'S ONLY A BABY.
MARTHA, NOW, YOU SAW
HOW WE FOUND HIM.
MARTHA CLARK KENT,
ARE YOU LISTENING
TO WHAT I'M SAYING?
JONATHAN!
[CREAK]
[BLOWS WHISTLE]
COME ON, GANG!
COME ON!
LET'S GO!
YEAH, BUT NEXT WEEK...
OOH! ALL RIGHT!
COME ON, GANG,
HUSTLE!
LET'S GO!
STACK YOUR
HELMETS NEATLY.
REMEMBER ABOUT
THOSE UNIFORMS!
CLEANED AND WASHED
BY TOMORROW
AND LOOKING LIKE
A FOOTBALL TEAM!
HEY, CLARK,
LET'S HAVE
ALL THOSE CLOTHES
WASHED AND READY
FOR TOMORROW'S GAME.
GOT TO BEAT
MOUNT VERNON!
GIVE ME A LIFT?
LANA?
DON'T BOTHER
WITH THESE, HUH?
I'LL TAKE THEM IN WITH
THE OTHER EQUIPMENT.
THANK YOU, CLARK.
SURE.
A BUNCH OF US ARE
GOING TO MARY ELLEN'S
TO PLAY SOME RECORDS.
WOULD YOU
LIKE TO COME?
SURE.
SOUNDS LIKE
IT WOULD BE FUN.
KENT CAN'T MAKE IT.
STILL GOT WORK TO DO.
I JUST FINISHED
STACKING ALL THE--
ALL THAT?
OH, BRAD.
HEY,
COME ON, LANA!
COME ON, LANA.
COME ON.
LET'S GO!
BYE, CLARK.
YEAH. BYE.
CLEAN THIS UP,
CLARK.
LET'S GO!
WE'RE OFF
TO MARY ELLEN'S!
ALL RIGHT!
BYE, CLARK.
[HONK HONK]
SEE YOU TOMORROW.
BYE-BYE.
[TRAIN WHISTLE BLOWS]
[WHISTLE BLOWS]
WHOO-HOO!
GOLLY!
I SAW A BOY OUT THERE WHO
RAN AS FAST AS THE TRAIN.
FASTER, EVEN.
HA HA! LOIS LANE,
YOU HAVE A WRITER'S GIFT
FOR INVENTION.
I'LL SAY THAT FOR YOU.
BUT--BUT--
LOIS, PLEASE READ
YOUR BOOK.
NO ONE EVER
BELIEVES ME.
[TEENS SHOUT]
Radio: ?? WE'LL HAVE SOME FUN
WHEN THE CLOCK STRIKES ONE ??
?? WE'RE GONNA ROCK
AROUND THE CLOCK TONIGHT ??
?? WE'RE GONNA ROCK, ROCK, ROCK
TILL BROAD DAYLIGHT ??
?? WE'RE GONNA ROCK, GONNA ROCK
AROUND THE CLOCK TONIGHT ??
?? WHEN THE CLOCK
STRIKES TWO... ??
HEY, LOOK,
THERE'S CLARK!
HOW COME HE'S HERE?
CLARK!
HOW'D YOU GET HERE
SO FAST?
I RAN.
RAN, HUH? TOLD YOU
HE'S AN ODDBALL.
LET'S GET
OUT OF HERE.
?? ...SIX AND SEVEN ??
?? WE'LL BE RIGHT
IN SEVENTH HEAVEN ??
?? WE'RE GONNA ROCK... ??
BEEN SHOWING OFF A BIT,
HAVEN'T YOU, SON?
UM...
I DIDN'T MEAN
TO SHOW OFF, PA.
IT'S JUST THAT
GUYS LIKE BRAD--
I WANT TO TEAR
THEM APART.
I KNOW.
YEAH, I KNOW
I SHOULDN'T.
YOU CAN DO ALL
THESE AMAZING THINGS,
AND SOMETIMES YOU THINK
THAT YOU WILL JUST BUST
UNLESS YOU CAN TELL
PEOPLE ABOUT IT.
EVERY TIME I GET
THE FOOTBALL,
I CAN MAKE A TOUCHDOWN.
IS IT SHOWING OFF
IF SOMEBODY'S DOING
THE THINGS
HE'S CAPABLE OF DOING?
IS A BIRD SHOWING OFF
WHEN IT FLIES?
NO. LISTEN TO ME.
WHEN YOU CAME TO US,
WE THOUGHT THAT PEOPLE
WOULD TAKE YOU AWAY
WHEN THEY FOUND OUT
THE THINGS YOU COULD DO,
AND THAT
WORRIED US A LOT.
THEN A MAN GETS OLDER,
HE THINKS DIFFERENTLY,
AND THINGS GET
VERY CLEAR.
THERE IS ONE THING
I DO KNOW, SON--
YOU ARE HERE
FOR A REASON.
I DON'T KNOW
WHOSE REASON,
WHATEVER
THE REASON IS.
MAYBE
IT'S BECAUSE, UM...
I DON'T KNOW,
IT'S, UH...
BUT I DO KNOW
ONE THING.
IT'S NOT TO SCORE
TOUCHDOWNS.
HUH?
THANKS, DAD.
I'LL RACE YOU TO IT.
YOU WILL, HUH?
COME ON, RUN. COME ON!
COME ON, RUN.
[DOG BARKS]
HEY, BARON! HEY, BOY.
OH, NO!
WHAT DID YOU DO
TODAY, BARON?
DID YOU MISS ME?
JONATHAN?
JONATHAN!
DAD.
NO!
OH!
JONATHAN!
NO!
ALL THOSE THINGS
I CAN DO...
ALL THOSE POWERS...
AND I COULDN'T
EVEN SAVE HIM.
[STATIC FROM RADIO]
[ANIMAL HOWLS]
[DOG BARKING]
[ROOSTER CROWING]
CLARK, GET UP!
GOOD MORNING, SMILEY.
[CHIRPS]
CLARK, BREAKFAST!
ARE YOU GOING TO SLEEP
ALL DAY?
COME ON, GET UP!
[ROOSTER CROWS]
[DOG BARKING]
I HAVE TO LEAVE.
I KNEW THIS TIME
WOULD COME.
WE BOTH KNEW IT
FROM THE DAY
WE FOUND YOU.
I TALKED TO
BEN HUBBARD YESTERDAY,
AND...
HE SAID THAT
HE'D BE HAPPY
TO HELP OUT
FROM NOW ON.
MOTHER...
I KNOW, SON.
I KNOW.
DO YOU KNOW WHERE
YOU'RE HEADED?
NORTH.
REMEMBER US, SON.
ALWAYS REMEMBER US.
[RUMBLING]
Jor-el: MY SON...
YOU DO NOT REMEMBER ME.
I AM JOR-EL.
I AM YOUR FATHER.
BY NOW, YOU WILL HAVE REACHED
YOUR 18th YEAR
AS IT IS MEASURED ON EARTH.
BY THAT RECKONING,
I WILL HAVE BEEN DEAD
FOR MANY THOUSANDS
OF YOUR YEARS.
THE KNOWLEDGE THAT I HAVE,
MATTERS PHYSICAL AND HISTORIC,
I'VE GIVEN YOU FULLY
ON YOUR VOYAGE
TO YOUR NEW HOME.
THESE ARE IMPORTANT MATTERS,
TO BE SURE,
BUT STILL MATTERS OF MERE FACT.
THERE ARE QUESTIONS
TO BE ASKED,
AND IT IS TIME
FOR YOU TO DO SO.
HERE IN THIS...
THIS FORTRESS OF SOLITUDE,
WE SHALL TRY TO FIND
THE ANSWERS TOGETHER.
SO, MY SON...
SPEAK.
WHO AM I?
YOUR NAME IS KAL-EL.
YOU ARE THE ONLY SURVIVOR
OF THE PLANET KRYPTON.
EVEN THOUGH YOU'VE BEEN RAISED
AS A HUMAN BEING,
YOU ARE NOT ONE OF THEM.
YOU HAVE GREAT POWERS,
ONLY SOME OF WHICH YOU HAVE
AS YET DISCOVERED.
COME WITH ME NOW, MY SON,
AS WE BREAK THROUGH THE BONDS
OF YOUR EARTHLY CONFINEMENT,
TRAVELING THROUGH TIME
AND SPACE
IN THE 6 KNOWN DIMENSIONS.
YOUR POWERS WILL FAR EXCEED
THOSE OF MORTAL MEN.
IT IS FORBIDDEN FOR YOU
TO INTERFERE
WITH HUMAN HISTORY.
RATHER LET YOUR LEADERSHIP
STIR OTHERS TO...
IN THIS NEXT YEAR, WE SHALL
EXAMINE THE HUMAN HEART.
IT IS MORE FRAGILE
THAN YOUR OWN.
FOR THE PAST 2 YEARS...
AS WE PASS THROUGH
THE FLAMING TURMOIL
WHICH IS THE EDGE
OF YOUR OWN GALAXY,
WE'LL ENTER THE REALM
OF THE RED KRYPTON SUN,
SOURCE OF YOUR STRENGTH
AND NOURISHMENT
AND CAUSE OF OUR EVENTUAL
DESTRUCTION.
THE PLANET KRYPTON,
MY SON--
YOUR HOME AS IT WAS.
THIS YEAR,
WE SHALL EXAMINE
THE VARIOUS CONCEPTS
OF IMMORTALITY
AND THEIR BASIS
IN ACTUAL FACT.
THE TOTAL ACCUMULATION
OF ALL KNOWLEDGE,
SPANNING THE 28 KNOWN GALAXIES,
IS EMBEDDED IN THE CRYSTALS
WHICH I'VE SENT ALONG WITH YOU.
STUDY THEM WELL, MY SON,
AND LEARN FROM THEM.
OVER THE PAST 12 YEARS,
WE HAVE REASONED OUT
LOGICAL JUDGMENTS.
BY THE TIME YOU RETURN
TO THE CONFINES OF YOUR GALAXY,
12 OF YOUR YEARS
WILL HAVE PASSED.
FOR THIS REASON, AMONG OTHERS,
I HAVE CHOSEN EARTH FOR YOU.
IT IS NOW TIME FOR YOU
TO REJOIN YOUR NEW WORLD
AND TO SERVE
ITS COLLECTIVE HUMANITY.
LIVE AS ONE OF THEM,
KAL-EL,
TO DISCOVER WHERE YOUR STRENGTH
AND YOUR POWER ARE NEEDED.
ALWAYS HOLD IN YOUR HEART
THE PRIDE
OF YOUR SPECIAL HERITAGE.
THEY CAN BE
A GREAT PEOPLE, KAL-EL.
THEY WISH TO BE.
THEY ONLY LACK THE LIGHT
TO SHOW THE WAY.
FOR THIS REASON ABOVE ALL,
THEIR CAPACITY FOR GOOD,
I HAVE SENT THEM YOU...
MY ONLY SON.
OK, THIS IS IT, MAC,
THEDAILY PLANET.
HEY, LADY,
HOW ABOUT A TOMATO?
HEY,
FRESH FRUIT HERE.
HEY, FRESH FRUIT
AND VEGETABLES!
FRESH FRUIT
GET THEM WHILE
THEY'RE HOT!
THEY'RE
BEAUTIFUL!
[TYPEWRITER]
[TELEPHONE RINGS]
HEY!
[RING]
SMILE.
HOW MANY Ts
IN BLOODLETTING?
2.
WHAT ARE YOU WRITING,
MISS LANE?
AN ODE TO SPRING.
HOW DO YOU SPELL
MASSACRE?
UH...M-A-S-S-A-C-R-E.
...R-E. THANK YOU.
HOW COME YOU GET
ALL THE GREAT STORIES?
A GOOD REPORTER DOESN'T
GET GREAT STORIES, JIMMY.
A GOOD REPORTER...
Both: MAKES THEM GREAT.
CHIEF, HERE'S THAT STORY
ON THE EAST SIDE MURDER.
THE WAY I SEE IT, IT'S
A BANNER HEADLINE, FRONT PAGE.
THERE'S ONLY ONE "P"
IN RAPIST.
LOIS LANE,
MEET CLARK KENT.
HI.
HOW YOU DOIN'?
JIMMY OLSEN, PHOTOGRAPHER.
CLARK KENT.
NICE TO MEET YOU.
IT'S GOT EVERYTHING--SEX,
VIOLENCE, THE ETHNIC ANGLE.
SO DOES A LADY WRESTLER
WITH A FOREIGN ACCENT.
KENT, CAN YOU
OPEN THIS?
OH, SURE, MR. WHITE.
THIS COULD BE
A SERIES OF ARTICLES.
"MAKING SENSE
OF SENSELESS KILLINGS."
WE GET PSYCHOLOGISTS,
SOCIOLOGISTS--
LOIS, YOU'RE
PUSHING A BUNCH
OF TABLOID GARBAGE.
THANK--I'M SORRY,
MR. WHITE.
OLSEN! WHY AM I PAYING
YOU $40 A WEEK
WHEN I SHOULD HAVE YOU
ARRESTED FOR LOITERING?
GO GET MR. KENT A TOWEL.
RIGHT, CHIEF.
MAKE MINE BLACK
AND NO SUGAR.
RIGHT, CHIEF.
AND DON'T
CALL ME SUGAR!
RIGHT, CHI--SUGAR.
CHIEF WANTS COFFEE,
NO SUGAR.
I'LL TAKE TEA WITH LEMON.
LOIS, WHY DON'T
YOU TAKE KENT
TO MEET EVERYBODY?
INTRODUCE HIM
AROUND.
HE'S STARTING
HERE TODAY.
I'M GIVING HIM
THE CITY BEAT.
CHIEF!
THAT'S MY BEAT!
LOIS, CLARK KENT
MAY SEEM LIKE
JUST A MILD-MANNERED
REPORTER,
BUT NOT ONLY DOES HE
TREAT ME WITH RESPECT,
NOT ONLY DOES HE HAVE
A SNAPPY PROSE STYLE,
BUT HE IS
THE FASTEST TYPIST
I'VE EVER SEEN.
EXCUSE ME.
I'M SORRY.
HERE. YOU FORGOT MY ARTICLE.
OH, UM...
MR. WHITE,
COULD YOU ARRANGE
FOR HALF MY SALARY
TO BE SENT
TO THIS ADDRESS?
YOUR BOOKIE, RIGHT?
DON'T TELL ME--
HE SENDS A CHECK
TO HIS GRAY-HAIRED MOTHER.
ACTUALLY, SHE'S
SILVER-HAIRED.
I'LL SEE
WHAT I CAN DO.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH,
MR. WHITE.
EXCUSE ME.
WELL.
ANY MORE AT HOME
LIKE YOU?
UH, NOT REALLY, NO.
I DIDN'T THINK SO.
WELL, GET YOURSELF
A DESK OVER HERE.
OVER HERE?
YEAH. THERE ARE
SOME PAPERS IN A PILE--
OH, SORRY.
EXCUSE ME.
HI. BILL FREES.
HI. CLARK KENT.
VERY NICE TO MEET YOU.
HERE'S YOUR TOWEL,
MR. CLARK.
UM...KENT.
WHAT?
KENT.
OH. CLARK KENT.
JIMMY OLSEN.
YEAH, I MET THIS
REALLY GREAT GUY.
HEY, FABULOUS.
I MET HIM
AT THIS DUDE RANCH.
OH, I GOT TO MAIL
THESE LETTERS.
GOOD LUCK TONIGHT.
OH, HI, CLARK.
HI, LOIS.
HOW WAS
YOUR FIRST DAY?
THE HOURS WERE LONGER
THAN I EXPECTED,
BUT MEETING YOU AND
JIMMY OLSEN AND MR. WHITE,
ON THE WHOLE,
I'D SAY IT'S BEEN SWELL.
SWELL?
YOU KNOW, CLARK,
THERE ARE VERY FEW
PEOPLE LEFT IN THE WORLD
WHO FEEL COMFORTABLE
SAYING THAT WORD.
WHAT WORD?
SWELL.
REALLY? I ALWAYS THOUGHT
IT WAS KIND OF NATURAL.
OOH...I'M SORRY.
CLARK!
IT'S ALL RIGHT.
SORRY, LOIS.
REX! SEE ANYTHING
GOOD TODAY?
NOT UNTIL
YOU CAME ALONG.
REX, THIS IS, UM...
CLARK KENT.
BYE.
UH...LOIS?
HEY, WHERE
ARE YOU GOING?
CAN I HELP YOU
WITH YOUR COAT?
DO YOU LIKE MR. WHITE?
I THOUGHT
HE WAS REALLY NICE.
HEY! COME HERE!
COME ON!
GET IN HERE!
LET'S GET
OUT OF HERE.
DO WHAT HE SAYS.
GET IN HERE!
DON'T...DON'T
DO ANYTHING.
WE'RE COMING.
EXCUSE ME.
GO ON, BACK THERE!
PLEASE DON'T
POINT THAT AT ME, SIR.
YOU COULD HURT SOMEBODY
WITH THAT.
OK, OK,
HOLD IT THERE!
JUST A MINUTE, MISTER.
I REALIZE OF COURSE
THAT TIMES ARE TOUGH,
BUT THIS ISN'T
THE ANSWER.
YOU CAN'T SOLVE
SOCIETY'S PROBLEMS WITH A GUN.
YOU KNOW,
YOU'RE RIGHT.
I'LL TURN OVER
A NEW LEAF.
SEE? HE DOESN'T REALLY
WANT TO HURT ANYBODY.
RIGHT AFTER I RIP OFF
THIS LADY'S PURSE.
OF COURSE.
COME ON, LADY,
HAND IT OVER.
LOIS, MAYBE YOU BETTER...
LOIS,
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
AAH!
CLARK!
CLARK, ARE YOU
ALL RIGHT?
CLARK!
WHAT HAPPENED?
GOLLY! I GUESS
I MUST HAVE FAINTED.
FAINTED?
YOU FAINTED?
SORRY.
SWELL.
REALLY, LOIS, SUPPOSING
THAT MAN HAD SHOT YOU?
IS IT WORTH
RISKING YOUR LIFE
OVER $10,
2 CREDIT CARDS,
A HAIRBRUSH,
AND A LIPSTICK?
HOW DID YOU
KNOW THAT?
KNOW WHAT?
YOU JUST DESCIBED THE EXACT
CONTENTS OF MY PURSE.
UM...WILD GUESS.
UH, TAXI!
HEY.
HI, OTIS.
[HONKS HORN]
SO WHAT'S
HAPPENIN', PARTNER?
LOOK WHAT WE GOT.
LET'S TAKE HIM.
WAIT. MAYBE HE'LL
LEAD US TO THE BIG MAN.
LEX LUTHOR?
YOU GOT IT, ARAMUS.
WE'LL MAKE CAPTAIN
BY MIDNIGHT.
HEY, WHAT DO YOU READ?
XK 101 ROCKET
TO BE USED.
HEY, MAC.
HEY, OTIS.
JUST GETTING
THEDAILY PLANETHERE.
[BARKING]
DOWN, DOWN!
OK, OK, ALL RIGHT!
SEE, I'M PAYING HIM.
I GOT A PRETZEL, TOO.
THANKS, OTIS.
HOW MANY DID
HE TAKE, SHUTZY?
THIS IS METROPOLIS 46.
WE'RE ON FOOT.
OVER AND OUT.
LET'S GO.
P.A.:
YOUR ATTENTION, PLEASE.
THE METROPOLIS FLYER
IS NOW READY FOR DEPARTURE
ON THE UPPER LEVEL,
TRACK 6,
STOPPING AT NEW ROCHELLE...
HE'S GOING
TO THE TRAIN PLATFORM.
I'M GOING AFTER HIM.
I'LL CALL
FOR BACK-UP.
BE CAREFUL.
ALL RIGHT, ARAMUS.
NOW BOARDING
ON THE LOWER LEVEL...
Man: 10 MINUTES, FOLKS.
COME ON.
AIR-CONDITIONED CARS.
MOUNT VERNON, POUGHKEEPSIE.
BOARD NOW. ALL ABOARD.
METROPOLIS TRANSPORTATION.
BUFFALO, SYRACUSE.
SMOKING CARS ARE FORWARD.
MOVE ALONG NOW.
LUGGAGE UP THE TOP.
SMOKING CARS FORWARD.
ALL ABOARD. BOARDING.
ARAMUS, ARAMUS,
MAKE IT TRACK 22.
I SEEN HIM,
AND I'M RIGHT ON HIM.
LOWER LEVEL. TRACK 22.
[TRAIN WHISTLE SOUNDS]
[BELL RINGING]
SO THAT'S IT!
IT'S AMAZING THAT BRAIN
CAN GENERATE ENOUGH POWER
TO KEEP THOSE LEGS MOVING.
[WHISTLE SOUNDS]
AAH!
HARRY!
HARRY, WHERE ARE YOU?
OH, NO.
HARRY.
SICK!
YOU'RE REALLY SICK!
SICK, MISS TESCHMACHER?
SICK, WHEN I'M MERE DAYS
FROM EXECUTING
THE CRIME
OF THE CENTURY?
STEP AWAY
FROM THAT, PLEASE.
HOW DO YOU CONGRATULATE
THE GREATEST CRIMINAL
MIND OF OUR TIME?
DO YOU TELL ME
THAT I'M BRILLIANT?
THAT WOULD BE TOO
OBVIOUS, I GRANT YOU.
CHARISMATIC!
FIENDISHLY GIFTED!
TRY TWISTED.
HA HA HA HA!
GET AWAY FROM THERE.
GET AWAY!
WHY DO SO MANY PEOPLE
HAVE TO DIE
FOR THE CRIME
OF THE CENTURY?
WHY DOES
THE PHONE ALWAYS RING
WHEN YOU'RE
IN THE BATHTUB?
WHY IS THE MOST BRILLIANTLY
DIABOLICAL LEADER OF OUR TIME
SURROUNDING HIMSELF
WITH TOTAL NINCOMPOOPS?
I'M BACK, MR. LUTHOR.
I WAS JUST
TALKING ABOUT YOU.
YOU WERE
FOLLOWED AGAIN.
IN SPITE OF
THOSE CATLIKE REFLEXES.
MR. LUTHOR...
MR. LUTHOR,
I'M SORRY.
OTIS, IS THAT THE NEWSPAPER
I ASKED YOU TO GET ME?
YEAH.
WHY AM I
NOT READING IT?
BECAUSE I HAVEN'T
GIVEN IT TO YOU YET?
RIGHT.
OH.
AT LAST
IT'S OFFICIAL.
THANKS TO
THE GENEROUS HELP
OF THE UNITED STATES
GOVERNMENT,
WE'LL BE INVOLVED
IN THE GREATEST
REAL-ESTATE SWINDLE
OF ALL TIME.
WHAT IS THIS OBSESSION
WITH REAL ESTATE?
WHEN I WAS 6,
MY FATHER SAID TO ME--
GET OUT!
HA HA. BEFORE THAT,
HE SAID, "SON...
"STOCKS
RISE AND FALL,
"UTILITIES AND
TRANSPORTATION SYSTEMS
"MAY COLLAPSE,
"PEOPLE ARE
NO DAMN GOOD,
"BUT THEY'LL ALWAYS
PAY THROUGH THE NOSE
"TO GET LAND.
REMEMBER," HE SAID--
LAND.
IT'S A PITY
THAT HE DIDN'T SEE
FROM SUCH
HUMBLE BEGINNINGS
HOW I'VE
CREATED THIS EMPIRE.
AN EMPIRE...THIS?
HOW MANY GIRLS
DO YOU KNOW WHO HAVE
A PARK AVENUE ADDRESS
LIKE THIS ONE?
PARK AVENUE ADDRESS?
200 FEET BELOW?
DO YOU REALIZE
WHAT PEOPLE ARE
SHELLING OUT UP THERE
FOR A FEW
MISERABLE ROOMS?
WHAT MORE
COULD ANYONE ASK?
OLSEN!
GET THIS LOCH NESS UPDATE
RIGHT INTO COMPOSING.
THAT'S IT, ROTH.
PUT IT TO BED.
WHY ARE YOU
STANDING AROUND HERE?
I'M NOT, CH--
I WASN'T
GOING TO SAY IT.
GO.
AH, THE SEX MANIAC PROFILE.
9 TO 5, IT'S
A PULITZER PRIZE WINNER.
THERE'S NO "Z"
IN BRASSIERE.
HEY, NICE JOB
ON THAT UNION SCANDAL, KENT.
GOSH.
THANKS, MR. WHITE.
UH...
OH, HI, CLARK.
GOOD NIGHT.
LET ME CARRY THAT.
THANKS A LOT.
LOIS, HAVE YOU
GOT A MINUTE?
UH...LOIS?
THESE TWO GO TO THE ADDRESSES
ON THE ENVELOPE.
LOIS, WOULD YOU LIKE
TO HAVE DINNER WITH ME?
I'M SORRY.
I'M BOOKED.
AIR FORCE ONE IS LANDING
AT THE AIRPORT.
I'LL BE THERE TO
MAKE SURE YOU-KNOW-WHO
ANSWERS SOME QUESTIONS.
DON'T YOU
EVER LET UP?
WHY? I'VE SEEN HOW
THE OTHER HALF LIVES.
MY SISTER HAS THREE KIDS,
TWO CATS, AND ONE MORTGAGE.
I'D GO BANANAS
IN A WEEK.
CAN I TAKE YOU
TO THE AIRPORT?
NOT UNLESS YOU CAN FLY.
UH, CLARK...LADIES.
SORRY.
LOIS,
MAYBE WE COULD--
OH. HMM.
UM...
UH, LOIS?
WOULD YOU BE A PET
AND MAIL THAT FOR ME?
SURE. UH...
GOOD NIGHT.
OH!
UH, GOING DOWN, PLEASE?
GOING DOWN?
UH, GOING DOWN?
GOING
UP, UP, UP!
GOOD NIGHT.
DAILY PLANETCOPTER ONE,
THIS IS GROUND.
PLANET ONE. GO AHEAD.
WE HAVE MISS LANE HERE
FOR A RIDE TO METROPOLIS
AIRPORT TO MEET AIR FORCE ONE.
WE'RE ON OUR WAY
AND HAVE YOU IN SIGHT.
ROGER, PLANET ONE.
YOU'RE CLEARED TO LAND.
WIND, 0-2-0 AT 1-5,
GUSTING.
ROGER, OVER AND OUT.
MALFUNCTION!
CAN'T GET LIFTOFF!
WHAT'S HAPPENING?
SET IT DOWN!
WE'VE LOST ROTOR CONTROL!
I CAN'T HOLD IT!
AAH!
OH!
I CAN'T HOLD IT!
HE'S LOST IT!
AAH!
WAKE UP!
OH, HELP!
HELP!
OH! OH!
UH!
[SIRENS]
STEP BACK, FOLKS.
ALL RIGHT!
LET'S GET BACK!
AAH! AAH!
BRING THE CANVAS OVER HERE!
SEE THE HELICOPTER
UP THERE?
HELP ME!
AAH!
[SIRENS]
MOVE BACK.
LET THE AMBULANCE THROUGH.
LET THESE FIREMEN
GET IN HERE.
HELP ME!
OH!
AAH!
GET BACK!
COME ON.
GET OFF THE STREET!
GET BACK! MOVE IT!
LET THE FIREMEN THROUGH!
BOYS, COME ON NOW.
MAKE A LINE!
MOVE TO THE OTHER SIDE
OF THE STREET!
COME ON! GET ALONG!
GET AWAY FROM THE SIDE
OF THE BUILDING.
HOLD THESE CROWDS BACK.
AAH!
HELP ME!
SAY, JIM!
EXCUSE ME.
THAT'S
A BAD OUTFIT! WHOO!
BRESSLAW,
MOVE THESE PEOPLE OUT.
UH!
AAH!
LOOK UP THERE!
WHAT THE HELL'S THAT?
EASY, MISS.
I'VE GOT YOU.
YOU--YOU'VE GOT ME?
WHO'S GOT YOU?
I CAN'T BELIEVE IT.
I CANNOT BELIEVE IT.
HE GOT HER.
OH!
GENTLEMEN,
THIS MAN NEEDS HELP.
I CERTAINLY HOPE
THIS LITTLE INCIDENT
HASN'T PUT YOU
OFF FLYING, MISS.
STATISTICALLY SPEAKING,
OF COURSE,
IT'S STILL THE SAFEST
WAY TO TRAVEL.
RIGHT.
WAIT!
WHOAREYOU?
A FRIEND.
BYE.
HI, THERE. SOMETHING WRONG
WITH THE ELEVATOR?
AAH!
GOING DOWN?
NAH.
OFFICER.
AH, GOOD EVENING,
OFFICER...MOONEY.
WELL, THEY SAY CONFESSION
IS GOOD FOR THE SOUL.
I'D LISTEN
TO THIS MAN.
TAKE HIM AWAY.
[TIRES SQUEAL]
[GUNFIRE]
[SIREN]
COME ON!
LET'S GET OUT OF HERE!
MOVE YOUR ASS!
COME ON, COME ON!
OK, LET'S GO!
LET'S GO!
DROP YOUR WEAPONS!
LET'S GET
OUT OF HERE!
HOLD IT RIGHT THERE!
OK, FREEZE,
YOU TURKEYS!
OK! DON'T SHOOT!
BAD VIBRATIONS?
YOU DON'T BELIEVE ME.
I SWEAR, FLYING.
WITH A BIG RED CAPE
AND RED BOOTS.
WATCH THE DESK.
HE FLEW UP IN THE AIR
LIKE A BIG BLUE BIRD.
A BIG BLUE BIRD
WITH RED BOOTS.
WHY DON'T YOU
TAKE THE NIGHT OFF
AND GO BACK
TO MURPHY'S BAR?
I'LL MEET YOU THERE
MYSELF.
[SIREN]
MOONEY...
THE FIRST BOTTLE'S
ON ME.
I'LL GET MY HAT.
HEY, FRISKY.
WILL YOU COME DOWN FROM THERE?
HI.
I'LL GET HIM.
COME ON.
IT'S ALL RIGHT.
HERE YOU GO, MISS.
GEE, THANKS, MISTER.
WELL...
GOOD-BYE, FRISKY.
SO LONG, NOW.
BYE.
BYE!
MOMMY, FRISKY
WAS STUCK IN THE TREE!
THIS MAN SWOOPED
OUT OF THE SKY
AND GAVE HIM TO ME!
HAVEN'T I TOLD YOU
TO STOP TELLING LIES?
METROPOLIS AIRPORT,
THIS IS AIR FORCE ONE.
COULD WE HAVE
THE LATEST WEATHER REPORT?
METROPOLIS, CURRENTLY,
CEILING 500 AND OVERCAST.
700 BROKEN VISIBILITY 1.
WIND 2-4-0 AT 2-5.
ROGER.
WELL, IT DOESN'T
LOOK TOO GOOD.
WHAT THE HELL WAS THAT?
WE LOST POWER
IN NUMBER ONE!
WE LOST
THE WHOLE ENGINE!
BRING UP
2 AND 3!
THERE'S NOT
ENOUGH PRESSURE!
MAYDAY, METROPOLIS TOWER!
AIR FORCE ONE.
WE HAVE LOST
PORT OUTBOARD ENGINE
AND PART OF WING.
REQUEST EMERGENCY LANDING.
WHAT'S THE POSITION?
10 MILES SOUTHWEST
OF METROPOLIS AIRPORT.
THE PRESIDENT'S
ON BOARD!
THAT'S 10 MILES
SOUTHWEST METROPOLIS AIRPORT.
HEADING 3-0-5.
HEIGHT, 6,000 FEET.
WHAT THE HELL HAPPENED?
WE GOT OUR ENGINE BACK?
WHAT THE HELL'S GOING ON?
FLY.
DON'T LOOK. JUST FLY.
WE GOT...SOMETHING.
I AIN'T SAYIN'
WHAT IT IS.
JUST TRUST ME.
Jor-el:
YOU ENJOYED IT?
I DON'T KNOW
WHAT TO SAY, FATHER.
I'M AFRAID I JUST GOT
CARRIED AWAY.
I ANTICIPATED THIS,
MY SON.
YOU COULDN'T HAVE.
YOU COULDN'T HAVE
IMAGINED...
HOW GOOD IT FELT?
YOU ARE REVEALED
TO THE WORLD.
VERY WELL.
SO BE IT.
BUT YOU STILL MUST KEEP
YOUR SECRET IDENTITY.
WHY?
THE REASONS ARE 2--
FIRST, YOU CANNOT
SERVE HUMANITY
28 HOURS A DAY.
24.
OR 24...
AS IT IS IN EARTH NOW.
YOUR HELP WILL BE
CALLED FOR ENDLESSLY,
EVEN FOR THOSE TASKS
WHICH HUMAN BEINGS CAN
SOLVE FOR THEMSELVES
BECAUSE THEY'RE HAPPY
TO ABUSE THEIR RESOURCES
IN SUCH A WAY.
AND SECONDLY?
SECOND,
YOUR ENEMIES WILL DISCOVER
THEIR ONLY WAY
TO HURT YOU--
BY HURTING THE PEOPLE
YOU CARE FOR.
THANK YOU, FATHER.
LASTLY...
DO NOT PUNISH YOURSELF
FOR YOUR FEELINGS
OF VANITY.
SIMPLY LEARN
TO CONTROL THEM.
THIS IS AN AFFLICTION
COMMON TO ALL,
EVEN ON KRYPTON.
OUR DESTRUCTION
COULD'VE BEEN AVOIDED,
BUT FOR THE VANITY
OF SOME WHO CONSIDER US
INDESTRUCTIBLE.
WERE IT NOT
FOR VANITY, WHY...
AT THIS VERY MOMENT...
I COULD EMBRACE YOU
IN MY ARMS.
MY SON.
REPORTS ARE COMING IN
OF A MIRACULOUS SAVING
OF AIR FORCE ONE...
A BURGLAR
WAS APPREHENDED...
...IN RESCUING
MISS LOIS LANE,
REPORTER
ON THEDAILY PLANET,
WITH ONE HAND,
AND A CRASHED HELICOPTER
WITH THE OTHER.
[BROADCASTS CONTINUE]
YEAH, THAT'LL BE
THE DAY, HUH?
THAT'LL BE THE DAY
WHEN A GUY CAN FLY, HUH?
OH, I DON'T KNOW.
YOU'D BE SURPRISED.
YEAH.
...SOME SORT
OF FANTASTIC HOAX.
YOUR GUESS IS AS GOOD
AS ANYBODY'S.
MIRACLE OR FRAUD?
MISS TESCHMACHER!
TURN IT OFF!
LEX!
WHAT'S THE STORY
ON THIS GUY?
IS HE
THE GENUINE ARTICLE?
IF HE IS, HE'S NOT
FROM THIS WORLD.
I'M THE ONLY HUMAN
WHO COULD PERPETRATE
SUCH A FANTASTIC HOAX.
UH!
OTIS!
MY ROBE!
RIGHT AWAY, MR. LUTHOR.
IT ALL FITS SOMEHOW,
HIS COMING HERE
TO METROPOLIS,
AND AT THIS PARTICULAR TIME.
THERE'S KIND OF
A CRUEL JUSTICE ABOUT IT.
TO COMMIT THE CRIME
OF THE CENTURY,
A MAN WOULD WANT TO FACE
THE CHALLENGE OF THE CENTURY.
MAYBE THIS GUY
THAT FLIES
IS JUST
PASSING THROUGH.
PASSING THROUGH?
NOT ON
YOUR LIFE, OTIS--
WHICH I WOULD
GLADLY SACRIFICE
FOR THE OPPORTUNITY
OF DESTROYING
EVERYTHING
THAT HE REPRESENTS.
AND OTIS,
BY THE WAY...
NEXT TIME,
PUT MY ROBE ON
AFTERI'M
OUT OF THE POOL.
NOW LOOK!
THE POST--"IT FLIES!"
THE NEWS--
"LOOK MA, NO WIRES."
THE TIMES--"BLUE BOMB
BUZZES METROPOLIS."
WE'RE SITTING ON
THE STORY OF THE CENTURY.
I WANT THE NAME
OF THIS FLYING WHATCHAMACALLIT
TO GO WITH THEDAILY PLANET
LIKE BACON AND EGGS,
FRANKS AND BEANS,
DEATH AND TAXES,
POLITICS AND CORRUPTION!
HE WOULDN'T LEND HIMSELF
TO CHEAP PROMOTION SCHEMES.
HOW WOULD YOU KNOW?
UM...UH...
JUST A FIRST IMPRESSION.
WHO'S TALKING CHEAP?
I'LL MAKE HIM A PARTNER
IF I HAVE TO--RIGHT?
RIGHT, CHIEF.
I WANT THE REAL STORY!
I WANT THE INSIDE DOPE
ON THIS GUY.
HAS HE GOT A FAMILY?
WHERE DOES HE LIVE?
A FRIEND?
TONY, WHO IS HE?
MIKE, WHAT'S HIS NAME?
HAS HE GOT BATTERIES
UNDER HIS CAPE?
WHY DID HE
SHOW UP LAST NIGHT?
WHERE DOES HE COME FROM?
DOES HE HAVE A GIRLFRIEND?
WHAT'S HIS FAVORITE
BALL TEAM, KENT?
NOW, LISTEN TO ME,
BOYS AND GIRLS.
WHICHEVER ONE OF YOU
GETS IT OUT OF HIM
WILL HAVE THE SINGLE
MOST IMPORTANT INTERVIEW
SINCE GOD TALKED TO MOSES.
WHAT ARE YOU
STANDING AROUND ABOUT FOR?
MOVE!
GET ON THAT STORY!
[TELEPHONE RINGS]
8:00, HE SAYS. 8:00.
SOME FRIEND.
THE STORY OF MY LIFE.
CINDERELLA BITES THE DUST.
GOOD EVENING,
MISS LANE.
UH...HI.
DID YOU HAVE PLANS
THIS EVENING?
OH...
THIS OLD THING? NO.
I'LL
COME BACK LATER.
DON'T MOVE!
UM...
UM...ER...
SURE, YOU CAN MOVE.
JUST DON'T FLY AWAY,
ALL RIGHT?
SORRY TO DROP IN
ON YOU LIKE THIS,
BUT THERE MUST BE
MANY QUESTIONS ABOUT ME
THAT PEOPLE
WANT ANSWERED.
OF COURSE, YES. UH...
YOU REALLY SHOULDN'T
SMOKE, MISS LANE.
DON'T TELL ME.
LUNG CANCER, RIGHT?
WELL, NOT YET.
THANK GOODNESS.
WOULD YOU LIKE
A GLASS OF WINE?
I NEVER DRINK
WHEN I FLY.
NICE PLACE.
OH, THANK YOU.
THANK YOU.
UM, SHOULD WE GET STARTED
WITH THE INTERVIEW?
OH.
THANK YOU.
WELL, UH,
LET'S START
WITH YOUR
VITAL STATISTICS.
ARE YOU MARRIED?
UH, NO.
NO, I'M NOT.
DO YOU HAVE
A GIRLFRIEND?
NO, BUT IF I DID,
MISS LANE,
YOU'D BE THE FIRST
TO KNOW ABOUT IT.
UM, HOW OLD ARE YOU?
OVER 21.
I GET IT.
DON'T WANT
ANYONE TO KNOW.
HOW BIG--
HOW TALL ARE YOU?
UH, ABOUT 6'4".
AND HOW MUCH
DO YOU WEIGH?
AROUND 225.
225?
HMM.
WELL, UM,
I ASSUME THEN THAT...
THE REST OF YOUR
BODILY FUNCTIONS ARE...
NORMAL?
I BEG YOUR PARDON?
WELL, PUTTING IT
DELICATELY...
DO YOU...
EAT?
YES. YES, I DO.
WHEN I'M HUNGRY.
YOU DO.
OF COURSE YOU DO!
WELL. WELL, THEN,
IS IT TRUE
THAT YOU CAN
SEE THROUGH ANYTHING?
YES, I CAN.
WELL, PRETTY MUCH.
AND YOU'RE TOTALLY
IMPERVIOUS TO PAIN?
WELL, SO FAR.
WHAT COLOR UNDERWEAR
AM I WEARING?
HMM.
OH, I'M SORRY.
I EMBARRASSED YOU, DIDN'T I?
OH, NO.
NOT AT ALL. THIS PLANTER
MUST BE MADE OF LEAD.
SO?
I, UH, SORT OF HAVE A PROBLEM
SEEING THROUGH LEAD.
OH, THAT'S
INTERESTING.
"PROBLEMS SEEING
THROUGH LEAD..."
UH, DO YOU HAVE
A FIRST NAME?
WHAT DO YOU MEAN,
LIKE RALPH OR SOMETHING?
PINK.
I'M SORRY, MISS LANE,
I DIDN'T MEAN
TO EMBARRASS YOU.
OH! YOU DIDN'T
EMBARRASS ME.
WHAT'S YOUR BACKGROUND?
WHERE DO YOU HAIL FROM?
WELL, IT'S KIND OF
HARD TO EXPLAIN, ACTUALLY.
YOU SEE, I'M FROM, UM...
WELL, PRETTY FAR AWAY.
ANOTHER GALAXY,
AS A MATTER OF FACT.
I COME FROM A PLANET
CALLED KRYPTON.
HUH?
KRYPTON.
OH, KRYPTON!
WITH A C-R-I?
NO, ACTUALLY, IT'S KRYPTON
WITH A K-R-Y-P-T-O-N.
K-R-Y...
DO YOU LIKE PINK?
I LIKE PINK VERY MUCH, LOIS.
WHY ARE YOU...
I'M SORRY?
WHY ARE YOU HERE?
THERE MUST BE A REASON.
I'M HERE TO FIGHT
FOR TRUTH, JUSTICE,
AND THE AMERICAN WAY.
YOU'LL BE FIGHTING
EVERY ELECTED OFFICIAL
IN THIS COUNTRY!
YOU DON'T REALLY MEAN THAT.
I DON'T
BELIEVE THIS.
LOIS?
I NEVER LIE.
UM...
UH, JUST HOW FAST
DO YOU FLY, BY THE WAY?
I DON'T KNOW, REALLY.
NO ONE ACTUALLY
BOTHERED TO TIME ME.
NO?
SAY, WHY DON'T
WE FIND OUT?
HOW DO YOU PROPOSE
WE DO THAT?
TAKE A RIDE
WITH ME?
YOU MEAN I CAN FLY?
I'D BE HANDLING
THE FLYING.
THIS IS
UTTERLY FANTASTIC.
WHERE ARE YOU GOING?
ARE YOU SERIOUS?
SURE. DON'T YOU
WANT TO GO?
YOU DON'T
NEED THESE.
I NEED A SWEATER.
IT MUST BE KIND OF COLD.
YOU'LL BE WARM ENOUGH.
READY?
CLARK...
SAID THAT YOU'RE JUST A FIGMENT
OF SOMEBODY'S IMAGINATION,
LIKE PETER PAN.
CLARK...WHO'S THAT,
YOUR BOYFRIEND?
HUH? OH, CLARK.
HE'S NOTHING.
PETER PAN, HUH?
UH-HUH.
PETER PAN FLEW
WITH CHILDREN, LOIS,
IN A FAIRY TALE.
AH!
UH!
OH!
AAH!
Lois:
CAN YOU READ MY MIND?
DO YOU KNOW WHAT IT IS
THAT YOU DO TO ME?
I DON'T KNOW WHO YOU ARE.
JUST A FRIEND
FROM ANOTHER STAR.
HERE I AM
LIKE A KID OUT OF SCHOOL,
HOLDING HANDS WITH A GOD.
I'M A FOOL.
WILL YOU LOOK AT ME?
QUIVERING.
LIKE A LITTLE GIRL, SHIVERING.
YOU CAN SEE
RIGHT THROUGH ME.
CAN YOU READ MY MIND?
CAN YOU PICTURE
THE THINGS I'M THINKING OF?
WONDERING WHY YOU ARE...
ALL THE WONDERFUL
THINGS YOU ARE.
YOU CAN FLY!
YOU BELONG IN THE SKY.
YOU AND I...
COULD BELONG
TO EACH OTHER.
IF YOU NEED A FRIEND...
I'M THE ONE TO FLY TO.
IF YOU NEED TO BE LOVED...
HERE I AM.
READ MY MIND.
OH, WE FORGOT
TO TIME OURSELVES.
UH-HUH.
WELL, MAYBE NEXT TIME.
OH!
YOU OK?
UH-HUH.
WELL, GOOD NIGHT.
OH, GOOD NIGHT!
WHAT A SUPER MAN.
SUPERMAN.
LOIS!
LOIS?
ANYBODY HOME?
[KNOCKING]
HELLO?
LOIS?
[KNOCKING]
HI. CAN I COME IN?
OH, YEAH.
LOIS,
FOR GOODNESS SAKE,
DIDN'T YOU
HEAR ME KNOCKING?
UH-HUH.
WE DID HAVE A DATE
TONIGHT, REMEMBER?
OH.
LOIS, YOU HAVEN'T
BEEN, UH...
HMM?
OH, NO.
I CERTAINLY HOPE NOT.
LET'S PUSH OFF, SHALL WE?
I'D BETTER GET A COAT.
IT MIGHT BE KIND OF
COLD OUT THERE.
I NEED A PURSE.
I HAVE TO
FIX MY HAIR.
[IN SUPERMAN'S VOICE]
LOIS...
THERE'S SOMETHING
I HAVE TO TELL YOU.
I'M REALLY--
UM...
[IN CLARK'S VOICE]
I MEAN, I WAS, AT FIRST,
REALLY NERVOUS ABOUT TONIGHT.
THEN I DECIDED TO SHOW YOU
THE TIME OF YOUR LIFE.
THAT'S CLARK, NICE.
I THOUGHT WE COULD
GO FOR A HAMBURGER.
NOW, THEN,
GIVEN THE EXACT
LOCATION
OF THE GALAXY
HE MENTIONS
AND THE PROXIMITY
TO OUR OWN
SOLAR SYSTEM...
IT'S AMAZING.
AMAZING!
TOO GOOD
TO BE TRUE.
IT'S TOO GOOD
HE'S 6'4",
HAS BLACK HAIR, BLUE EYES,
DOESN'T DRINK,
DOESN'T SMOKE,
AND TELLS THE TRUTH.
MISS TESCHMACHER,
PEOPLE CAN READ
WAR AND PEACE
AND THINK IT'S A SIMPLE
ADVENTURE STORY.
OTHERS READ
A GUM WRAPPER
AND UNLOCK SECRETS
OF THE UNIVERSE.
LEX, WHAT HAS
CHEWING GUM GOT TO DO
WITH SECRETS
OF THE UNIVERSE?
RIGHT. RIGHT,
MISS TESCHMACHER.
"N"..."N".
"M"! YOU WANT "M",
MR. LUTHOR?
SO, THERE YOU GO, "M".
"M" AS IN MORON, OTIS?
NO, IT'S "N"!
AS IN NEANDERTHAL,
NINCOMPOOP, NITWIT!
AND "L"
AS IN LADDER!
LADDER, MR. LUTHOR.
COMING RIGHT UP.
I'M SORRY,
MR. LUTHOR.
OOH!
IN THE INTERVIEW,
HE SAYS THAT
THE PLANET KRYPTON...
OOH!
EXPLODED IN 1948.
THAT RIDICULOUS
LITTLE FREAK
TOOK 3 YEARS
IN A ROCKET SHIP
TO GET TO EARTH.
ERGO...
ERGO...1948,
3 YEARS...
HE'S 6'4",
YOU KNOW THAT?
YOU KNOW WHY THE NUMBER 200
IS SO VITALLY DESCRIPTIVE
FOR BOTH YOU AND ME?
IT'S YOUR WEIGHT
AND MY IQ.
THINK, PEOPLE, THINK!
DEDUCTIVE REASONING,
THAT'S THE NAME OF THE GAME.
FRAGMENTS FROM
THE PLANET KRYPTON
EXPLODED AND WENT
INTO OUTER SPACE.
IT IS REASONABLE TO ASSUME
SOME OF THOSE PARTICLES
OF DEBRIS DRIFTED TO EARTH.
METEORITES!
JAWOHL.
VOILA!
VOILA.
A METEORITE FOUND
IN ADDIS ABABA?
I KNOW I'LL GET RAPPED
IN THE MOUTH FOR THIS,
BUT SO WHAT?
YOU MEAN, TO US
THEY'RE JUST METEORITES.
FAIR ENOUGH.
BUT THE LEVEL OF SPECIFIC
RADIOACTIVITY IS SO HIGH
TO ANYONE FROM
THE PLANET KRYPTON,
THIS SUBSTANCE
IS LETHAL!
WAIT A MINUTE,
MR. LUTHOR.
YOU MEAN FIRE AND BULLETS
CAN'T HURT THIS GUY,
BUT THIS STUFF HERE
WILL KILL HIM?
OH!
DOESN'T IT GIVE YOU
A SHUDDER OF ELECTRICITY
THROUGH YOU
TO BE IN THE SAME ROOM
WITH ME?
NOT LIKE THE SHUDDER
YOU'LL GET
WHEN YOU TRY LAYING
THAT ROCK ON HIM.
HE CAN SEE YOU COMING
FROM MILES
WITH THOSE
SUPER PEEPERS OF HIS.
OH, LORD, YOU GAVE THEM EYES,
BUT THEY CANNOT SEE,
NOR CAN SUPERMAN,
THROUGH LEAD.
HE CAN'T SEE
AND KRYPTONITE
WILL DESTROY HIM.
ANY QUESTIONS,
CLASS?
I WONDER WHAT THEY'RE
WEARING IN ADDIS ABABA.
LOOKS LIKE A BURNOOSE.
IT'S JUST A WRAPAROUND.
ARE WE GOING TO ADDIS ABABA,
MR. LUTHOR?
MOTHER BIRD
TO MISSILE CONVOY. OVER.
MISSILE CONVOY TO
MOTHER BIRD. GO AHEAD.
EVERYTHING LOOKS GOOD.
SEE YOU AT BASE.
OVER AND OUT.
ROGER.
[BEEPING]
CAPTAIN, OVER HERE.
LOOKS PRETTY BAD.
DO YOU THINK
SHE'S DEAD?
BETTER CHECK
HER PULSE.
GET AN AMBULANCE
DOWN HERE.
I DON'T WANT
TO HOLD THIS CONVOY UP.
SHE'S HAVING TROUBLE
BREATHING, SIR.
WHAT DO YOU THINK?
I SUGGEST
VIGOROUS CHEST MASSAGE.
THAT DOESN'T WORK,
MOUTH-TO-MOUTH.
YES, SIR!
I WON'T HAVE MY MEN
DOING ANYTHING
I WOULDN'T BE PREPARED
TO DO MYSELF.
GET AN AMBULANCE.
ALL RIGHT, MEN.
GATHER AROUND.
ABOUT FACE!
[SIREN]
HI.
SOMEBODY HURT?
HA HA!
OH! I DID IT!
I DID IT,
MR. LUTHOR.
I DID IT JUST LIKE
YOU TOLD ME.
ALL RIGHT, OTIS.
ALL RIGHT.
IT ISN'T THAT I DON'T
TRUST YOU, BUT...
I DON'T
TRUST YOU, OTIS.
WHAT DID YOU DO?
WELL, I SET THE FIRST
DIRECTIONAL VECTOR
TO, UH, 38,
THE SECOND ONE TO 67,
AND THE THIRD ONE TO 117.
WHAT ABOUT
THE FOURTH ONE?
WHAT FOURTH ONE?
WAIT A MINUTE.
THE THIRD ONE
TO 117?
YES. SEE?
I WROTE IT DOWN.
OTIS. OTIS!
THE THIRD ONE
WAS SUPPOSED TO BE 11
AND THE FOURTH ONE 7!
WELL, GEE,
MR. LUTHOR.
I GUESS MY ARM
WASN'T LONG ENOUGH, SEE?
WOULD YOU LIKE
TO SEE A LONG ARM?
OTIS, WOULD YOU
LIKE TO SEE
A VERY, VERY
LONG ARM?
OH, NO, MR. LUTHOR!
OTIS!
[HORN HONKS]
GET IT RIGHT,
WILL YOU?
YES, MR. LUTHOR.
[HONK HONK]
DIDN'T YOU SAY THIS ROAD
WAS BLOCKED OFF?
JABLONSKI,
DIDN'T YOU TELL--
I ASKEDYOU!
ALL RIGHT,
FOLLOW ME.
FOLLOW ME, MEN.
BACK THAT THING
OFF THE ROAD.
OFF THE ROAD!
GET BACK
INTO THAT THING
AND GET IT
OFF THE ROAD.
YOU'RE GOING TO
HAVE TO--
HECK OF A DAY,
ISN'T IT?
WE WERE LOOKING
FOR ROUTE 12.
THAT'S BACK THERE,
ISN'T IT?
IT'S UP THERE.
SERGEANT, UH...
I'M A LIEUTENANT,
A NAVAL OFFICER.
SHUT UP!
THIS MAN
IS A DIABETIC.
MY NEWSPAPER,
THEDAILY PLANET,
IS VERY INTERESTED
IN THAT DAM,
BUT WHAT
I DON'T UNDERSTAND
IS WHY YOU'D
SELL OUT
TO A PERSON
YOU'VE NEVER MET--
YEAH!
AT THE STUPID HIGH PRICE
HE OFFERED
FOR THIS WORTHLESS
PIECE OF DESERT,
I HOPE IT'S CUSTER.
PERFECT. THAT'S
JUST WHAT I NEED.
THANKS.
REPORTING LIVE
FROM THE LAUNCH SITE,
GROUND ZERO.
WELL, TODAY MARKS
A HISTORIC OCCASION.
2 XK 101 ROCKETS WILL
BE LAUNCHED SIMULTANEOUSLY,
ONE BY THE ARMY
AND ONE BY THE NAVY.
HI, EVERYBODY.
HAS ANYBODY SEEN LOIS?
NO, BUT THE CHIEF
WANTS TO SEE YOU.
YOU'RE BLOCKING
THE SET, CLARK.
OOPS, SORRY, GIL.
HOW'S JUDY TODAY? OK?
GOOD.
EXCUSE ME.
MR. WHITE?
HAVE YOU SEEN
LOIS ANYWHERE TODAY?
SHE'S OUT WEST LOOKING INTO
A LAND FRAUD DEAL.
SENT YOUNG OLSEN WITH HER
ON HIS FIRST ASSIGNMENT.
SOME UNIDENTIFIED CLOWN
IS BUYING
ACRES OF WORTHLESS DESERT
AT INCREDIBLE PRICES.
THAT DOESN'T
MAKE SENSE.
THE WORLD
DOESN'T MAKE SENSE.
LOOK AT THIS DISPATCH
FROM ADDIS ABABA.
PEOPLE BREAK INTO A MUSEUM,
KILL 2 PEOPLE,
AND TAKE A WORTHLESS
PIECE OF METEORITE.
HOW DO YOU
FIGURE THAT?
I'VE NEVER BEEN ABLE
TO UNDERSTAND
VIOLENCE IN ANY FORM.
THAT'S ONE OF THE REASONS
I WANTED TO TALK TO YOU.
I'VE BEEN IN THIS NEWS GAME
40 YEARS, MAN AND BOY.
I GOT WHERE I AM WITH GUTS,
COMPASSION, ELBOW GREASE,
AND SOMETHING YOU'RE
SADLY LACKING IN, SON.
HUMILITY?
NO, NOT HUMILITY.
YOU'VE GOT BAGS OF HUMILITY.
AGGRESSION, CONFIDENCE,
THAT'S THE TICKET.
TAKE CHARGE!
LET PEOPLE KNOW WHO YOU ARE!
[HIGH-PITCHED SOUND]
[WOOF! WOOF!]
THIS IS LEX LUTHOR.
YOU'RE THE ONLY THING
WITH LESS THAN 4 LEGS
THAT CAN HEAR
THIS FREQUENCY, SUPERMAN.
IN APPROXIMATELY
5 MINUTES,
A POISON GAS PELLET CONTAINING
PROPANE LITHIUM COMPOUND
WILL BE RELEASED THROUGH
AIR DUCTS IN THE CITY,
EFFECTIVELY ANNIHILATING
HALF OF METROPOLIS' POPULATION.
I WAS A REPORTER BEFORE
MY FRIENDS WERE COPY BOYS.
HAVE LOIS INTRODUCE YOU
TO SUPERMAN.
FIND OUT WHO HE IS,
WHAT'S HE LIKE.
WHERE'D HE GET
THAT BLUE SUIT?
DID HE HAVE IT MADE?
IS IT SILK?
IS IT PLASTIC?
Luthor: I KNOW IT ALL SEEMS
A BIT MUCH,
BUT HOW ELSE
WAS I GOING TO MEET YOU?
I KNEW YOU'D NEVER ACCEPT
AN INVITATION TO TEA.
BUT A DISASTER
WITH PEOPLE IN DANGER,
I JUST KNEW
YOU COULDN'T RESIST
THE CHANCE
TO SORT OF PITCH IN.
KNOW WHAT I MEAN?
THAT'S SUPERMAN!
OH, LOOK!
IT'S SUPERMAN!
OH, WOW!
LOOK AT HIM!
Luthor:
THERE'S A STRONG STREAK
OF GOOD IN YOU, SUPERMAN,
BUT THEN, NOBODY'S PERFECT.
ALMOST NOBODY.
WHAT THE--
SUPERMAN!
GEE!
STAND BACK, PLEASE.
NOTHING TO GET WORRIED ABOUT.
DON'T SIT THERE,
YOU NUMSKULL!
LOOK AT THAT OVERGROWN
BOY SCOUT.
TELL ME WHAT YOU SEE.
CUTENESS,
DIMPLES.
YOU LIKE CUTENESS, HUH?
DIMPLES?
I'LL GIVE YOU DIMPLES.
THE PRESSURE'S
STILL ON YOU, SUPERMAN.
YOU WHAT THEY SAY--
IF YOU CAN'T STAND THE HEAT,
GET OUT OF THE TUNNEL.
THIS IS
YOUR LAST CHANCE, SUPERMAN.
WHY DON'T YOU DO YOURSELF
A FAVOR AND FREEZE?
GOD.
GOOD.
I THINK
HE'S COMING.
HE'S DEFINITELY
COMING, MR. LUTHOR.
IT'S OPEN.
COME IN.
MY ATTORNEY
WILL CONTACT YOU
ABOUT THE DAMAGE
TO THE DOOR.
OTIS, TAKE
THE GENTLEMAN'S CAPE.
I DON'T THINK HE WANTS
ME TO, MR. LUTHOR.
WHERE'S THE GAS PELLET?
SOMEWHERE.
IN THE BACK
OF MY MIND, ACTUALLY.
LITTLE IDEA
I WAS TOYING WITH.
IS THAT HOW A WARPED BRAIN
LIKE YOURS GETS ITS KICKS?
BY PLANNING THE DEATH
OF INNOCENT PEOPLE?
NO, BYCAUSINGTHE DEATH
OF INNOCENT PEOPLE.
FIRE.
NAVY BIRD...
WE HAVE A GOOD LAUNCH,
NAVY MISSILE.
XK 101...XK 101...
ANGLE OF ATTACK
IS PERFECT.
CLIMBING FAST.
HYDRAULICS, PURE FUNCTION.
AS YOU MAY
OR MAY NOT KNOW,
I AM VERY HEAVY
INTO REAL ESTATE.
IN ORDER TO MAKE MONEY
IN THAT GAME,
YOU HAVE TO BUY
FOR A LITTLE
AND SELL FOR A LOT.
SO, THE PROBLEM--
HOW TO MAKE THE LAND
MORE VALUABLE
BETWEEN THE TIME
YOU BUY IT
AND THE TIME YOU SELL IT.
THIS IS CALIFORNIA,
THE RICHEST STATE
IN THE UNION.
I DON'T NEED A GEOGRAPHY
LESSON, LUTHOR.
YOU'VE BEEN THERE.
YOU GET AROUND.
WHERE WAS I?
CALIFORNIA.
THE SAN ANDREAS FAULT.
MAYBE YOU'VE
HEARD OF IT?
THE JOINING TOGETHER
OF 2 LAND MASSES.
THE FAULT LINE
IS SHIFTING,
WHICH IS WHY
YOU GET EARTHQUAKES.
WONDERFUL!
COULDN'T HAVE SAID IT
BETTER MYSELF.
EVERYTHING WEST
OF THIS LINE
IS THE RICHEST REAL ESTATE
IN THE WORLD--
SAN DIEGO, LOS ANGELES,
SAN FRANCISCO.
EVERYTHING
ON THIS SIDE
IS JUST
HUNDREDS OF MILES
OF WORTHLESS
DESERT LAND
WHICH HAPPENS
TO BE OWNED BY...
LEX LUTHOR,
INCORPORATED.
NOW, CALL ME FOOLISH,
CALL ME IRRESPONSIBLE...
IT OCCURS TO ME
THAT A 500-MEGATON BOMB
PLANTED AT JUST
THE PROPER POINT,
WOULD, UH...
WOULD DESTROY
MOST OF CALIFORNIA.
MILLIONS OF INNOCENT
PEOPLE WOULD BE KILLED.
THE WEST COAST
AS WE KNOW IT WOULD--
FALL INTO THE SEA.
BYE-BYE, CALIFORNIA.
HELLO, NEW WEST COAST.
MY WEST COAST.
COSTA DEL LEX,
LUTHORVILLE,
MARINA DEL LEX,
OTISBURG.
OTISBURG?
MISS TESCHMACHER,
SHE'S GOT
HER OWN PLACE.
OTISBURG?
IT'S A LITTLE,
BITTY PLACE.
OTISBURG?
I'LL JUST
WIPE IT OFF.
YOU'RE A DREAMER,
LEX LUTHOR--
A SICK, TWISTED DREAMER.
YOUR PLAN COULDN'T WORK.
THERE WERE
SOME PROBLEMS--
ADJUSTING THE TRAJECTORY
OF THE MISSILE,
FINDING THE OPTIMUM
STRESS POINT
FOR THE FAULT LINE
ITSELF--
WHICH, BY THE WAY,
IS TARGET ZERO,
RIGHT HERE.
OOH!
[HUMS]
[ALARM SOUNDS]
ARMY BIRD...
WHAT?
ARMY BIRDS
HAVE VARIED THEIR COURSE.
WHAT'S HAPPENING,
LIEUTENANT?
TRAJECTORY
MALFUNCTION, SIR.
WE HAVE INITIAL FAILURE.
THEN ABORT!
DESTRUCTION AND ABORT.
ALL COUNTERCONTROL UNITS,
REMOTE PRESSURE TO MAXIMUM.
ABORT MISSION.
FUNCTION NEGATIVE,
SIR!
CAN'T YOU KNOCK
THEM DOWN?
ABSOLUTELY
IMPOSSIBLE, SIR.
THEY HAVE THE NEW
P-20 AVOIDANCE SYSTEMS.
GET ME
THE PENTAGON.
...POSSIBLE RE-ENTRY
OF ROCKETS.
WHAT DO YOU THINK,
SUPE, BABY?
INTERESTING?
YOUR THEORY'S
QUITE IMPRESSIVE, LUTHOR.
OTIS, WOULD YOU GO
TO THE VIEWING ROOM?
BUT AS FOR THE REST,
IT'S NOTHING
BUT A SICK FANTASY.
FANTASY?
NO. NO.
IT'S HISTORY.
IT'S HAPPENING,
SUPERMAN.
MISS TESCHMACHER!
YES, LEX?
WHERE'S
THE ROCKET NOW?
IT'S GOING LIKE A BAT
OVER THE GRAND CANYON.
SO'S THE OTHER ONE.
THE OTHER ONE?
THERE'S 2 OF THEM?
[SNAP]
YES, SUPERMAN.
DOUBLE JEOPARDY.
EVEN YOU WITH
YOUR GREAT SPEED
COULDN'T STOP
BOTH OF THEM.
I COULD STOP THEM
WITH MY DETONATOR.
ALL RIGHT, LUTHOR.
WHERE IS IT?
WHERE'S THE DETONATOR?
YOU DISEASED MANIAC!
DID YOU REALLY THINK
YOU COULD HIDE IT FROM ME
BY ENCASING IT IN LEAD?
WHOA!
I'LL MOLD THIS BOX
INTO YOUR PRISON BARS.
DON'T TOUCH THAT!
I TOLD YOU.
IT'S KRYPTONITE,
SUPERMAN.
A SOUVENIR
FROM THE HOMETOWN.
I'VE SPARED NO EXPENSE
TO MAKE YOU FEEL
RIGHT AT HOME.
YOU WERE GREAT
IN YOUR DAY, SUPERMAN.
BUT IT JUST
STANDS TO REASON,
WHEN IT CAME TIME
TO CASH IN YOUR CHIPS,
THIS OLD DISEASED MANIAC
WOULD BE YOUR BANKER.
MIND OVER MUSCLE.
YOU DON'T EVEN CARE
WHERE THE OTHER MISSILE'S
HEADED, DO YOU?
CERTAINLY I DO.
I KNOW EXACTLY
WHERE IT'S HEADED.
HACKENSACK, NEW JERSEY.
OHH!
HEH HEH HEH.
I HAVE TO LEAVE.
NO HARD FEELINGS.
WE ALL HAVE
OUR FAULTS.
MINE'S IN CALIFORNIA.
LEX, MY MOTHER
LIVES IN HACKENSACK.
MISS TESCHMACHER!
Radio:
NAVY BIRD LEVELING OFF.
ARMY BIRD, WE ARE HOLDING
FOR OUR RADAR CONTACT.
...LOW-LEVEL FLIGHT,
EASTERLY DIRECTION.
RADAR CHANGE ANTICIPATED.
OTIS.
UHH! UHH!
MISS TESCHMACHER...
PLEASE, YOU CAN'T...
YOU CAN'T
JUST STAND THERE.
SHH!
YOU CAN'T
JUST STAND THERE
AND LET MILLIONS
OF INNOCENT PEOPLE DIE.
MAYBE.
PLEASE.
PLEASE HELP ME SAVE THEM!
IF I HELP YOU,
DO YOU PROMISE
TO SAVE MY MOTHER FIRST?
BUT LOIS AND JIMMY...
MY MOTHER COMES FIRST!
IF YOU PROMISE ME,
I'D BELIEVE YOU
BECAUSE YOU ALWAYS
TELL THE TRUTH.
I--I PROMISE.
I PROMISE.
UHH!
WHY--WHY DID YOU
KISS ME FIRST?
IT--I DIDN'T THINK
YOU'D LET ME LATER.
THANK YOU,
MISS TESCHMACHER.
WHY IS IT I CAN'T GET IT ON
WITH THE GOOD GUYS?
STAND ASIDE NOW.
I WOULDN'T
STAY HERE, EITHER.
ARMY BIRD HEADING
DUE EAST.
NAVY BIRD HEADING
DUE WEST.
LOSING RADAR CONTACT.
NEXT RADAR CONTACT,
3 SECONDS.
...BOTH BIRDS.
ARMY BIRD STILL
HEADED EAST, SIR.
NAVY BIRD HEADING 2.7.
ARMY BIRD
LAUNCHING INTO SPACE.
GAINING ALTITUDE.
MISS TESCHMACHER.
RADAR CONTACT STRONG.
MISS TESCHMACHER!
NAVY BIRD,
SAN ANDREAS AREA.
15 SECONDS TO IMPACT.
HEADING DOWN.
15 SECONDS,
AND COUNTING.
Radio:
?? ...GIVE A LITTLE BIT ??
?? GIVE A LITTLE BIT
OF MY LIFE FOR YOU ??
[HONK HONK]
IMPACT...SAN ANDREAS.
[GLASS BREAKS]
OH!
HUH!
Radio: A MILITARY MISSILE
HAS EXPLODED
IN SOUTHERN CALIFORNIA.
THE FORCE OF THE EXPLOSION
HAS ACTIVATED
THE SAN ANDREAS FAULT.
CALIFORNIA IS SUFFERING
A MAJOR EARTHQUAKE.
[RUMBLING]
[TIRES SQUEAL]
WHAT'S GOING ON?
SOMETHING WRONG?
[HONK]
AAH! AAH!
[SCREAMING]
[TRAIN WHISTLE BLOWS]
HEY, WHAT'S GOING ON?
IT'S A QUAKE. LOOK!
[TIRES SQUEAL]
WE'RE GOING
TO CRASH!
HOLD ON!
AAH!
GET TO THE BACK
OF THE BUS!
AAH!
UHH! UHH!
OH! OH!
OK, KIDS.
IT'S ALL RIGHT NOW!
HEY!
IT'S SUPERMAN!
HOLY MACKEREL!
WE'RE GOING
OFF THE TRACKS!
HANG ON!
CAN'T HOLD HER!
[RUMBLING]
[ALARM SOUNDS]
P.A.: ALL PERSONNEL
EVACUATE THE DAM.
ALL PERSONNEL
AAH!
Man: WATCH THAT CABLE!
UH! AH!
SOMEONE TRY
AND PULL THE MAIN!
IT'S IMPOSSIBLE!
IT'S RED HOT!
AAH!
GENTLEMEN,
IS THAT MAN ALL RIGHT?
YEAH.
AAH!
HANG ON, JIM.
THE DAM BURST!
COME ON!
HURRY!
YOU'LL BE SAFE
HERE, SON.
THAT'S OK! MISS LANE
WILL BE DRIVING BY SOON.
COME ON, GEORGE,
COME ON!
Radio: THERE HAS BEEN
MAJOR QUAKE DAMAGE
TO SOUTHERN CALIFORNIA.
THE SAN ANDREAS FAULT
HAS MIRACULOUSLY SEALED ITSELF,
YET SOUTHERN CALIFORNIA IS
SUFFERING MAJOR AFTER SHOCKS
OF A MAJOR EARTHQUAKE.
THE POPULATION
IS STILL WARNED...
PLEASE, COME ON, TURN OVER.
COME ON!
AAH!
OH!
NO!
HELP ME. HELP ME.
NO! PLEASE, NO!
AAH!
WAIT!
RUN!
UH...
AH...
OH! OH!
[COUGHING]
AAH!
NO. NO.
NO.
AAAAAHH!
Jor-el: IT IS
FORBIDDEN FOR YOU
TO INTERFERE
IN HUMAN HISTORY.
Jonathan: SON, YOU ARE
HERE FOR A REASON.
IT IS FORBIDDEN
FOR YOU
TO INTERFERE
IN HUMAN HISTORY.
ALL THOSE THINGS I CAN DO,
ALL THOSE POWERS,
AND I COULDN'T EVEN
SAVE HIM.
[THUNDER]
Jor-el: [ECHOES]
IT IS FORBIDDEN.
[ENGINE WON'T START]
HI.
DON'T BOTHER.
I THINK IT'S DEAD.
SURE, IT'S DEAD.
MEN OF STEEL
ARE NEVER AROUND
WHEN YOU WANT THEM.
WHILE YOU WERE OFF
FLYING AROUND,
I WAS ALMOST
IN AN EARTHQUAKE,
THIS GAS STATION BLEW UP
BESIDE MY CAR,
I'M ALMOST KILLED,
AND TO TOP THINGS OFF,
THIS STUPID CAR
RUNS OUT OF GAS!
I'M SORRY
ABOUT THAT, LOIS,
BUT I'VE BEEN KIND OF
BUSY FOR A WHILE.
I'M SORRY.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT.
HEY! THANKS A LOT,
SUPERMAN.
YOU LEAVE ME
IN THE MIDDLE OF NOWHERE
DURING AN EARTHQUAKE--
NO FOOD, SNAKES EVERYWHERE.
I DIDN'T KNOW
IF YOU WOULD COME BACK.
THERE'S SOMETHING
I HAVE TO DO.
I'LL SEE YOU LATER.
HE CAN'T STAY STILL
FOR A SECOND.
GOLLY, MISS LANE,
IT'S TOO BAD
MR. KENT WASN'T HERE
TO SEE ALL THIS.
YEAH, HE'S NEVER
AROUND WHEN SU...
CLARK...
WAIT A MINUTE.
WHAT?
LOIS LANE, THAT IS
THE SILLIEST IDEA.
MISS LANE, I THINK
HE REALLY CARES ABOUT YOU.
CLARK?
OF COURSE HE DOES.
NO, NOT CLARK.
OH, WELL...
SUPERMAN CARES
ABOUT EVERYBODY, JIMMY.
BUT, UH, WHO KNOWS?
SOMEDAY, YOU KNOW,
IF HE'S LUCKY...
[ALARM SOUNDS]
[DOGS BARKING]
YOU'RE MESSING UP
MY SUIT,
YOU LUMMOX, YOU!
COME ON, STOP IT.
OTIS,
IT'S YOUR FAULT.
WATCH THE GROUND!
GOOD EVENING, WARDEN.
THESE MEN
SHOULD BE SAFE HERE
UNTIL THEY CAN GET
A FAIR TRIAL.
WHO IS IT, SUPERMAN?
LEX LUTHOR,
THE GREATEST CRIMINAL MIND
OF OUR TIME!
I HEREBY SERVE NOTICE...
HE'S SERVING
NOTICE TO YOU--
WILL YOU SHUT UP!
TAKE THEM AWAY, BOYS.
NINCOMPOOP!
THIS COUNTRY IS
SAFE AGAIN, SUPERMAN,
THANKS TO YOU.
NO, SIR. DON'T
THANK ME, WARDEN.
WE'RE ALL PART
OF THE SAME TEAM.
GOOD NIGHT.
Movie & Captions Presented By :
KoushiK DaS
[ koushik-das@wassup.co.in ]
[ koushik@moviefan.com ]
" Hope You've Liked & Enjoyed The Movie !!! "
Subtitle downloaded with
Sublight (www.sublight.me)