Subtitle downloaded with
Sublight (www.sublight.me)
-Somebody will see!
-No way.
-Does Maryann kiss as good as I do?.
-How would I know?.
-You said we were special.
-I meant everything.
Somebody's there!
We weren't doing anything.
We were just messing a...
Please, don't!
Hi, girl. Excuse me! Hi, boy.
You speak English?.
How far is it to Camp Crystal Lake?.
That far?.
Okey-dokey. See you later.
It's 7:01 on Friday the 13th of June.
This is Big Dave and it's time for you
Lazybones to get out of bed.
It's bLack-cat day in Crystal Lake.
I must have seen that Kojak 82 times.
Excuse me. How far
is Camp Crystal Lake from here?.
What is it, Enos?. About 20 miles?.
-About that.
-Camp Blood?.
-They' re opening that place again?.
-Lots of luck.
-Can I get a bus or something?.
-Not likely.
You going out to the crossroads, Enos?.
What about a lift?. That would be halfway.
No sweat, Trudy. Okay, kid, let's move it.
-Name's Annie.
-All right, Annie, let's go.
All the girls up there
gonna look as good as you?.
-You're going to Camp Blood, ain't you?.
-Goddamn it, Ralph, get out of here!
Leave people alone!
-You'll never come back!
-Oh, shut up, Ralph!
It's got a death curse!
He's a real prophet of doom, ain't he?.
Climb up, miss.
He's causing problems enough
for your boss with all that talk.
Goddamn nuisance.
-He tell you anything?.
-Who?.
Your boss. Steve Christy.
I'll be cooking for 50 kids and 10 staff.
-Campers will mostly be inner-city children.
-No, I mean about what happened.
No.
Come on. There's something
you're not telling me.
-Quit. Quit now.
-Quit?. Why would I want to quit?.
- Camp Crystal Lake is jinxed!
- Terrific.
-Not you too. You sound
like your crazy friend back there.
-Well, maybe.
Did Christy tell you about
the two kids murdered in '58?.
Boy drowning in '57?. A bunch of fires?.
Nobody knows who did any of them.
In 1962, they were going to open up.
The water was bad.
Christy will end up like his folks:
crazy and broke.
He's been up there a year fixing up that
place. Must have dropped $25,000.
And for what?. Ask anybody.
-Quit!
-I can't.
Dumb kids. Know-it-alls.
Just like my nieces. Heads full of rocks.
-You're an American original.
-I'm an American original.
-Dumb kid.
-At least I'm not afraid of ghosts.
-Take care of yourself.
-No sweat. Thanks for the lift.
Hey, Marcie. You really think
there'll be other gorgeous women...
..at Camp Crystal Lake besides yourself?.
-ls sex all you ever think about, Ned?.
-Hey, no. No. Absolutely not.
Sometimes I just think about
kissing women.
-You wanna give me a hand over here?.
-Sure.
Alice! I wanna get this tree stump out.
Get on this side, you pull
on that side. Alice!
Coming.
-That's great. I'm Steve Christy.
-Jack.
-Marcie
-Ned Rubinstein.
Welcome to Camp Crystal Lake.
This is Alice.
- Hi. Steve, Cabin B is all ready.
- Where's Bill?. Cleaning out the boathouse?.
- Haven't seen him in half an hour.
- I wanted him to start painting. Brenda?.
-Setting up the archery range.
-I'd rather she paint. Come on. Let's go.
I thought we had two weeks.
Come on. I'll show you
where you can get changed.
-Here, let me give you a hand with that.
-Thank you.
You got it?.
You draw very well.
Thanks. I wish I had more time to do it.
Oh, dummy.
-When did you do this?.
-Last night.
-Do I really look like that?.
-You did last night.
You're very talented.
You're very pretty.
This really isn't your cup of tea, is it?.
Any particular reason?.
It's just a problem I have.
It's nothing personal.
You wanna leave?.
I don't know. I may have to go back to California
to straighten something out.
Come on. Give me another chance.
Stay a week.
Help get the place ready.
By Friday, if you're not happy,
I'll put you on the bus myself.
All right. Friday. I'll give it a week.
Thanks, Alice.
Bill?. Steve wants to know
if we need more paint.
-Paint's all right. Need more thinner.
-Okay.
-Alice. Did the others show up?.
-Yeah, eVerybody except that girl Annie.
-Think you're gonna last all summer?.
-I don't know if I'm gonna last all week.
-I'll tell Steve about the thinner.
-Fine.
-You want it listed separately?.
-Right.
Brenda, I want you to
finish the archery range.
If Annie gets here, get her started
in the kitchen. Do your best.
I'll be back sometime after lunch.
It's supposed to rain like hell,
so get as much done as possible.
He neglected to mention that downtown
they call this place "Camp Blood. "
Next there'll be snakes in the
outhouse and crocodiles in the lake.
No, the crocodiles are in the cabins.
- Are you crazy?.
- Wanna see my trick shot?. It's even better.
I don't believe you!
You know, you're beautiful
when you're angry, sweetheart.
You come to help me or scare
me to death?. You do that again...
-...I'll tack you up on the wall to dry.
-I love that sexy talk!
Hi. I'm going to Camp Crystal Lake.
Guess I always wanted to
work with children.
I hate when people call them "kids. "
Sounds like little goats.
But when you've had a dream
as long as I have, you'll do anything.
Hey, wasn't that the road for
Camp Crystal Lake back there?
I think we better stop.
Please?.
Stop, please! Please! Stop!
Please, stop!
No. No.
No.
All right, move it out. A little to the left.
Little to the left.
Move it out. Move it out. Okay,
little to the left. Now-- No, no.
If you were a flavor of ice cream,
what would it be?.
-Rocky Road.
-Hey!
What's that Vitamin C
stuff do for you, anyway?.
Vitamin C is supposed to neutralize
the nitrates or something.
What's the matter?.
Do you see something?.
No. Nothing.
Ned! Get out of here!
Hey, you guys.
Ready to go back to work?.
-Come on, Alice.
-Help! Help!
-Something's wrong with Ned.
-Get a life preserver!
-Can he swim?.
-I don't know.
-He's right around here somewhere.
-I got it.
Go ahead, dive for him.
-There he is!
-Come on. Help me.
-Watch his head!
-Got him?.
Can you giVe mouth-to-mouth?.
-Oh, God.
-Come on, Ned.
-Oh, Neddy!
-Oh, Jesus Christ!
Look, I'm sorry. I'm sorry, all right?.
Bill!
Bill, come here, quick! Hurry!
-What is it?.
-There's a snake over there.
Where?.
-What do I do?.
-Kill it.
- It might bite.
-Haven't you ever been in the woods?.
We're not in the woods.
-Bill, what are you doing?.
-There's a snake.
-Why are we in here?.
-Feet don't fail me now!
-I can't sleep with a snake in here.
-Nobody said anything about snakes.
-Kill it!
-I can't get it until it comes out.
-Well, call him!
-How do you call a snake?.
I'll flush him!
-I got it.
-Where?.
Is it dead?.
Either that or it's got a very short clone.
-Well, at least we know what's for dinner.
-Marcie!
I'm making salad. Want me
to make some for everybody?.
-That would be great. There's hamburger
-None for me.
There are apples.
Know how to make apple pie?.
-Sure. No sweat.
-What is going on?.
Oh, shit.
-Who are you people?.
-Camp counselors. Ned is fooling around.
-Right, just...
-Can it, Cochise.
SteVe Christy hire you people?.
He pay you for this?.
-Nice bike.
-You been smoking, boy?.
Smoking?. Don't smoke. Causes cancer.
You just get off a spaceship or something?.
Colombian gold. Grass. Hash. The weed.
-What's he talking about?.
-Don't get smart.
-Me?. I'm as dumb as they come.
-Not another word out of you, understand?.
-Nothing's going on here.
We're getting the place in shape.
-For what?.
-ls there anything we can do to help?.
-I'm looking for somebody.
-Who's that?.
-A guy named Ralph. The town crazy.
There's no crazy people around here.
I told you to sit on it, Tonto. I got word
Ralph was pedaling out this way...
-...spouting his gospel.
-We haven't seen anybody here.
-Just us.
-This guy Ralph. Is he dangerous?.
Every time that loony gets drunk,
he gets his calling.
I spend the morning in court,
he gets a week in jail.
Cycle Two, where are you?
Come in, Cycle Two.
This is Dorf. I' m out here
at Camp Crystal Lake. Over.
Haul it back in, Dorf.
Chief wants you back in town.
Roger that. 10-5. On my way. Out.
Never keep the chief waiting.
You kids keep your noses clean.
You'll be hearing from me if you don't.
We ain't gonna stand
for no weirdness out here.
I'm a messenger of God.
You're doomed if you stay here
This place is cursed. Cursed.
-It's got a death curse!
-Who are you?.
What do you want?.
-God sent me.
-Get out of here, man!
I got to warn you.
You're doomed if you stay.
Go. Go!
-I think we just met Ralph.
-God, what's next?.
You're doomed. You're all doomed.
-Who likes them rare?.
-Me.
How can you guys eat that?.
It looks like dead animals.
Dead animals?. That's the old counselors.
You cannibals!
If you would mix this stuff right,
you'd get all the protein you need.
-Too bad Annie never showed. She was supposed
to be a good cook.
-Don't expect me to play chef.
-Trouble?.
-Yeah. A bad bulb or no power.
Seems a little gloomy in here.
SteVe taught me how to use
the emergency generator.
-Town power lines are lousy.
-Don't you love that macho talk?.
Emergency generator.
-Want to give me a hand?.
-Yeah.
-Wait for me.
-Can you watch the burgers?.
-Think he's gonna be bent out of shape?.
-I don't know.
This looks almost like the one
at my uncle's cabin in Maine.
-Well, here goes.
-What an antique.
Well, what hath God wrought?.
Hello?.
Can I help you?.
Hello?. Hello?.
-Come on.
-Coming, I'm coming.
Wind's come up.
Shifted a good 180 degrees.
Makes me want to hold onto you.
-What about Ned?.
-I don't love Ned.
-He keeps acting like such a jerk.
-Neddy!
-Don't call him.
-Thought you wanted to give him
one of your motherly lectures.
Look, Neddy's gonna do whatever
Neddy wants to do, you know?.
It's gonna storm. Gonna tear down
that Valley like a son of a gun.
- I've been afraid of storms since I was little.
-No. Really?.
I've had this dream about five or six
times where I'm in a thunderstorm...
...and it's raining really hard.
It sounds like pebbles when it hits the ground.
I hear it and I try to block it out
with my hands, only it doesn't work.
It just keeps getting
louder and louder.
And then the rain turns to blood...
...and the blood washes away
in little rivers...
...and then the sound stops.
-It's just a dream.
-I know. I call it my "shower dream. "
Hey, hey. This is no dream.
Come on, we're gonna get soaked.
- Jack and Marcie are gonna get drenched!
- Not if they're where I think they are.
That's nice.
I know what we can do.
We'll play Monopoly.
-I hate Monopoly!
-Not the way I play it, you don't.
-Like what?.
-We're going to play strip Monopoly.
-I'll be the shoe.
-You have got to be kidding.
What if Steve walks in?.
We'll give him a handicap.
He can keep his boots on. It's easy.
Instead of rent, you pay clothes. Bill
can be banker. Unless he's chicken.
Heaven help you if you land
in my hotel!
Why don't you see if Marcie
left any of that grass?
-What happened to my 500's?.
-They're there. Where's my shoe?.
I'm not going to pass "Go"
without a glow.
We rolled for you. You're going last.
Community Chest cannot
give you your clothes back
Double sixes! I get to roll again!
-We're being hustled.
-I think you're right.
You are so fine.
Where are you going?.
I gotta pee.
You're lying on my bladder.
Hurry back, okay?.
It's getting cold in here.
-You'll save my place for me?.
-Yeah.
Five.
-Baltic Avenue. I'll buy it.
-No one ever lands on Baltic Avenue.
I think it's a pretty color.
Come on.
Eight.
-Baltic Avenue. You owe me one boot.
-Coming.
Alice draws first blood.
-Terrible way to talk about my feet.
-Thank you.
Who's next?.
You know I think I'm beginning
to like this game.
Wait until he lands
on my old Kentucky home.
-More beer?. More beer.
-Let's see. A railroad.
Forty Yards to the Outhouse,
by Willie Makit.
Come on, kids,
you can do better than that.
Jack?
When I looked into that mirror,
I knew I'd always be ugly.
I said,
"Lizzie, you'll always be plain. "
Hello?.
Ned?
Hey, come on, you guys.
It must be my imagination.
-Hello.
-Shit.
-Worst run of bad luck since Richard Nixon.
-You can call it quits.
Fat chance! You're two steps
from Pacific Avenue and Skin City.
What can I say?.
It's not much, but I call it home.
-I'll get it. I'll get it.
-Get the money.
-God!
-It's blowing like crazy out there
I think I left the windows
in my cabin open. Shoot!
We'll have to finish this game some other
Just when it was getting interesting.
-See you guys in the morning.
-See you.
-Good night.
Look at this mess! Here.
-Were you going to go ahead with it?.
-I hadn't made up my mind.
We'll have to finish
the game another night.
-ls there anything else you want?.
-No, thanks, Sandy. I'm fine.
You can't go out in that rain.
You want to drown?.
I've got to.
I've got six new counselors at camp.
They are babes in the woods,
in every sense.
They'll be okay if they know enough
to come out of the rain.
-Well, what do I owe you?.
-Just a night on the town, Steve.
-Come on now, you know what I mean.
-That's okay. Two and a quarter.
Thank you.
-Here's your change.
-No, you keep it.
Thank you.
-Drive careful.
-I will.
-Hi.
-Thought that'd go through anything.
-Not dragging a trailer.Can you give me a lift?
-I'll have a counselor bring me back.
-Why not?.
Help me!
Hello.
-Hello.
-Over here. Please somebody help me.
Hello.
Come quickly, please.
Come quickly. Help.
Where are you?
Hello?
Hello?.
All right.
Come on out! You're not funny anymore!
It's not funny at all.
Bill.
-Hi. The generator is okay.
-I thought I heard a scream.
-How can you hear in that wind?.
-lt sounded like Brenda.
- I'd better look.
- Somebody turned on the lights
at the archery range.
I can't see anything.
- They're off now.
- I'm gonna check it out.
-Bill. Can I come?.
-Come on.
Brenda!Brenda!
Where is she?.
She must be with Jack and Marcie.
Alice?.
Come here.
What is going on?.
Come on!
Jack! Jack, open the door.
-Where are they?.
-I don't know. Come on.
Brenda?.
Marcie?.
Jack?. Neddy?.
- Bill, I think we should call someone.
- If this is a joke, I'll brain them!
I'm serious.
I really think we should call someone.
- The sucker's locked.Where's the key?
- I don't know.
Wait a minute.
Watch out.
Be careful.
Let me get the light.
- What's wrong?.
- It's dead. Try the pay phone.
- Do you have a dime or a quarter?.
- No. Check the desk.
Hello?
This damn thing's dead too!
- What's the matter with it?.
- It's wet.I don't know.
Why don't we just hike out of here?.
Get out. Right now!
It's 10 miles to the nearest crossroads.
Steve will be back soon.
We can use his jeep if we need
to get help. Don't worry.
-There's some stupid explanation for this.
-Like what?.
We'll be laughing about this tomorrow,
I promise.
Let's get out of the rain.
It's not bad enough to have Friday the
13th, we've gotta have a full moon too.
We keep statistics. We have more
accidents, more rapes, more robberies..
...more homicides, more of everything
when there's a full moon.
- It upsets people. Makes them nuts
- You're making science out of coincidence.
I hear Ralph was out your way today.
His wife was a nervous wreck
until we got him home.
That's all I need,
Crazy Ralph running around.
Well, the rain's stopping.
It was a pisser while it lasted.
Sgt. Tierney, come in.
Sgt. Tierney, Car Niner.
This is Tierney.
Rescue squad with Jaws of Life.
Near mile-marker 17. Possible fatals
Three, maybe more, trapped.
Head on.
Roger. Acknowledge receipt.
Estimate arrival, 15 minutes.
-I have to let you off here.
-Sure.
- Thanks.
- Good luck.
Who is that?.
What are you doing
out in this mess?.
- What do you think happened?.
- I don't know.
The generator's probably out of gas
I'll go check it.
Do you want me to come with you?.
Why don't you stay here
and try and sleep.
I'll be right back.
Full of gas.
Generator....
What am I gonna do?.
Who are you?.
I'm Mrs. Voorhees.
An old friend of the Christys.
I can't help you
if you don't calm down.
But she's dead and he's dead.
Oh, my God! Poor Bill! Oh, God!
-All right. Come on, dear. Show me.
-No. No!
It's all right. I'll take care of you.
I used to work for the Christys
What's going on?.
Help me get out of here!
It's this place and the storm.
That's why you're upset.
No, no! They're all dead!
They're all dead!
-All right. I'll go look.
-Don't leave me! They'll kill you too!
I'm not afraid.
Oh, my Lord!
So young.
So pretty.
What monster could have done this?.
Bill is out there!
Oh, God, this place!
Steve should never have opened this place again!
There's been too much trouble here.
Did you know a young boy drowned?
The year before those two others were killed.
The counselors weren't paying attention!
They were making love while that young boy drowned!
His name was Jason.
I was working the day it happened.
Preparing meals.
Here. I was the cook.
Jason should have been watched!
Every minute! He was...
He wasn't a very good swimmer.
We can go now, dear.
I think we should wait for Mr. Christy.
- That's not necessary.
- I don't understand.
Help me!
Help, Mommy!
Help! Help, Mommy!
I am, Jason. I am.
You see, Jason was my son.
And today is his birthday.
Where's Mr. Christy?.
I couldn't let them open this place again.
Could l?.
Not after what happened.
Oh, my sweet, innocent Jason.
My only child...Jason.
You let him drown!
You never paid any attention!
Look what you did to him!
Kill her, Mommy. Kill her!
Don't let her get away, Mommy.
Don't let her live!
I won't, Jason. I won't!
Where are the goddamn bullets?.
Come, dear It will be easier for you
than it was for Jason.
Kill her, Mommy. Kill her!
Kill her.
Kill her, Mommy. Kill her.
She can't hide.
No place to hide.
Get her, Mommy. Get her!
Kill her! Kill her.
Ten milligrams, Valium.
It's all right.
It's all over. Everything's over.
Roll over. Roll over, dear.
Your folks are on the way up.
Is anyone else alive?.
- Are they all dead?.
- Yes, ma'am.
Two of my men pulled you out of the lake.
We thought you were dead too
Do you remember very much?.
The boy.
Is he dead too?.
-Who?.
-The boy, Jason.
Jason?
In the lake. The one who attacked me.
The one who pulled me under the water
Ma'am, we didn't find any boy.
But he....
Then he's still there.
Please rate this subtitle at www.osdb.link/4vd9t
Help other users to choose the best subtitles