Subtitle downloaded with
Sublight (www.sublight.me)
Griffin.
Griffin, what did I say?
I'm in the middle
of a game.
Yeah, you can't play that in the car
unless you take your Dramamine.
It's too late for Dramamine,
we're practically there.
Don't roll your eyes at me.
You want him puking in the car again?
- I said I was sorry.
- No. It's not your fault.
- That was smelly.
- Was not. It was only an accident.
- Nobody is blaming you, honeybun.
- It was smelly.
- Following the GPS.
- It stinks.
Look.
That's left end of Kitty Hawk.
No, no, no...
Dad.
- There's no way we can live here.
- Oh. Come on.
You haven't even
seen the house yet.
- There are power lines.
- Relax.
I can feel the tumors
swarming already.
- No one is getting tumors.
- What tumors?
- It's a joke, dumbass.
- It's a joke, dumbass!
- Don't say that, sweetie.
- Make a U-turn in 50 feet..
- What?
- Oh. You miss the turn?
- Yes ma'am.
- Dumbass.
- Okay. - Wee...
- Madison.
- Wee...
- Ha-ha.
Come on.
Nice right?
- Yeah.
- Cosy.
- I think it's nice.
- I think it's nice too.
Piggycorn too.
- Mr. And Mrs. Bowen.
- Hi. Sorry we're late.
We missed that turn
on Kitty Hawk.
Yeah.
Modern technology.
He's gonna go right in.
Start checking it out.
That hoop is cool.
Nice tree, huh?
That's been here longer
than any of the houses.
You want to climb?
Mom, Mom there's a kitchen.
- Oh wow.
- I'm going to see my bedroom.
Slow down please,
on the stairs.
That security system works.
The owner was a bit of a technophile.
So this house is wire proof
for whatever you might need.
You'll noticed.
He puts speakers in all the walls.
So you can hear
music in every room.
Including the john.
Will either of you two
be commuting to work?
Not me.
I'll be home with the kids.
Amy is an amazing writer.
- Oh Eric. Come on.
- She is.
She's being humble right now,
she is very good.
I'm trying to be
but you know.
It's just hard to find time.
I know, believe me.
I have two of my own.
They're in college.
I'm glad they're gone.
I mean,
I'm getting my life back.
Where did you say that
you worked, Mr. Bowen?
John Deere Corporate
over at Marlene.
That's a wonderful company.
We have a riding mower.
It's lasted us for years.
Oh, we love John Deere.
Oh well. I'd be very flattered
right now if I hadn't get laid off.
- Oh I'm sorry, I didn't realise that.
- That's alright.
No. They do have a quality.
Yeah they do, but.
No, they were making some
cut backs and I was...
Hey Eric.
Come look at this.
I love to honey but
I'm in the middle of a
very awkward exchange
with our realtor right now.
- Come see.
- Is that alright?
- Don't go anywhere.
- Please.
- Hey. Oh hey.
- There is a field.
- Whose property is that?
- Oh, that's city property.
That's a good place for a bushfire.
We have to try to like this.
Okay, I'll try.
Would you like to
see the upstairs?
Yes, I would.
And this is the master
that you're showing us!
- That's correct.
- Oh.
How is it up there, kiddo?
I like our house better.
Oh, that's not an option honey.
You call that a bedroom,
but really it's an attic.
That could be where
Griffin sleeps.
It's funny.
Yeah.
Piggycorn?
No, Piggycorn is not my baby.
She's just a doll.
She is half pig and
half unicorn. See.
She has a little horn.
Honk-honk.
Who are you talking to?
No one.
Mom, we like this house.
Jesus.
This really is stuck.
That's probably just moisture,
it rained last week.
Okay, well ...
I don't know.
All the houses are like this
in our price range.
And this is the least sucky
one we've seen so I think.
- Maybe.
Yeah maybe ...
Foreclosure has hit this
neighbourhood really hard.
There's some wiggle room
on the price.
How much wiggle
are we talking?
Whoa, whoa, whoa...
Whoa! Whoa!
Whoa!
- Come on. Man!
- Sorry.
- Perfect.
- Buck up, kiddo. It's temporary.
We ruin your life.
- Good.
- Yeah.
Heh-heh-
hee-hee..
What if the bad guys
break in a window?
Then the alarm will still go off.
But what if the bad guys
cut the wires to the alarm?
The wires are in the house.
But what if the bad guys went to the
power plant and cut the wires there?
Uh well. They will be
electrocuted and then if
their... then they'll be dead.
And if they're dead
then they can't get in the house.
Bizz.
- Are we arm yet?
- Mm-Hm.
Getting there.
Might wanna...
think about getting
a dog or something.
No.
Here it says you have to input the
security code and then the star key.
- Oh, yeah, smart guy?
- Oh, What was that?
Same thing happened to me.
Ain't that weird.
It's not even winter.
And they found this house.
They ate it all up.
What are you doing?
Playing.
Do you want
to see a trick?
What kind of trick?
No way.
How are you doing that?
Heh-heh-heh...
You try.
You look ridiculous.
The hair.
Why do I have
to be up here?
Because this is
the coolest room.
And you're the
coolest kid in the house.
But I don't like the ceiling.
Okay. Now you're just
being silly, come on.
Now. Who's my superboy?
- Mom...
I'm sorry.
Are you too big to say it now?
- No.
- Then who's my superboy?
- I am.
- Yeah. You are.
- I love you.
- I love you too.
Now get some sleep, okay?
The nightlight!
Nightlight!
Sorry, sorry. Sorry...
Okay, okay, okay?
Is that better?
Griffin, there's nothing
to be afraid of.
Okay.
- Good night, buddy.
- Good night.
I had to do something.
This place is like a
complete shit hole.
I mean there's
not even any malls,
like the malls are
all boarded up.
Oh my god.
That actually sounds really sad.
So, your dad get sacked.
Dude, dude, dude.
Oh yea.
I love that show.
Yeah.
Oh my god.
That guy is a total freak.
I'm Carrigan Burke
and I'm here to clean house.
Oh. Yeah, yeah, yeah.
I love it when he's like
Okay, ready.
"This house...
- is cleaned."
- Is cleaned.
Hey, hey, hey.
Can you turn that down?
Uh, come in?
Kids are going to sleep.
Hi, Lauren.
Hey, Mrs. Bowen.
Thank you, goodnight.
- Heh-ha-ha...
- Mrs. Bowen?
What is Griff
freaking out about?
- The nightlight.
- And.
The nightlight.
I don't know
what it is with him.
Yeah, well.
We got too many kids.
I know. I said we should
have stopped at 2.
- Well. Maddie's not the problem.
- Not yet.
Here's to the little jerks.
Do you think we should
take him to a shrink?
No.
He's fine.
He's not fine. It's because
I lost him in that mall. Eh.
Baby.
That was 3 years ago. And you
were more freaked out than he was.
Some kids are just nervous.
You know.
My brother was the same way.
- Yeah, Now he lives alone in a trailer park.
- He doesn't live alone.
- Yes, he does.
- He has got like 20 cockatoos.
You are not making
me feel better.
Maybe you could coach?
- What? High school?
- Yeah. Could be a fun thing.
I mean you'll be happy.
And be hungry.
We'll all be.
Can't support a family
coaching high school.
I should go back to work.
Again with that, come on.
You don't want to do that.
You leave me alone
with these monsters.
My, I need new underwear.
Look at these.
These are sad.
- Your underwear is sad?
- Yes, my underwear is sad.
Oh. My are very happy right now.
So get over here.
Serious.
We can't keep holding up for
something on your old salary.
I think we're holding up.
Why can't I just
look for something?
Because we agreed I would work,
so you can write your book.
That's what we agreed about.
I'm not writing my book.
You will. When the
kids go back to school.
Don't put this on my kids
This is on me.
Hey. I'm gonna
find something. Okay.
You got to trust me.
We got that dinner party
tomorrow night.
You love parties.
I've watched you drink Bourbon.
'Course it's gonna be such a drag.
We don't even know those people.
Yeah, but Gary knows him.
He says the husband might be hiring.
Oh yeah.
Maybe our luck is about to change.
Aren't you feeling lucky?
- Nm-nm.
- I think things are... looking up.
You're such a dork.
I'm a dork?
- You and your sad underwear.
- Take your pants off.
Yes ma'am.
- Really?
- Yeah.
- Wow.
- Take it off.
- Alright.
- Eh-heh-heh...
- Dad.
- Yes!
Hey!
- What's up, buddy?
- There's something upstairs.
I think there's something
in my room.
I'll... I'll be up there
in a second.
So much for my luck.
- Don't move, be right back.
- Okay.
- Think dirty thoughts.
- Mm-Mm.
Okay. What is it, buddy?
Was it something in the attic?
Houses make noises at night.
It's normal, I promise.
Not our old house.
Well. That's true.
Hey, why don't you
tell me what you heard.
Where does all these
clowns come from?
I found them in there.
Why would somebody
have a box of clowns?
People collect weird things, pal.
I don't like it up here.
What's the matter? You scared?
What are you scared of?
Everything.
You got to get over that.
You gotta try to worry less, kiddo.
You know.
If you're scared all the time,
Maddie gonna get scared.
You got to set a good example.
You're the big brother. Be brave.
You got to be
brave. You know.
Oh shit!
- Dad!
- Hah!
What is it?
Hah!
Talk to me.
Why you linger here?
Use me, I can release you.
Use me.
- What's going on?
- I do not know.
Eric. What is going on up there?
What, what.
What, what?
We have a squirrel.
You are such a nut ball.
- Big, fuzzy, tail, terrible.
- You scared us.
Perfect.
Rodents.
Let's set a trap tomorrow.
After you catch it
with the trap.
Will you release it
to the woods.
Yeah sure.
- Would that make you feel better, honey?
- Mm-Hm.
I'm not sleeping up
there until it's gone.
Who else is there with you?
Can Griffin come too?
Yes, I do mean free.
I have to ask my mommy.
No.
I'm not afraid.
Yes.
But.
How will you get here?
Maddie, what's going on?
They are coming.
Who is?
Who is coming?
Maddie, get away from the TV!
What is going on?
They are here.
It says here it's probably just a loose
conductor on the electrical power.
Yeah, well. I'm calling an electrician.
Oh what're you going to pay
him for when I can do it myself.
Those guys charge normally like a...
Griff will me, right buddy?
- Griff will help you fix an electrical panel?
- Yeah.
I found out where the
squirrel got in by the way.
- There's a hole by the the roof line.
- Uh-huh.
- Dad, I don't want cereal, I want pizza.
- I'm gonna blocked it up.
- Yeah! For breakfast?
- For all the timer.
3 times a day.
Griffin, I told you
not to touch my phone.
- I didn't touch your phone.
- Then why is it fried?
- How do I know
- Here we go.
I need a new phone.
- Oh. You do, huh.
- No more. No more phones, honey.
This isn't a luxury item, dad.
I mean, it's a necessity.
What if you need to
reach me in an emergency?
- We can't afford it, honey.
- That's bullshit.
- Kendra.
- Hey, why are you being so selfish about.
- That's bullshit!
- Hey, Maddie.
If you want a new phone,
you can get a part time job.
I'll get a job when
you get a job
- Hey! Hey! She has a job.
- Excuse me?
You kids are her job.
Oh.
Which I apparently suck at it.
- I don't think you suck at it.
- Thank you sweetheart.
Hey Maddie. Do you
remember last night?
- When you said, they are here.
- Uh-huh.
What did you mean?
- Who is here?
- Just my friends.
Yeah.
Your pretend friends?
No, they are lost people.
They are not pretend, mommy.
Girl's going to put
me in a hole, man.
She's grounded.
Judge Bowen has spoken.
For at least 24 hours.
Remind her, she's babysitting
tonight. Will you.
I hate it Kendra babysits.
- So does she, pal.
I think I might make us
some squirrel traps.
Yeah, that's a good idea.
What is this?
- Oh, Griffin. Put that down.
- What is that?
- Put that down.
- Is that a bone or something?
- Yes. Put that down.
- Let me see.
This is a buried pet or something.
Maybe it's a horse.
Maybe it's a.
Maybe it's a pig too.
- A Pig.
- This thing freaking you out.
- Stop.
- What's the matter?
Stop.
Alright.
Put that back.
Yeah, that's not going through.
I'm sorry about that. My wife said
she might cancel one of the cards
because we don't need them all.
I didn't know she did it.
It's not canceled,
it's over the limit.
- Is that what is says there?
- Yup.
Okay, let's try this one.
Ms. Apron.
Are you in the Union?
You have a good
pension here for this...
- Sorry. This one is... canceled too.
- Yeah.
Strike 2, huh.
Alright.
- Hey. Third one's the charm.
- Fingers crossed.
How're doing?
Are we good?
- Yeah. Yeah, you're good.
- Love that sound. Okay.
Aw.
Damn it.
Griffin.
I asked you to bring these comic
- books upstairs.
- I was just about to do it.
Yeah. I almost broke my neck.
Because you were walking and playing
that games at the same time I bet.
Thank you.
Maddie.
Is that you?
Maddie?
Maddie.
This isn't funny.
All right, everybody.
Come downstairs.
- Come on, family meeting.
- Dad! Dad!
- Dad! I have to tell you something.
- Let's go. Kendra, come down here.
Hey baby. What's going on
with the flowers out there?
I don't know.
Did you get pizza?
- I just made Chicken Nuggets.
- It's okay, we'll have both.
Pizza.
- Get everyone a pizza
- you put them together you got Chicken Nugget Pizza.
- Dad!
- Sounds good right.
- Dad, the weirdest thing happened!
Oh yeah. Why are you screaming
at me, Griffin? You're screaming.
- What?
- What? What?
Here's what.
Huh.
- What's that?
- Look at that.
- No way.
- Yeah way.
- You know what else?
- Now get off my back.
- Thank you, daddy.
- You got it.
- Dad! And guess what?
- Yeah.
- The ball rolled across the floor
- What? What?
- Knocked into the closet and
- Hey look at this.
- Got you that AR drone you wanted.
- Look at that, ain't it cool.
- Dad! You're not listening to me.
It has a camera on it.
- It does?
- What are you doing?
What are you doing, kidding?
Look at that.
These are the ones you like.
To wear them to
the party tonight.
Dad, that's not all. There was
this tower of comic books formed.
When I turned around,
they blew back at my face.
They have just appeared out of no where.
- Oh wow.
- And make them all.
- Really? That's crazy.
- It's not funny, Dad.
- Yes. Hilarious.
How did you pay this?
What. How do you think.
I stole it. Robbed a bank.
- Uh oh.
- Oh oh. Daddyo.
We gotta bring this set back.
You have to take it back.
- Mom. No. Mom.
- We're not bringing anything back.
- Griffin.
- I think we deserve a treat.
Why doesn't anyone listen to me?
Griffin, gosh! It's been
all afternoon with this.
Just so you know, I putting a pass code
on my phone. So you can't get to it.
- Please don't antagonize him.
- Dad, we have to move.
We're not moving.
Now quit it
- Amy.
- No, I expect this from Maddie.
But I'm starting to think
he's the baby in the family.
- Hey you go, mommy.
- Thank you sweetheart.
- Griffin, I'm sorry.
- Everything didn't go well as I hope.
- How's the pizza? Yeah.
- Mm...
- No good.
- Yeah.
No.
Alright, you need to just try with
the nuggets. It's a little better.
- Daddy. Break my arm. Break my arm.
- Okay. Okay.
- Now my neck! Neck! Neck!
- Dad.
Dad, what if the
squirrel gets in?
I've sealed up the hole.
It's tighter than Fort Knox up there.
- Bye bye, daddy.
- Then why did you leave the trap?
Insurance, you can't be too safe.
Squirrels are wildlly smart.
- Okay. Bye, bye, bye...
- Okay. Don't worry about it.
- Set the alarm. Call us if you need us.
- I will.
- Call you on my new phone.
- Yeah you will.
- Okay. Be good to your sister.
- Bye mommy.
- Lock the door.
- I will. Bye. Bye.
I want to stay up all night!
- No. Maddison, no. Go upstairs.
No!
Alright.
Wait, wait.
Piggycorn says she
wants more kisses.
- She does, huh?
- Uh-huh.
- How many?
- She says 3.
- 3.
- Sure?
- Uh-huh.
- Okay.
- 1.
- 2.
- 3.
20.
I love you.
I can't fall sleep.
Why not?
I think there's a storm coming.
Eric tells me you played ball together in college.
Said you had quite a swing.
Oh, triple A. But I still do
swing with the best of them.
Don't get any ideas, Barbara.
He could have played in the Mayors,
he's been very modest.
I had a bad shoulder,
so it wasn't meant to be.
Well. Lucky you had a
plan B to fall back on.
Nothing wrong with suit and tie.
I keep telling my son.
It pays the rent.
It's a good thing I have
a suit and tie then,
I can put them on
Monday morning, if you like.
What time do I start?
9.
They just moved
to Willow Point.
My brother had a house in that
development back in the 90s.
We've never visit him because
of the cemetery thing.
The thought of it
just give me the willies.
- What cemetery thing?
- Just that.
That development was
built on a former cemetery.
- But they moved it though.
- Yeah.
The developers relocated the
whole thing to Bronson Park.
200 hectares.
This was years ago.
You can't mean they
moved the whole cemetery?
- The realtor didn't mention it?
- No. Actually, they didn't mention it.
Just like, you know. Very uncool.
They like to move all those bodies and.
Well. It's not like it was an
ancient tribal burial ground.
It's just 10 minutes away. I mean,
people can still visit loved ones.
But now it's in
a nicer neighborhood.
Oh, I'm sorry.
There is nothing to be afraid of.
HELP!
PLEASE HELP!
Kendra!
Maddie.
We're gonna get
into big trouble.
Griffin?
I'm scared.
Just stay away from the closet.
Don't leave me!
Kendra!
Aww!
Dad!
DAD!
(Dad... Dad...)
What the hell is that?
Alright stop.
- Stop the car.
- Why?
Stop the car.
Help me!
Aw!
Somebody help!
Griff?
Help!
Griffin.
Oh my god.
Griff.
Are you alright?
Okay baby.
What the hell is going on?
Mom!
- Dad. Mom. Dad.
- What... What's going on?
The basement.
I got locked in the basement.
Slow down. Slow down, I cannot..
- What? What did you say?
- I can't find Maddie.
Madison?
Where are you, Maddie?
Mom?
Madison?
Mom.
Mom!
Griff?
Griff.
Mom.
Mommy?
Maddie, where are you?
Mommy.
Daddy, is that you?
- We don't even know what happened.
- I know but we have to tell them.
- We got to figure out what happened. Okay.
- We have to call them.
We can't call the cops.
What're you going to tell them?
That our daughter got, I don't know what just
happened there. - I'm gonna tell them that.
We need to figure out
what's going on. Okay.
Listen.
Listen to me.
If you call the cops,
they're going to blame us.
No, they're not going to blame us.
We're just gonna tell them what happened.
We're just gonna tell them the truth.
I'm going to tell them the truth.
We're going to tell the truth together.
I'm going to tell them the
truth of what happened.
I wanted hope.
We don't know what the truth is, honey.
- We don't know what the truth is.
- Eric, we have to call someone.
There's got to be somebody
who is going to believe us.
DEPT. PARANORMAL
RESEARCH
Griffin was the first one
to notice things, noises.
Things.
I thought he was making it up.
Sorry, buddy.
We didn't know
where else to go.
No. You did the right
thing coming here.
When I was a student here,
This office has the craziest reputation.
I think we still do.
Um.
May I ask where
your husband is?
He's at home with Kendra, our oldest.
We don't want to leave Maddie alone.
The last time you had contact with her
was after she disappeared?
Just the one time.
Uh.
Through the television set. I'm sorry.
I hear how crazy this sounds?
I know I must sound ridiculous.
No. No, it doesn't.
It doesn't sound crazy at all.
- It's my fault.
- No, it is not.
Look at me. Look at me
It's not your fault.
Why... Why do you think
it's your fault?
I left her alone.
I knew I shouldn't have.
But I was scared.
Of course.
Of course you were scared.
You have to get my sister back.
You have to.
Can you do that?
I can try.
That's the uh.
TV where Maddie's
hands were on.
This is the staircase that Griffin
was first grabbed by the trees.
Aw!
And then, there's that.
That slob shocker.
You guys want some
sandwiches or something?
- It won't be necessary.
- I'm going to start recording, is that cool?
Yeah.
Knock yourself out.
That's solid wall. I poked and
probed it about 100 times.
You think she got pulled
through there somehow?
We don't know.
What do you think.
It's like a magical portal?
I just said we don't know.
Hey. Would you mind if I hold on to that?
I just, till she gets back.
I don't want it, you know.
Lost in the shuffle.
No. No problem.
You know I shot a pretty amazing
occurrence recently.
We were at this an old
house in Naperville and,
a piano bench rolled 10 feet
across the parlor floor.
It took seven hours.
- To roll 10 feet?
- Yeah.
But I used this special time-lapse
setting on my camera
so...
nailed the whole thing.
You can't catch that kind of a thing
with the naked eye so I...
Did you get all that on your
time-lapse camera?
From my experience, this doesn't
seem to be a classic haunting.
What you have here is probably
closer to a poltergeist intrusion.
What is the difference?
Ghost usual appears as harmless
apparition whereas poltergeist ...
They are noisy, they lash out,
they are violent, they move objects.
It comes, and it can
just suddenly go away.
And take Maddie with it?
- You okay?
- Yeah.
Yeah. What's going on?
Should have been me.
Home, you know.
- Should have been home.
- Don't do this, okay. Okay.
I can't lose you now.
If I say: It's not gonna be okay.
You have to say: Of course it is, sweetheart.
Otherwise we're not
going to get through this.
We've done a scan of the house.
And now we're, we're wiring into you system
so if Maddie tries to
make contact again,
we will be able to have a better
sense of what's going on
which may help us get her back.
Is that sound okay?
That sounds great.
Can we do it a little faster?
Watch it.
Hey, let me ask you something?
Your dad.
He's been out of work a while.
Right?
Yeah, I guess.
That's okay.
Nobody's perfect.
I was just thinking about it.
You know If you really want
to make some money quick.
A poltergeist abduction
isn't a bad idea.
Even if it turn out to be a fake
You know you go public with it.
You do some TV appearances.
- You get your own reality show.
- Would you stop
How cool would that be?
We don't want a reality show.
We just want to Maddie back.
You're good, kid.
Very good.
Did you set up the heat sensor
in the back of the closet yet?
No, not yet. I didn't uh,
didn't know how to fasten that thing.
Screw it, Boyd.
Okay.
Captain.
Screw it.
Damn.
Gotcha.
You all done up there?
Yeah.
The heat sensors in the closet?
Sort of.
Boyd. I really need you
to take this more seriously. Okay?
- Okay?
- Okay.
Okay.
Good.
What I think
what I was saying is...
some people believe there are
different levels of reality.
We're on a physical plane.
But when we die,
our spirits go to uh,
Another level.
An astro plane or spiritual plane.
Which is sort of here and
not here at the same time.
Okay.
Look at this.
Like this.
Thank you, Dr. Powell.
Is us, here. On the physical level.
And some how
Maddie got pulled... here.
Here and not here
at the same time.
Exactly.
Then someone should go in there
and show her the way back here.
That's actually not a bad idea.
I'm fairly certain that Maddie is able to
hear us a lot better than we can hear her.
So this equipment is going to ...
filter out all the interference,
so that we'll be better able
to communicate with her.
How do we start?
You just call out to her.
Okay
Yeah.
Maddie?
Madison, it's mommy.
Can you hear me?
Madison, we want to talk to you.
We just want you to let us
know that you're safe.
Are you with us?
Maddie, we need to hear your voice, okay sweetheart.
Can you say hello to Mommy?
Are you with us?
We all miss you very much.
Mommy misses you
so, so, so... much.
Mom.
Mommy.
Oh, hey baby.
Hey honey, Daddy's here too.
We're all waiting for you, honey.
Daddy, where are you?
We're home, we need you to
come back to us now honey.
I tried,
but I can't find you.
Okay, okay, okay.
Well, keep on trying.
Okay, because we are right here.
Okay, you're so close.
Mommy.
Mommy, Daddy.
Is that you?
No.
Daddy is right here, honey.
There's somebody with her.
- Who is with you, baby?
- Daddy's right here, honey.
Who is with you?
They are all around me ...
Mom.
Look out.
Maddie!
- Maddie, can you hear us?
- What's going on with the lights?
Mommy.
- Daddy?
- Maddie?
Madison
Daddy, I'm scared.
Maddie
- No. Wait, wait, wait...
- Mr Bowen, no! Mr Bowen, no!
Maddie. It's me, honey.
Give her back!
Can't have her!
You okay?
Did you get hit?
No. You okay?
Everything okay?
What is that?
- Eric?
- Eric.
What happened?
That, Mr. Bowen.
That's Maddie's way out.
But I think we're gonna need
some help in getting her there.
What kind of help?
Have you ever heard
of Carrigan Burke?
No F you way.
What happened to your hand?
Blanchard, Michigan, '97.
Found a root basement,
spirit didn't want to leave.
- Lucky, they're not all that angry.
- Ours is.
- Hey buddy, you okay?
- Yeah. The guy is there.
- You must be the Bowens.
- You must be the cavalry.
- Yeah.
- Dr Powell.
Well. We're all set up if
you want to get started.
Hey.
Big fan of.
My name is Boyd.
Nice to meet you.
Here.
- He knows this can't be on TV, right?
- Yeah. I told him that.
So why is he doing it?
This is the area of bilocation.
The table fell out, I was almost crushed.
Is everything alright?
If it was,
I wouldn't be here.
This house
is not clean.
- Shh.
- What?
Alright
First things first.
I want you to tell me a
little bit about Maddie.
Did you ever feel that she
was uh, a little bit off?
- Off? What do you mean?
- How do you mean. Off?
You know. Have you ever hear her
talking to things that weren't there?
Yeah, but. She has imaginary
friends, but that's normal.
I think what he's trying to say is that,
Maddie might had been born with a gift.
That's not the word I use,
but alright.
You mean
she can talk to ghosts?
She's 6 years old.
Which means that her
life force is at its purest.
Without judgment or cynicism.
Why do you think they reach out
to her in the first place.
They didn't reach out
to any of you?
You keep saying "they",
where, who, who are "they"?
Uh now. Brooke tells me that this
development was built on a cemetery.
- Right?
- Dad, really?
Calm down. It is a
former cemetery. Former.
They moved the bodies
a long ago.
- Relocated to.
- Yeah. They moved into a nicer neighborhood.
Now. I don't think
that they are.
I think they just told people
they moved the cemetery and...
I think they just
moved the headstones.
And they left the bodies.
Oh my god.
This isn't just a few pissed-off
spirits that we're dealing with.
This is unlike anything
that I ever felt before.
This is.
It's more like a mob.
They suffered a terrible injustice...
and that, that anger and frustration
has created a more powerful force.
The poltergeist.
They are trapped,
and they are desperate.
And your daughter is their
ticket out of this purgatory.
What do they want with her?
They want her to be their
lantern in the darkness.
To lead them into the light.
What happens if she
goes into the light?
Then there's no getting
her back if she does that.
Okay. Just because he said that,
it doesn't mean it's, that's true. Okay.
Hey, nothing you said
makes sense to me.
And everything else does, right?
The closet, the tree, the smoldered hole
in the ceiling. All that makes sense to you.
- But I'm full of crap.
- I don't know, okay? I don't know.
We just want our daughter back. Okay.
We just want our daughter back.
Eric. I know exactly
how you feel.
- I don't know if you do.
- I felted it
every single day of my entire life.
It is hard to know what to believe in,
but I am here to help.
You believe that, don't you?
Okay.
You're all I've got.
So let's do it.
So. Everybody gets a GPS tracker.
This is going to tell us where you are.
Anytime. In case anything
gets, gets weird.
What are we suppose
to do with this?
Just put it in your pocket.
- Weird, right?
- Yeah.
- Check the leg?
- I don't know.
Can you show me
how to fly this thing?
Okay.
It's kind of complicated.
Do you want me to fly it?
I can handle it.
You can ask me about it,
or just stare at my leg the whole day.
I don't know what
you're talking about.
Let's just get this
over with, shall wet?
What are you doing?
No, no, no, no.
We don't need to
see that, it's weird.
- Ugh, what happened to you?
Portugal, 2003.
There's a monastery in the forest of
Bussaco with a particularly nasty entity.
And, you got rid of it?
Not before it took a
piece of my leg with it.
Okay uh, thank you for that.
It's gross, I'm gonna go
throw up. Thanks.
And what about that one?
That's a good story.
Let's save that for after
this is all over, shall we?
Assuming you don't die.
Okay.
Why do you do that?
- What?
You tell him your
old war stories.
You make yourself
sound like an old man.
Comes with the territories.
We aged in dog years.
You have kids, Mr. Burke?
Sadly no.
My wife didn't think it was a
good idea given our line of work.
It wasn't just the work.
Oh.
You...
The... two...
The two of you were...
- Briefly.
- We were young and stupid.
- The only one of us is stupid.
- Don't be so hard on yourself.
I was irresistible, back then.
I'm gonna go check
the readings up stairs.
And she goes,
just like she fled our marriage.
Straight into the arms of academia.
Safe, stable academia.
- Still misses me though.
- No, I don't.
- You do, a little.
- No, not even a little bit.
She thinks that I can
sense these things.
- I have special powers, you know.
- You're not that special.
You alright?
I'm a little scared.
Yeah. Me too. What are you
going to do about that?
I don't know
Think about Maddie?
Let's try that.
- Feeling less scared?
- No, not in a way.
Yeah, me neither.
- I feel a little braver though.
- Me too.
- We're good.
- Brooke, video's up.
- We're all set to go down here.
- Let's go.
Kendra, would you throw me
that belt that's in that bag there?
That's it.
Alright.
Just so we're all clear.
First, we use the rope to bridge
the way in to the way out.
The rules are different in there.
There is no up. There is no down.
There are no straight lines.
Which is why
we have to make one.
This rope is our lifeline.
If we let go of it...
we will never find our way.
It worked.
Once we've done that.
We send the drone in
to get eyes on Maddie.
Keep it steady now.
Keep it steady.
Maddie.
- Maddie, can you hear me?
- Mommy.
Madison.
Madison, honey.
Madison, are you hurt?
It's Mommy.
Mommy?
Maddie!
Daddy?
- Madison. Carrigan!
- We're losing her now, get her out.
- I will go.
- No!
Listen to me, Eric. Listen to me.
I'm her mother, I have to go.
- You have to listen. You can't, you have to back me up.
- I'm going in.
She's too close to the light.
I got to go in and get her out.
No, I'm going.
- You can't go. She won't come to a stranger.
- You've never done this before.
You have no idea what
you are dealing with.
Shout out and sound
the family service!
- I got to get here out of there now!
- Wait. Everyone stop!
- Griffin is already upstairs.
- Griff!
Oh my god.
Griff.
Griffin!
I should have never
left her alone.
No!
Griffin!
- Griffin!
- No!
GRIFFIN!
Griffin!
No!
Go downstairs, grab a hold onto the rope.
When I give you the signal,
pull with all your might.
What if it doesn't work?
Amy, sweetheart.
It's gonna work.
This better work.
Hey man. You seem you
can talk to these things, right?
Well you tell them,
it's time to let Maddie go!
I'm counting on you.
This child has done you no harm.
She speaks no harm.
Wait.
No, no, no...
He's off the screen. He's off the screen.
We lost him.
Maddie.
Maddie?
Griffin.
Maddie, we have to go.
I can't.
Yes, you can.
We have to go now.
They'll never let me leave.
The rope!
Run, Maddie.
Come on!
Watch out!
Maddie.
Griffin.
I got you.
- Come on, baby. You'll be okay.
- Are they breathing?
- Eric!
Mommy's right here.
Mommy, sweetie.
Are they okay?
- What do we do?
- Get them in the water now!
- Wake up, baby. Wake up, baby.
- Griffin, wake up.
Okay, sweetie.
Come on, baby. Wake up.
Can you hear me?
Can you hear Mom?
Alright.
Wake up, sweetheart.
- Come on. Come on. Sweetheart.
- Come on, please. Wake up.
- Come on.
- Griffin, I'm counting on you.
- I need you to wake up right now. Okay.
- Buddy.
- Good boy. Good boy.
- Oh, baby.
- There he is.
- Is Maddie okay?
- Yeah. Maddie is okay.
Maddie is going to be okay.
- Okay. Can you hear Mommy?
- Come on, sweetheart.
Please wake up.
Oh, sweetheart.
Oh, baby.
Oh sweetheart.
Hi Mommy.
Hi Daddy.
- Hey.
- Hey sweetie.
It's okay, Mommy.
Griffin's safe.
Yeah, he is. You know why?
Because you're superboy.
I love you two.
I love you ten.
Oh my god.
Alright.
Hop on your sit.
- When are we ever coming back?
- No, sweetheart. No way in hell.
Hey. Thanks for everything.
And uh
Hope we'll never see you again.
I don't know why
they always say that.
- Bye.
So tell me.
I deserve it.
Burbank, California 2012.
They were shooting an episode
in a haunted car wash.
And the sound guy
fell asleep.
- So not a ghost?
- No.
Just a dozy boom operator
with a very, very large microphone.
- Do the line!
- I'm not saying it.
- Mom, it's for Lauren.
- Burke, give her the line!
- The house is cleaned.
- Better. Come on.
- The house... is cleaned.
- Oh my god. She's going to freak.
- This house is cleaned.
- It isn't though.
Yes it is, sweetheart.
You helped the spirits
go into the light.
But they didn't.
- Dad. Go.
- Dad. Go, go, go...
They wouldn't go into the light, mommy.
They needed me to take them.
But I wouldn't go away,
so neither did they.
- Dad. Go.
- Dad. Go, go, go...
- Go, go. Dad.
- Dad!
Get out of the car.
Mom!
Honey, you okay?
- Everybody okay?
- Yeah.
Here, baby,
Hold on.
Where' Maddie?
Where is she? Where is she?
Maddie!
Mommy?
Something's wrong, Mom.
Maddie.
Maddie!
- Mom.
- Maddie!
- Hold on.
Mom.
Mom!
Here, baby.
Come on.
Mommy!
Hold on!
- Pull!
Release your hold on this family!
As you yourself wish to be released!
No.
Don't do something stupid.
I know something stupid?
The way you left me.
Carrigan.
Please.
They're never gonna
let this family go.
I'm tired of faking it for
the cameras. Brooke
I'm the only one left who can
lead those souls into the light.
You know that.
- Wait. You don't have to do this.
- I know, I want it.
Wait. How would I know
if you make it back?
I'll think of something.
Bye, Brooke.
Amy, come here.
Let's go.
Maddie.
Come on.
- Watch your head.
- Okay.
Maddie. Maddie.
Okay, let's go.
Mommy's going to get you.
- No. No.
- Kendra. Come here!
- Let's go.
- I'm sorry I'm such a bitch to you, Dad.
Okay, honey. Can we talk
about it later? Let's go.
- Hey! What are you doing?
- I got a job to do.
Wait!
- Dad!
- Eric.
Eric, jump.
- Amy, we got to find a car.
- Mom!
Wait, Eric.
Take mine, go.
Mom!
Come on!
Let's go!
Any sign of him?
Nothing.
The GPS isn't picking him up.
Wait, we're getting something.
- Hello.
- Hi.
Hello, you obviously found it. Okay.
Isn't it beautiful?
I think this one is "it".
I mean great school district,
the high school ball field close by.
Wait till you see the inside.
4 proper bedrooms
and the place is just
swimming in closet space.
- That's aren't really high on our wish list.
- Our last closet eat me.
That's sweet.
Anyway.
This house just scream character.
I mean look at the way it's squatting.
And in here is the foyer,
period detail throughout.
Oh. And this is the den.
The den leads right into the backyard.
Perfect for the kids.
And do you see that tree.
I mean it's ancient.
It was here before...
Hello?
Perfect.
Let's get outta here.
This labyrinth joined network hosts
to a malevolent spirit.
I'm Carrigan Burke.
- And I am here to flush his ...
- And I am Brooke Powell.
- And we're here to clean house.
- I hadnt finished.
- I hadn't finished my line.
I would not say clean house.
Requote that.
Because I thought that my cue was
when you said 'and I'm Carrigan Burke'.
- I didn't say that.
- As soon as I heard 'and'
I just came right out.
- That's the wrong window.
- Okay.
I.
Do..do...
Does someone want to tell me the right way.
Please rate this subtitle at www.osdb.link/3v5qu
Help other users to choose the best subtitles