Subtitle downloaded with
Sublight (www.sublight.me)
11:55. Almost midnight.
Enough time for one more story.
One more story
before 12:00...
just to keep us warm.
In five minutes,
it will be the 21st of April.
One hundred years ago,
on the 21st of April...
out on the waters
around Spivey Point...
a small clipper ship
drew toward land.
Suddenly, out of the night,
the fog rolled in.
For a moment,
they could see nothing...
not a foot ahead of them.
Then they saw a light.
By God, it was a fire
burning on the shore...
strong enough to penetrate
the swirling mist.
They steered a course
toward the light...
but it was a campfire
like this one.
The ship crashed
against the rocks.
The hull sheared in two.
The mast snapped like a twig...
and the wreckage sank
with all the men aboard.
At the bottom of the sea...
lay the ''Elizabeth Dane''
with her crew...
their lungs
filled with salt water...
their eyes open
and staring into the darkness.
And above,
as suddenly as it had come...
the fog lifted...
receded
back across the ocean...
and never came again.
But it is told
by the fishermen...
and their fathers
and grandfathers...
that when the fog returns
to Antonio Bay...
the men
at the bottom of the sea...
out in the water
by Spivey Point...
will rise up
and search for the campfire...
that led them
to their dark and icy death.
Twelve o' clock,
the 21st of April.
It's twelve midnight...
and we just started
into the witching hour.
This is Stevie Wayne,
on top of the world tonight.
And I'll be here
right up until about 1:00.
I'm all through, Father.
Oh, thank you, Bennett.
I won't need you
until four tomorrow, Bennett.
Yes, sir.
Would you like something to
keep you warm on the way home?
No, thank you.
Father, can I get paid?
Why don't you come in at six
instead of four tomorrow?
Yes, sir.
Bennett?
It's 59 degrees outside.
And let me be the first
to wish Antonio Bay...
a happy birthday.
We're one hundred years old
today.
The weatherman's
been trying to spoil it for us.
He says we may be
in for some rain tonight.
But from where I'm sitting,
it looks like clear skies.
I think the weatherman's
been working too hard.
Well, I'll stay here
for another hour...
just to see if he's right.
And I'm inviting you
to stay here with me.
There's a cutter run aground
over here on the east bay, over.
Global 1X5.
It's the ''Lady Belle Pacific.''
Serial number 024KL596. Over.
Global 1X5,
the ''Lady Belle Pacific''...
is seaworthy, no major damage.
Why don't you
send a tow on over here...
about a quarter mile
above the Boatel. Over.
This is KAB,
Antonio Bay, California.
Six minutes after midnight.
Haven't heard
from the weatherman yet...
so I can't say for sure
about that rain...
but there's a full moon
and no clouds in the sky.
I'm Stevie Wayne.
And if you don't have anything
to do right now...
I'll be here playing music
all through the witching hour.
Even if you do
have something to do...
keep me turned on for a while...
and I'll try my best
to do the same for you.
OK!
-How far you going?
-Other side of town.
That's close enough.
-Make it?
-Yeah. Thank you.
Sip?
Thanks.
Listen,
I never hitchhiked before.
I just really want
to be careful.
-Can I ask you something?
-Sure.
Are you weird?
Yes, I am.
Yes, I am weird.
You are weird.
Thank God you're weird.
The last one was so normal,
it was disgusting.
He picked me up
in Santa Barbara.
By the time we got to Carmel
he wanted to marry me.
Oh, yeah. I thought
you never hitchhiked before.
Not before last week.
You're my...
thirteenth ride.
Oh, great. Weird and unlucky.
We'll see.
Look out!
-Are you all right?
-I'm fine.
-You're sure?
-I think so.
What the hell was--
It's exactly twelve minutes
after midnight...
and this is Stevie Wayne.
Let's get out of here.
I'm high tonight in the KAB
lighthouse on Spivey Point.
And in case you've forgotten,
it's April 21st...
and a happy birthday
for Antonio Bay.
Now, there's a celebration
planned for tonight.
So if you're so excited
about it you can't sleep...
well, stay up with me...
and I'll figure out some way
to keep you occupied.
Or not.
-KAB.
-Hi, sweetheart.
Hi, Dan. What have you got?
Well, I'm just calling
to see if you're lonely...
if there's anything
I can do about it.
Never lonely, Dan.
I thought
you were off work at 8:00.
I changed shifts to make it
to the big party tonight.
Will you be there?
Until I can talk someone else...
into giving up city life
for Antonio Bay, I'm it.
-And ''it'' means day and night.
-Too much work.
That's what I get
for owning a station.
And if you don't tell me
why you called...
in about fifteen seconds,
I'll have to hang up on you.
-Want something to talk about?
-Anything.
I've got a position
on a trawler about...
fifteen miles out
called the ''Sea Grass.''
And I've got
something on my scope--
appears to be a fog bank.
It's about 25 miles out,
moving in their direction.
Thanks, Dan.
That's worth about ten seconds.
I'm on the air. Bye.
Ahoy, maties.
This is KAB, Antonio Bay.
Stevie Wayne here
beaming a signal across the sea.
To the men of the ''Sea Grass,''
fifteen miles out tonight...
a warm hello...
and keep a watch out
for that fog bank...
heading in from the east.
Now, in the meantime...
relax with me
while I play this song...
from the Coupe DeVilles,
dedicated just to you.
Boy, would I like to meet her.
I saw her
at a grocery store one day.
-And?
-You would like to meet her.
She's crazy.
There's no fog bank out there.
What do you know about her?
-She owns that lighthouse.
-I know that.
Her son plays Little League
with my kid brother.
She's a mother?
I thought
you were happily married.
Not that happy.
No fog bank out there.
There's a fog bank out there.
All right. I'm drunk enough.
Let's go back.
All right, all right.
Al, come here.
-Just give him a hand.
-Come here.
What was that?
Come here.
It's the generator.
Wha--wha...
Al.
It's gone.
There was just a ship out there.
Al, listen.
Nothing.
-Listen.
-Who's there?
Who is that?
Al, it's right beside us.
It's big, Al. It's a ship.
It's a big ship!
What happened?
Did you get wet?
It's 12:43...
and I've got
four in a row for you...
right here on KAB.
Nothing but water, Stevie.
But it sure beats Chicago.
KAB.
I like what you said...
but for your information,
you lied.
The fog bank
has moved due west...
and probably
missed the ship entirely.
Well, my gauges must be wrong.
I've got a wind blowing
due east.
What kind of a fog
blows against the wind?
-You got me.
-I'm not so sure I want you.
You're just
a voice on the phone.
You're a voice on the radio.
We'd make a perfect couple.
You let me take you to dinner
tonight, I'll prove it to you.
Sorry, Dan.
My idea of perfection
is a voice on the phone.
OK, mystery lady.
-Good night.
Not bad.
I started a week ago
in San Diego...
right up the coast,
five drawings a day.
It'll probably take me a month
to get to Vancouver...
and if I can sell them
for five bucks apiece...
-I'll be rich.
-Yeah.
-Can I ask you something?
-Sure.
What's your name?
-Elizabeth.
-Nick.
-Hello, Nick.
-Hi.
Is that where you're from,
San Diego?
Wait a minute. You said,
''Can I ask something?''
Well, something,
to me, means one thing.
-San Diego is two things.
-OK.
Pasadena, and a lot of money.
Never a chance to do
anything I want to do.
What do you want to do?
I don't know.
That's OK. Me, neither.
I think I got to have this one.
Can I buy it?
The drawing's free.
It's 1:00, straight up...
the end of the witching hour,
and time for me to sign off.
So until tomorrow night,
at 6 P.M...
when KAB
comes back on the air...
this is Stevie Wayne,
your night light...
hoping you have
a nice rest of the night.
Hey, Mom !
Mom, come on. Get up.
Look what I found.
Andy...I love you...
but sometimes
you're a real pain.
Sure, Mom, but look it.
First, it was a gold coin.
Then it turned into
this neat piece of wood.
This is one of those times.
Look at it, Mom.
Good morning, Andrew.
Did you have a nice time
last night?
Yeah. Old Mr. Machen
told us ghost stories.
Did you thank Mrs. Kobritz
for bringing you home?
Yes, ma'am. Mom, can I have
a stomach pounder and a Coke?
-After lunch.
-OK.
I'm gonna go look
for another one.
Maybe this time
I can get the gold coin.
Where the hell is he?
Rolled out of here
at 4:15 yesterday.
-That's the last I saw of him.
-Al said 7:30, right here.
You know Al.
If I were you--
Did you call
the Coast Guard, Hank?
Nick, they probably
got drunk last night.
-No, he wouldn't do that.
-He'd do anything.
Al and I got drunk so many times
I can't count them all...
but we never got so shitfaced
we couldn't make it back in.
He's too good a sailor
to stay out there all night...
and not let somebody know.
-You sound like his wife.
-Just his friend.
-You worry too much, Nick.
-Yeah.
Where are we going?
I'm going to talk Ashcroft
into taking out his boat...
and looking for the ''Sea Grass.''
Who's Ashcroft?
Someone who owes me a favor.
Can I come along?
I thought you had to move on
to Vancouver?
Eventually.
The sheriff
will drive his own car.
The mayor and his wife
are to be picked up at 6:45...
and brought to the mayor's box.
Then we will have speeches
by the mayor...
the sheriff, and me.
-Do you have my notes?
-Yes, ma'am.
Then we will pass out
the candles...
and begin the procession.
Then I will go home
and pass out.
I'm almost afraid to look.
Well...
Not bad. Not bad at all.
A work of art.
Sandy, just be civil to me
for another five hours.
That's all I ask.
Let's see now.
The candles.
Did you order the candles?
What a thought--a candlelight
procession with no candles.
All taken care of.
And the promotional material--
did you get that to Stevie?
Signed, sealed, and delivered.
Sandy, you can be a very
annoying person at times...
but you do keep me together.
Thank you, Mrs. Williams.
...Spivey Point.
As of 1:57 today...
the ''Sea Grass''
had not responded...
to radio communication.
The Coast Guard
has begun a sweep...
south from Watley...
around Arcom Reef...
and should be
in the area of Spivey Point...
in approximately one hour.
Repeating this bulletin
from the Coast Guard...
be on the look out
for the ''Sea Grass''...
a thirty-foot trawler...
last seen approximately 15 miles
east of Spivey Point.
If you sight this vessel...
please notify
the Coast Guard immediately.
Nick, can I ask you a question?
Is it always like this?
It's always different.
You're worried, aren't you?
Yeah. She can get real mean.
There.
If I can just get through
the speeches without yawning.
-I couldn't sleep last night.
-Too excited?
No. Al went out on his boat
last night and didn't come home.
-He still isn't back.
-Mrs. Williams!
I called the Coast Guard,
and they said...
''Oh, he might have had
engine trouble.''
They said not to worry.
He was complaining
about his boat last week.
Maybe you ought to go home.
That's the last place
I want to go.
My dog started to bark
at 12:00 last night...
and didn't stop
until 6:00 this morning.
What happened?
He was pointed toward the ocean
and growling.
What does that tell you?
My dog goes crazy and
decides to bark at the water.
I heard the church bells
at midnight...
as I started
to drift off to sleep...
and my car alarm went off
for absolutely no reason.
-Really?
-Woke up the whole block.
This town sits around for
100 years and nothing happens...
and then one night,
the whole place falls apart.
Take this line, too.
Al! Tommy! Dick!
Cabin and steering house
are empty.
Maybe somebody picked them up.
There's water in the generator.
But the deck is dry as a bone.
There you have it.
My next project...
restoration of
the Morgantown Road Cemetery.
It's historical.
Our ancestors are buried here.
-It'll cost a lot.
-Come on. So?
This town should be proud
of its past.
But trying to get
anyone involved...
in community affairs
is like pulling teeth.
Better get
the estimates ready...
for the council meeting
next month.
Yes, ma'am.
Sandy, you're
the only person I know...
who can make ''Yes, ma'am''
sound like ''Screw you.''
Yes, ma'am.
Now, if we'll just say
a little prayer...
asking that
he not be in his cups.
Not a good sign.
Father Malone?
Another bad sign.
You try the study,
and I'll look up front.
-Jesus!
-I'm sorry, Mrs. Williams.
-Mrs. Williams--
-Are you all right?
I have something to show you.
''December 9.
''Met with Blake this evening
for the first time.
''He stood in the shadows...
''to prevent me from getting
a clear look at his face.
''What a vile disease this is.
''He is a rich man
with a cursed condition...
''but this does not
prevent him...
''from trying to better
his situation...
''and that of his comrades
at the colony.''
Every single gauge is broken.
-All the glass is shattered.
-Remind you of something?
-Last night.
-Your truck.
Thermometer's broken.
The mercury's stuck
at twenty degrees.
No water got in here,
but something awful cold did.
''December 11.
Blake's proposition is simple.
''He wants to move off
Tanzier Island...
''and relocate the entire colony
just north of here.
''He has purchased
a clipper ship...
''called the 'Elizabeth Dane.'
with part of his fortune....
''and asks only for permission
to settle here.
''I must balance my feelings
of mercy and compassion...
''toward this poor man...
''with my revulsion
at the thought...
''of a leper colony
only a mile distant.''
It's rusted to the wall.
It was on.
They drank a lot of beer
last night.
Every night.
What's it like?
It's always the same.
Room starts spinning--
I mean fishing.
You fish.
The only thing I know
about fishing...
is you use a lot of worms.
Salt water.
She was clean two nights ago.
I checked her out myself.
Now it's as if she's been
turned over in the water.
''April 20.
The six of us met tonight.
''From midnight until 1:00...
''we planned the death
of Blake and his comrades.
''I tell myself
that Blake's gold...
''will allow
the church to be built...
''and our small settlement
to become a township...
''but it does not soothe
the horror that I feel...
''being an accomplice to murder.''
Now what?
Wait for the Coast Guard.
I'm sorry.
What for?
Ever since you picked me up,
things have been going wrong.
The clock broke, the windows
have been breaking...
the weirdo at the door
last night.
-That isn't you.
-I'm not so sure.
Things seem to happen to me.
I'm bad luck.
I don't believe in luck,
good or bad.
I don't believe
in anything much...
Something did happen once.
My father was a fisherman.
He ran a trawler
out of Whitely Reef.
One night, late,
he was coming back in.
He was out beyond the reef,
out near Spivey Point.
He looked to windward...
and saw a brig
under shortsail...
heading right for him.
And he radioed.
There was no reply.
Nothing moved on the deck,
but she held her course.
My dad and two of his hands
boarded the brig--
the ''Resa Jane.''
No one was on board.
There was food on the table...
and a hot, steaming
cup of coffee.
But underneath, the tin cup
was rusted to the table.
And then something caught
my father's eye.
It was a gold doubloon
minted in Spain, 1867.
My dad picked up the coin,
put it in his breast pocket...
of his jacket,
and zippered it up.
He came home,
told us the story.
And he unzippered the pocket
to give me the coin.
It was gone.
I think I'll go
to Vancouver now.
''April 21st. The deed is done.
''Blake followed
our false fire on shore...
''and his ship broke apart
on the rocks off Spivey Point.
''We were aided
by an unearthly fog...
''that rolled in
as if heaven-sent...
''although God had no part
in our actions tonight.
''Blake's gold
will be recovered tomorrow...
''but may the Lord forgive us
for what we have done.''
I couldn't read any further.
Your grandfather
had a way with words.
Our celebration tonight
is a travesty.
We're honoring murderers.
Side one,
KAB promos and lead-ins.
More music on
top of the world KAB 1340.
Thirty-three.
KAB 1340.
Fifty-seven.
From the top of the world...
fabulous 1340.
KAB, Antonio Bay.
Thirty-one.
From the top of the world,
fabulous 1340.
The smooth sound of KAB,
Antonio Bay, California.
Fifty-four.
KAB 1340.
Thirty-one.
The sounds of the surf
from Antonio Bay.
KAB 1340.
Thirty-nine.
Fabulous 1340,
KAB, Antonio Bay.
More music on
top of the world, KAB 1340.
EST-111-B, cut two.
From the top of the world...
fabulous 1340 KAB,
Antonio Bay.
Father, where did you find this?
My grandfather hid his sins
in the walls.
When did you find it?
Last night,
just after midnight.
What difference does it make?
That's the same time
the rest of the town fell apart.
And the same time
the six conspirators met...
one hundred years ago.
It's really getting late.
There's not much we can do
about any of this.
Are you going to give
the benediction tonight, Father?
Antonio Bay has a curse on it.
Do we take that as a ''no''?
Maybe it's just as well.
We're leaving now, Father.
Will you be all right?
I'm going to call Dr. Thayden
and ask him to just drop by.
I think you're taking
all of this much too seriously.
We're all cursed,
Mrs. Williams...
all of us.
1340 KAB.
Forty-four.
The smooth sound.
Fabulous 1340 KAB.
Forty-five.
From the top of the world,
fabulous 1340 KAB...
Antonio Bay, California.
Forty-six.
The smooth sound...
Something like
an albatross around the neck...
No. More like a millstone...
a plumbing stone, by God.
Damn them all!
Nine.
Every hour on the hour...
KAB news and weather.
Ten.
Every hour on the hour,
KAB news and weather.
End side two, KAB promos.
How can a man drown
and not touch the water?
He had water in his lungs...
salt water around his mouth,
seaweed in his clothes.
Unless...
You OK?
Did you see his eyes?
Yeah, I saw his eyes.
Andy, the telephone.
I got it, Mrs. Kobritz.
Andy, where did you get
that piece of driftwood?
I told you, Mom.
On the beach this morning.
-Where?
-By the rocks.
What was it doing?
First it was a gold coin...
and then it turned
into the wood.
Andy, I want you
to stay away from the rocks.
Do you understand?
Don't pick up anything else
off the beach.
It didn't belong to anybody.
I know, honey.
It's all right.
I just don't want you
to pick up anything else...
unless you come
and get me first. OK?
OK.
Is Mrs. Kobritz there?
She just came in.
OK. I have to start
the broadcast now.
Andy, promise me you won't
leave the house tonight.
Oh, Mom.
Promise me.
Oh, OK.
I love you, Andy.
Me, too, Mom. Bye.
Ahoy, maties.
This is Stevie Wayne,
your night light...
and KAB, Antonio Bay,
California, is on the air.
I've lined up some tunes
to help you celebrate...
the 100th birthday
of Antonio Bay.
So let's get down to business.
What did your mother want, Andy?
Nothing.
It must have been something.
Mrs. Kobritz,
what are those clouds out there?
Evidence of deep
penetrating wounds...
in each ocular orbit...
entering into
the cranial cavity.
Also jagged lacerations
to the face...
Do you want to wait out front?
I'd rather wait with you.
OK.
Thorax has been crushed...
and the lungs
are filled with fluid.
Talk to you a minute?
She gonna be all right?
-Did you talk to Simms?
-I got him on the radio.
He's coming back
from Bodega Bay.
What the hell
happened out there?
There was rust
all over everything.
It was like the boat had been
out there a long time...
taking on water.
He was down below
near the bunks.
Nick, his wounds
are covered with algae...
his lungs are full...
and there's silt
under his fingernails.
I saw Dick Baxter
three days ago in Salinas.
Now he's lying in there
on the table...
looking like he's been
underwater for a month.
-Do you feel that?
-I'll tell you what happens.
-It just got cold in here.
-The water acts like ice.
A whole body would take a year
to decompose...
longer if it was down
far enough, cold enough.
But he was on the boat.
He was below decks.
No. Dick Baxter
died in the ocean.
You remember those three kids
that went diving...
for that old boat off the Point?
We got to them,
they'd been down for a week...
maybe ten days.
I swear to you right now,
he's been down longer.
And while the wrecking
of that beautiful ship...
upon our coast was,
of course...
a tragedy to those
who were on the ship...
it still was the catalyst
that brought together...
all of the people
of this wonderful area.
They came together...
they formed the charter
for Antonio Bay...
the charter by which you have
voted for these councilmen...
who sit on my left
and my right tonight.
The Coast Guard's
looking for them.
They're going to cover the area
pretty good...
so, really,
all we can do is wait.
I understand, Sheriff.
Thank you.
I got to go. I'm up next.
I'm so sorry, Mrs. Williams.
It's funny,
but all I can think about...
is my silly dog
barking all night...
and me just wishing
Al would come home.
Now, we can't have
the chairlady...
of the birthday celebration
in tears, can we?
I don't think you ought
to go out there.
I think that's exactly
what I ought to do.
I appreciate
all your help, Nick.
That's all right.
I searched
a long time for this one.
I hope you remember it.
Happy 100th, Antonio Bay.
The ceremonies are underway
at Shelby Square.
And we'll have that candlelight
procession in about an hour.
So if you hurry,
you can still make it.
The Coast Guard
dropped me a note.
They found the ''Sea Grass''
earlier this afternoon...
but there's no further word...
as to the condition of the ship
or the men on-board.
I'll keep you posted
as the news comes in to me.
Hope no one else gets lost
out there in the fog.
I'll be right back.
Hello. My name's Nick Castle.
You don't know me,
but I'm one of the men...
who found the ''Sea Grass''
this afternoon.
I'm sorry.
I don't have any further word.
I understand.
That's not what I called about.
You just mentioned something
now on the radio about the fog.
This is going to sound
a little strange, but...
I saw the fog last night...
out in the ocean
in the distance.
It was...glowing.
What seemed to be happening...
is that the wind
was moving due east...
and the fog
just kept moving west.
I know that sounds
completely crazy.
Right now it doesn't.
Something happened last night.
At the same time
that fog was moving in...
this whole town went unglued.
Hold on.
I've got some more
birthday music for you...
and a few other surprises.
Then I'll be ready to check in
with the weatherman.
And the weatherman will be
ready to check in with you.
-Hello?
-I'm still here.
There's one other thing.
It may have nothing
to do with the ''Sea Grass''.
Anything.
My son found a piece
of driftwood this morning.
Hey, Mel. How you doing?
Your girlfriend on the radio
has been talking about you.
I came in tonight
just to keep her happy.
I thought
you were off tonight.
I love my job.
You can tell them all
about that big fog bank...
moving in
the southeast there.
-Where?
-You'll see it.
I'm on my way.
See you tomorrow.
Yeah, Mel. I'll see you.
There you are.
I've got to make a run
out to the lighthouse...
at Spivey Point.
Want to come?
-Sure.
-Come on.
Hi, sweetheart!
I thought you were celebrating.
I couldn't spend an evening
without you.
I'm up in about thirty seconds.
What's new?
Another fog bank.
Where?
It's coming in off the ocean
from the southeast.
It's heading inland.
It should be here...
at the weather station
in ten minutes.
Dan, hold on.
I have a special
weather bulletin.
The tri-county
weather station...
reports a fog bank moving
southeast along the coast.
For whoever's interested...
that's the weather station
on Old Russellville Road.
Repeating--a fog bank is moving
southwest along the coast...
toward the weather station
on Old Russellville Road.
Dan, are you still there?
I'm still here.
You sound different tonight...
kind of intense.
I just feel like talking,
that's all.
You told me you didn't like
to talk on the telephone...
because you talked
on the radio all day.
Dan, where's the fog now?
It should be
right outside my door now.
Hold on.
I'm going to try something.
I can see it.
Now, what is the big deal?
You've seen fog once,
you seen it for life.
There's something
different about this fog.
It glows.
Can't you see anything yet?
Glows? Oh, I get it.
You take something
to keep you going, right?
Does it make you feel
a little weird sometimes?
-Hey.
-What?
The lights went out.
Everything's going crazy.
Barometer's falling,
temperature's dropping.
Dan, what is it?
What the hell's that?
What's happening?
What is it?
Someone's shining a light
through the window.
Dan, listen to me.
Hold on, sweetheart.
I want to check this out.
Dan, stay on the phone!
This has got to be a joke.
Someone's at the front door,
sweetheart...
playing a stupid joke.
And whoever it is...
they ain't gonna like
finding me home.
Dan, stay away from the door!
Anybody here?
Some asshole got drunk
and started taking...
this 100-year-old business
too seriously.
And so all of us living here
in Antonio Bay today...
owe a great debt
of gratitude...
to those men and women
a hundred years ago...
who struggled and sacrificed
to make this town grow...
into what it is today.
And it's up to us to keep
their kind of spirit alive.
I have an urgent bulletin.
Will Sheriff David Simms please
contact KAB Radio immediately?
The number is 555-2131.
This is an emergency.
So we must redouble our efforts,
work together.
We have a vital,
thriving community.
And I say
we have to keep it that way.
This is an emergency.
Sheriff David Simms,
please contact KAB immediately.
555-2131.
This is an emergency.
Sheriff Simms?
And so, as we make our way...
to the presentation
of the statue...
I think we should all
keep in mind...
the significance
of this night...
for every citizen
of Antonio Bay.
We should all proceed
over to the statue.
Single file. Don't push.
Take your time.
Start!
Please start!
Why did all the lights go out?
One of the lines
are probably down, Andy.
They usually take care
of these things right away.
I think it's kind of neat.
What's that now?
Start!
Andy! Andy,
get out of the house!
Mrs. Kobritz, get him
out of the house! Please! Run!
I think maybe we better
close all the windows, Andy.
Are your bedroom windows
closed?
I'll go see.
Someone listen to me!
My son is trapped!
887 White Beach Lane!
My son is trapped by the fog!
Andy, get out of the house!
Run!
Wow! Look at that!
Are your windows all closed?
Yes, ma'am.
What about
your mother's bedroom?
Please, someone!
My son is trapped!
Andy, run! Run!
Mrs. Kobritz, run!
Andy, I want you
to go to your room.
I think I should stay.
-Right now.
-Yes.
Go to your room.
I want to see who it is.
Can't I stay
for two more seconds?
OK, I'm going.
Mrs. Kobritz?
Please. My son is trapped!
887 White Beach Lane.
Someone get
to 887 White Beach Lane.
My son is trapped!
Get him out of the fog!
Please, someone!
My son is trapped!
Come on!
Get out of there, now!
Andy, run! Run!
Come on! Come on.
Go! Go!
Come on!
Don't pop it.
Try to ease it out.
Oh, Jesus.
Come on, baby!
Come on. It'll go.
Reverse! Reverse!
Come on!
Come on, do it! Do it!
...Stevie Wayne
for the last twenty minutes.
I think it's best
we call it a night here.
Another five or ten minutes...
everyone will have
seen the statue.
All right, but let's get them
through as quickly as we can.
Probably be a good idea
if you went home, Kathy.
We can close up here.
I should see it through
to the end.
Mrs. Williams,
there's nothing more to do here.
Let me take you home.
A little annoying,
but you're right.
-Would you please take me?
-Yes, ma'am.
-I'll call you tomorrow.
-Thank you.
Andy, I don't even know
if you can hear me.
I'm sorry that
I didn't come for you...
that I wasn't there.
Andy, please understand.
I have to stay here.
The fog is moving inland...
away from the beach...
towards Antonio Bay.
It's over by the armory.
I can't remember the name.
No, no--
I think it's Chestnut.
Feel like listening
to some music?
Sure.
It's moving faster now.
Up Regent Avenue.
Up to the end
of Smallhouse Road.
What is that?
It's just hitting
the outskirts of town.
Broad Street.
Clay Street.
It's moving down 10th Street.
Get inside and lock your doors.
Close your windows.
There's something in the fog.
If you're on the south side
of town, go north.
Stay away from the fog.
Richardsville Pike
up to Beacon Hill...
is the only clear road.
Up to the church.
If you can get out of town,
get to the old church.
Now the junction at 101
is cut off.
If you can get out of town,
get to the old church.
It's the only place
left to go.
Get to the old church
on Beacon Hill.
-It cut us off!
-Where is it?
-Right behind us.
-Quick, inside.
Come on.
Hurry.
Father, is there a basement
or cellar in here?
-We can't hide any longer.
-We have to try!
No matter where we go,
it will find us.
Is there a basement
or cellar here?
There's a study in back.
I'll show you the way.
Come on. Hurry.
Give me that.
The fog is sweeping inland.
It's almost like a wall
across the east end of town.
Blake and his men
have come for us.
-Who's Blake?
-It's in the journal.
-What journal?
-I don't know.
-We're cursed.
-What are you talking about?
-Where is the journal?
-It's in there.
Over by the window?
-It can do us no good now.
-It's all we got.
If anything happens,
just lock the door.
Get back. Shut the door.
''Six must die.''
The three men
on the ''Sea Grass''.
And the weatherman is four.
-Mrs. Kobritz.
-Yeah, five.
And one of us makes six.
That's what they want.
They've come back...
for the six
original conspirators.
There must be something
in here!
It's me they want.
I am the sixth!
Why would they want you?
Wait, Father.
You didn't read us this.
''Were it possible
to raise the dead...
''I would return Blake's fortune
to him intact...
''save the money spent
on these walls that hide it.''
''My fellow conspirators
believe...
''that the confiscated fortune
has been stolen...
''from them, when in fact,
I am the thief...
''and God's temple
is the tomb of gold.''
''I am the thief,
and God's temple--''
Now, wait. Get rid of that.
Get out of the way!
-Give me a hand.
-Andy, stay right there.
The gold.
He melted down the gold
into this.
Somebody help her!
Don't go in there!
Blake, I have your gold.
Blake?
This is your gold, Blake.
My grandfather stole it
from you.
I'm the one
who must answer for it.
I'm the sixth conspirator.
I'm Father Malone.
Take me.
Father Malone!
Look.
It's going away.
I don't know what happened
to Antonio Bay tonight.
Something came out of the fog...
and tried to destroy us.
In one moment, it vanished.
But if this has been
anything but a nightmare...
and if we don't wake up to find
ourselves safe in our beds...
it could come again.
To the ships at sea
who can hear my voice...
look across the water
into the darkness.
Look for the fog.
Why not six, Blake?
Why not me?
Please rate this subtitle at www.osdb.link/4uc89
Help other users to choose the best subtitles